<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Informative on The TechGlider</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/tags/informative/</link><description>Recent content in Informative on The TechGlider</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 10:51:01 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/tags/informative/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Things I wish I knew in College</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2016/10/01/things-i-wish-i-knew-in-college/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 10:51:01 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2016/10/01/things-i-wish-i-knew-in-college/</guid><description>Meta About a month ago, I asked the following question to the NIT Calicut CSE student body:
If you could ask only one question to an NITC CSE alumnus with diverse experience in industry, higher studies, and research, what would you?
The most raised concerns were:
How to decide between higher studies and industry as your next career move? What are the limitations of an NITC CSE education and how to succeed in the field despite them?</description></item><item><title>Controlling iTunes using Android Wear</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2015/07/14/controlling-itunes-using-android-wear/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2015 16:58:36 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2015/07/14/controlling-itunes-using-android-wear/</guid><description>I happen to be surrounded by a lot of gadgets lately. One of them is a pretty Moto 360, one of the early Android Wear watches:
and another a MacBook Air (PlatiniumAir) which is about to celebrate its first anniversary:
This morning while walking-reading in my room, I had iTunes on the MacBook playing some tracks from one of the auto-generated Apple Music playlists. Now, it’s fairly easy to flick away mobile (lying away on my desk) notifications using my watch and not interrupt my reading for more than a couple seconds.</description></item><item><title>100 Days of Grammati</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2015/03/15/100-days-of-grammati/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2015 14:38:01 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2015/03/15/100-days-of-grammati/</guid><description>Haris had posted the following tweet few months ago:
http://t.co/jRrbjaPWSG is the only e-learning site that I have been able to consistently follow. 2 month streak now.
Thanks @hallidude!
&amp;mdash; Haris Ibrahim K. V. (@harisibrahimkv) December 5, 2014 After quickly checking out grammati.com, I had signed up. Received the following email this morning (for some reason Google decided to mark this as spam for the first time) and I thought it was time to spread the word:</description></item><item><title>LaTeX Project Report Template Updated</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2013/02/15/latex-project-report-template-updated/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2013 14:36:40 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2013/02/15/latex-project-report-template-updated/</guid><description>The LaTeX logo (Photo credit: Wikipedia)
This will be quite short.
Many have told me they found the LaTeX Project Report Template that I published about two years back pretty useful. Today, I am releasing an update for the same. This includes a fix for a nasty bug in the original template apart from some layout changes.
Fork it from Github at https://github.com/k4rtik/latex-project-report-template to start creating your project reports.Visit http://k4rtik.</description></item><item><title>Best Tool for Downloading YouTube Videos and Playlists</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2012/07/13/best-tool-for-downloading-youtube-videos-and-playlists/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2012 18:30:17 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2012/07/13/best-tool-for-downloading-youtube-videos-and-playlists/</guid><description>How many times does it happen that you stumble upon an awesome youtube video, you make up your mind to download it but fail short to find a good tool which actually works?
In this post I want to introduce one of the best tools for downloading videos from YouTube and other video platforms - youtube-dl. This command line tool is basically just a python script released by its developers in public domain and it works on any platform that supports Python 2.</description></item><item><title>A Fun Security Weekend with null and sCTF</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2012/06/22/a-fun-security-weekend-with-null-and-sctf/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2012 19:39:05 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2012/06/22/a-fun-security-weekend-with-null-and-sctf/</guid><description>I know it&amp;rsquo;s quite late to post about the last weekend when another weekend is around the corner, but couldn&amp;rsquo;t control myself as the last one was so eventful. :)
It was almost 2 weeks back that I got to know about sCTF 2012. I have always wanted to learn about computer security (and the darker side of hacking), but haven&amp;rsquo;t been able to give time it to it. What followed was a quick search for team members from among my batch via FB - Nithin immediately showed interest, we pulled Jerrin in too.</description></item><item><title>(Bangalore) Summer of '12... with BeagleBone</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2012/06/13/bangalore-summer-of-12-with-beaglebone/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2012 16:42:13 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2012/06/13/bangalore-summer-of-12-with-beaglebone/</guid><description>This post will be slightly long. Lots of exciting things happening over a Bangalore summer this year for me. :D
Somehow I always wanted to learn more about hardware and with a mentor like Khasim the road seems a lot more exciting. I first met him when he came to conduct a workshop on BeagleBoard during Tathva 2009 at my college - NIT Calicut. I was just a fresher then and have since regretted that I could not attend that workshop completely (due to my participation in various CS related competitions).</description></item><item><title>Ponderings of the Year Past: Part 1</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2012/03/26/ponderings-of-the-year-past-part-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2012 19:59:28 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2012/03/26/ponderings-of-the-year-past-part-1/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been long since I wrote something. To be frank, it was last July in which I actually spoke out my mind. Of course, I wished to write a lot more (who doesn&amp;rsquo;t). This one is going to be long, so I decided to partition it.
The following are few important lessons I learnt over the gone year - 2011:
Computer Science != Computer Engineering Vineeth Sir always calls it Computing Science, we even had a discussion over it, perhaps over a year back( and once again recently); the doubt got cleared up only after I looked up ACM&amp;rsquo;s Computing Curricula Recommendations which defines five sub-disciplines of computing: Computer Science, Computer Engineering, Information Systems, Information Technology, and Software Engineering (they have pretty decent comparisons among these disciplines using pictures and charts).</description></item><item><title>Control All Computers in a Lab from a Single System</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2012/02/12/control-all-computers-in-a-lab-from-a-single-system/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2012 03:10:21 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2012/02/12/control-all-computers-in-a-lab-from-a-single-system/</guid><description>Quoting Dhandeep, our super-cool lab-admin:
now , all 70 systems in the lab can be switched on and switched off by single commands from the hostel&amp;hellip;
Yes, that and a lot more is possible in our Software Systems Lab now. How? Read on&amp;hellip;
The Setup We have over 70 systems with Ubuntu 10.04 LTS installed on them. There is an administrative account (let&amp;rsquo;s call it admin for this post) and a guest (limited privilege) account on each.</description></item><item><title>Configuring Apache for Developing Multiple Websites under Ubuntu Linux</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2011/08/18/configuring-apache-for-developing-multiple-websites-under-ubuntu-linux/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2011 18:30:13 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2011/08/18/configuring-apache-for-developing-multiple-websites-under-ubuntu-linux/</guid><description>Are you a beginner in web development with LAMP environment, or a CS/IT student overwhelmed with setting up LAMP and configuring it for your web-related academic project? If yes, then you are at the right place.
We have discussed earlier how easy it is to setup a web development environment on your Ubuntu desktop. In this article we will try to have a more customized setup of this environment for easily working with multiple websites.</description></item><item><title>Remove Orphaned Actions in Drupal 7</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2011/07/14/remove-orphaned-actions-in-drupal-7/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2011 16:41:53 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2011/07/14/remove-orphaned-actions-in-drupal-7/</guid><description>I recently discovered this weird behaviour by drush when I disabled Comment module in Drupal 7 - drush was giving the following warning whenever I tried enabling/disabling any module:
WD actions: 3 orphaned actions (comment_publish_action, comment_save_action, comment_unpublish_action) exist in the actions table. Remove orphaned actions After some scrounging on drupal.org (where most solutions were meant for Drupal 6), I found the solution at http://blog.devkinetic.com/node/9 Just execute the following once:
drush php-eval &amp;#34;actions_synchronize(actions_list(), TRUE);&amp;#34;</description></item><item><title>Easiest Way to Setup a Web Development Environment on Ubuntu-based Distros</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2011/07/08/easiest-way-to-setup-a-web-development-environment-on-ubuntu-based-distros/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2011 18:30:21 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2011/07/08/easiest-way-to-setup-a-web-development-environment-on-ubuntu-based-distros/</guid><description>Did you know how easy it is to get a basic web development environment on your Ubuntu-based Linux distribution? Guess what, it just takes 2 commands on the Terminal:
sudo apt-get install tasksel This will install a small utility which lets you install a lot packages grouped together as software collections.
sudo tasksel Launch tasksel and select &amp;lsquo;LAMP server&amp;rsquo; by pressing the SPACE key, press ENTER when you are done (see attached screenshot).</description></item><item><title>Use rfkill to Enable/Disable Wireless on your Linux Laptop</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2011/06/29/use-rfkill-to-enabledisable-wireless-on-your-linux-laptop/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2011 18:30:56 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2011/06/29/use-rfkill-to-enabledisable-wireless-on-your-linux-laptop/</guid><description>Imagine a situation when you have to book an air/train ticket in a jiffy, or check an important mail quickly and the only option you have is a wi-fi connection from either your smart phone or surroundings, and you have only some Linux variant installed on your system. And even after installing all the necessary drivers, you are unable to get the wi-fi on your laptop working? Frustrating right? If yes, then you might want to read on about this useful utility called rfkill which you can keep in handy for those weary situations.</description></item><item><title>Restore GRUB in Ubuntu after installing Windows</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2011/06/25/restore-grub-in-ubuntu-after-installing-windows/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2011 18:30:44 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2011/06/25/restore-grub-in-ubuntu-after-installing-windows/</guid><description>So, you had Ubuntu (or any of its derivative) installed on your system and then decided to install Windows with it? And after installing Windows, you can&amp;rsquo;t load Ubuntu again, just follow the steps to get this working:
Boot the system using a Ubuntu Live disk.
After you reach the desktop, open Terminal (press Alt+F2, type &amp;ldquo;gnome-terminal&amp;rdquo; without quotes and press enter).
Execute:
``` sudo fdisk -l ``` Execute (after replacing sda7 with your corresponding linux root partition, which you will be able to identify from the output of the previous command - it&amp;rsquo;s usually marked as Linux): ``` sudo mount /dev/sda7 /mnt ``` Just check whether you got the root partition right, if you have more than 1 linux partition on your hard disk: ``` cd /mnt ls ``` If the listing contains names like bin, boot, dev, etc, home, tmp, usr, var, et cetera then you are in the right partition.</description></item><item><title>Root Samsung Galaxy S i9000 running GINGERBREAD.DDJV6 using Ubuntu Linux</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2011/06/21/root-samsung-galaxy-s-i9000-running-gingerbread-ddjv6-using-ubuntu-linux/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2011 17:01:54 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2011/06/21/root-samsung-galaxy-s-i9000-running-gingerbread-ddjv6-using-ubuntu-linux/</guid><description>I bought a Samsung Galaxy S i9000 just last month. The most prominent reason to buy an Android phone was that it&amp;rsquo;s based on Linux and I love the UNIX-based OS. Besides, Android as a platform provides so many opportunities into application development (and even kernel hacking) that I was simply tempted to buy one since last year.
I have explored the phone since I got my hands on it - trying various apps, playing with 3G internet speeds (3.</description></item><item><title>Choosing an Android Phone - Not an Easy Job</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2011/05/23/choosing-an-android-phone-not-an-easy-job/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2011 16:42:51 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2011/05/23/choosing-an-android-phone-not-an-easy-job/</guid><description>Little background It&amp;rsquo;s almost a month now since I sold my old Nokia N72 (fondly named PlatiniumJunior by me), hoping to buy an Android-based smartphone soon. Since then, I have realized how dependent I was on the phone - thinking of taking a quick snap and realizing I don&amp;rsquo;t have a camera anymore is disappointing, same is getting stuck at a word while reading and missing that MSDict software on my phone which was always ready as a quick reference, similar is being jobless at places I am forced to visit at times (or when there were power outages of countless hours at home, more on this in another post) and missing the phone again which I could use to read some or other ebook.</description></item><item><title>Really Achieving Your Childhood Dreams - The Last Lecture</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2011/03/09/really-achieving-your-childhood-dreams-the-last-lecture/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2011 19:01:21 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2011/03/09/really-achieving-your-childhood-dreams-the-last-lecture/</guid><description>I finally got a chance to watch this wonderful talk (by Randy Pausch) popularly known as The Last Lecture. I wanted to watch this for a long time - since Anjhan mentioned about it in his keynote at foss.in and since Prateek Kalyankar had recommended this to me in Jan.
A really nice watch for anyone who has ever dreamed and thought of fulfilling them. I was particularly amazed to see a youthful, energetic, handsome Randy deliver that talk in such a cheerful, darkly funny way, while being just a few months away from his death (and knowing it!</description></item><item><title>Building a Modern Computer in 12 Steps - A Perfect Elective Course for Sem 3 of CSE</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2011/02/28/building-a-modern-computer-in-12-steps-a-perfect-elective-course-for-sem-3-of-cse/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2011 17:01:40 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2011/02/28/building-a-modern-computer-in-12-steps-a-perfect-elective-course-for-sem-3-of-cse/</guid><description>Just watched this Google Tech Talk on From Nand to Tetris in 12 steps by Shimon Schocken introducing a course he developed along with Noam Nisan:
A must watch for all CS faculty of hardware, algorithms and systems.
The course covers 12 projects to be done over a single semester covering building everything from basic logic gates to computer architecture, and from machine language to an operating system starting from a False and a NAND using a custom HDL.</description></item><item><title>Input/Output using Text Files Without Diving into File Handling</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2011/02/10/inputoutput-using-text-files-without-diving-into-file-handling/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2011 10:18:08 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2011/02/10/inputoutput-using-text-files-without-diving-into-file-handling/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s quite easy to use text files as input source or to redirect the output of programs to files if you happen to do programming on a unix/linux terminal.
Let&amp;rsquo;s take an example of a usual random number generator:
// random.c #include &amp;lt;stdio.h&amp;gt;#include &amp;lt;stdlib.h&amp;gt;int main () { int i, count=99999999; for (i = 0; i &amp;lt; count; i += 1) printf(&amp;#34;%d\n&amp;#34;, (int)random()); return 0; } Let&amp;rsquo;s generate an executable by the name random.</description></item><item><title>Accessing NIT Calicut's Ubuntu Mirror (in the campus)</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2011/02/01/accessing-nit-calicuts-ubuntu-mirror-in-the-campus/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 01:20:47 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2011/02/01/accessing-nit-calicuts-ubuntu-mirror-in-the-campus/</guid><description>As the FOSSCell webserver has been facing troubles these days, the instructions to use the Ubuntu Mirror of NIT Calicut that were available on the FOSSCell wiki are being missed by many. Here they are though not in the informative way as were given on the wiki:
Add the following to your /etc/apt/sources.list and comment out other similar repos.
deb http://192.168.40.97/ubuntu lucid-updates main multiverse restricted universe deb http://192.168.40.97/ubuntu lucid-security main multiverse restricted universe deb http://192.</description></item><item><title>Drupal 7 Exploration</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2011/01/23/drupal-7-exploration/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Jan 2011 12:51:45 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2011/01/23/drupal-7-exploration/</guid><description>I finally managed to install Drupal 7 on my Arch Linux Desktop after some difficulty, but feels like I learned a lot in the meantime.</description></item><item><title>Just finished reading Oral history inter...</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/status/2011/01/22/just-finished-reading-oral-history-inter/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2011 13:15:50 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/status/2011/01/22/just-finished-reading-oral-history-inter/</guid><description>Just finished reading Oral history interview with Edsger W. Dijkstra (transcript availabe on that link). This was suggested by Subhashree mam in our first lecture of Discrete Computational Structures course with her. An interesting read about Dijkstra&amp;rsquo;s life and history of the establishment of computing science as a discipline.</description></item><item><title>Just discovered accidentally - In GMail ...</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/status/2010/12/28/just-discovered-accidentally-in-gmail/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Dec 2010 06:43:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/status/2010/12/28/just-discovered-accidentally-in-gmail/</guid><description>Just discovered accidentally - In GMail chat, if you surround text with 2 underscores or 2 stars, they show up as italicized and bold text respectively in the chat. For example: _hello_ gets converted to hello and *world* to world. If you discover more such hidden features of GMail, feel free to share here.</description></item><item><title>Here is a video about the features of th...</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/status/2010/12/20/wpvideo-yynw9isj/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2010 08:06:55 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/status/2010/12/20/wpvideo-yynw9isj/</guid><description>Here is a video about the features of the theme I am using:
NOTE (2014-10-26): This post was for the P2 theme I was using on my wordpress.com blog for almost 4 years!</description></item><item><title>LaTeX Project Report Template</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2010/11/13/latex-project-report-template/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2010 05:39:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2010/11/13/latex-project-report-template/</guid><description>UPDATE RELEASED - Please use the latest version for all the LaTeX goodness.
Last week, starting from Sunday was spent in preparing my first project report in college and first using LaTeX. It took me over four days to finish the work. The end result was quite good and impressive. (See the attached report.pdf if you want to take a look).I abstracted a template from the report for future use. Hope it may be find some use for other NITCians or in general for everyone.</description></item><item><title>Recover files deleted from GNU/Linux</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2010/11/06/recover-files-deleted-from-gnulinux/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Nov 2010 15:43:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2010/11/06/recover-files-deleted-from-gnulinux/</guid><description>It was an embarassing today that after making a presentation on Drupal and promising the audience to distribute the presentation file after the session, I deleted it accidentally.
And all my fears regarding Linux being so different when it came to file recovery (unlike Windows, where you had a choice of many recovery software) and it was next to impossible to undelete files from linux, seemed to come true. A quick search in Ubuntu Software Center listed a software called &amp;lsquo;recover&amp;rsquo; which was meant only for ext2 partitions, and mine being ext4 I was hopeless.</description></item><item><title>First Hands-on with Assembly Language Programming</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2010/10/25/first-hands-on-with-assembly-language-programming/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2010 09:46:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2010/10/25/first-hands-on-with-assembly-language-programming/</guid><description>I always wanted to learn assembly language programming. I had never tried do it myself and was disappointed to know that it was not there in our Logic Design course this semester (this because it was mentioned in the syllabus and I had taken pains to find good books on assembly from the library and get them issued, just to return them after learning that the syllabus for the course was too less compared to what was given on the department&amp;rsquo;s website).</description></item><item><title>Installing 64-bit version of Flash Player on Fedora 13</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2010/10/16/installing-64-bit-version-of-flash-player-on-fedora-13/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Oct 2010 17:18:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2010/10/16/installing-64-bit-version-of-flash-player-on-fedora-13/</guid><description>I have been using Fedora 64-bit KDE for many months now, but was too lazy to install flash player (I don&amp;rsquo;t usually need it as I am no YouTube junkie) until now. But today I had to visit some sites whose content seemed next to none without flash plugin on my browser. This forced me to install flash player finally.
Such a person who always wants to remain at the cutting edge as I am, I tried installing the latest Flash Player &amp;ldquo;Square&amp;rdquo; Preview Release 64-bit available from Adobe Labs.</description></item><item><title>Using gdb to see through your program flow!</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2010/10/05/using-gdb-to-see-through-your-program-flow/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2010 11:37:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2010/10/05/using-gdb-to-see-through-your-program-flow/</guid><description>Using GDB was something I wanted to learn since I started programming in GNU/Linux environment. I read through man pages, info pages, and some vague guides on the net over the weeks but couldn&amp;rsquo;t figure out why wasn&amp;rsquo;t I able to use it properly.
Then somehow I found this: RMS&amp;rsquo;s gdb Debugger Tutorial and learned that the I was making a very small mistake every time while compiling the code.</description></item><item><title>Ubuntu Tips and Tricks - Part 1</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2010/09/25/ubuntu-tips-and-tricks-part-1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Sep 2010 09:53:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2010/09/25/ubuntu-tips-and-tricks-part-1/</guid><description>Just learned some new commands on Ubuntu:
If sometime you get into a (big!) trouble such as the Gnome panels not loading but the desktop is visible, you can open the gnome-terminal using the key combination Ctrl + Alt + T (of course this is a good shortcut for normal desktop usage too).
Because of the above problem, you may want to create a bootable drive to reinstall Ubuntu, but how do you do that as you cannot load the Ubuntu Startup Disk Creator?</description></item><item><title>Use the World Class IDE and Compiler for C++ for Free</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2008/03/24/use-the-world-class-ide-and-compiler-for-c-for-free/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2008 23:17:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2008/03/24/use-the-world-class-ide-and-compiler-for-c-for-free/</guid><description>I know you have been using around 20 years old Borland Turbo C++ IDE for quiet a lot of time now. The one with blue screen and big characters that runs on DOS environment. Its editor is sometimes a pain in the neck and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t run on Vista. Well let&amp;rsquo;s get back to the present. Who needs to use Turbo C++ (Ver 3.0) when a world class IDE like Microsoft Visual Studio 2008 Express Edition is available for free.</description></item><item><title>Use Dictionary and Pronunciation Guide on your PC</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2008/03/12/use-dictionary-and-pronunciation-guide-on-your-pc/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2008 20:55:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2008/03/12/use-dictionary-and-pronunciation-guide-on-your-pc/</guid><description>This is for those of you interested in improving their English skills and find it cumbersome to searching for meanings of words by turning over the pages of dictionary. If you work on your PC most of the time, then you can utilize it to improve on your vocabulary and pronunciation skills:
If you have a net connection and are online most of the time, then the best option is to use Google as a dictionary tool:</description></item></channel></rss>