<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Freedom on The TechGlider</title><link>techglider.in/tags/freedom/</link><description>Recent content in Freedom on The TechGlider</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 10:51:01 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="techglider.in/tags/freedom/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Things I wish I knew in College</title><link>techglider.in/post/2016/10/01/things-i-wish-i-knew-in-college/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 10:51:01 -0400</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2016/10/01/things-i-wish-i-knew-in-college/</guid><description>Meta About a month ago, I asked the following question to the NIT Calicut CSE student body:
If you could ask only one question to an NITC CSE alumnus with diverse experience in industry, higher studies, and research, what would you?
The most raised concerns were:
How to decide between higher studies and industry as your next career move? What are the limitations of an NITC CSE education and how to succeed in the field despite them?</description></item><item><title>Review of V for Vendetta</title><link>techglider.in/post/2015/05/01/review-of-v-for-vendetta/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 20:59:51 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2015/05/01/review-of-v-for-vendetta/</guid><description>V for Vendetta by Alan Moore
My rating: 4.5 of 5 stars
I had seen the film adaptation 4-5 years ago but hardly recalled what it was about. Decided to watch it again after I was done with the graphic novel and compare the two.
The Graphic Novel First couple of volumes in the 10-volume series didn&amp;rsquo;t make much sense and were rather slow to read as I was just getting introduced to the characters.</description></item><item><title>Review of No Place to Hide by Glenn Greenwald</title><link>techglider.in/post/2015/04/12/review-of-no-place-to-hide-by-glenn-greenwald/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2015 12:37:38 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2015/04/12/review-of-no-place-to-hide-by-glenn-greenwald/</guid><description>No Place to Hide: Edward Snowden, the NSA and the Surveillance State by Glenn Greenwald
My rating: 4 of 5 stars
I had bought this book right away after reading the following tweet from a concerned friend:
It took me another 5 months to actually start reading the book.
Review First two chapters read like a Dan Brown thriller except that you constantly keep reminding yourself that this is not fiction and events leading to the Snowden revelations actually happened this way.</description></item><item><title>Swaraj by Arvind Kejriwal - A Review</title><link>techglider.in/post/2014/03/20/swaraj-by-arvind-kejriwal-a-review/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2014 17:53:41 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2014/03/20/swaraj-by-arvind-kejriwal-a-review/</guid><description>Swaraj by Arvind Kejriwal
My rating: 4 of 5 stars
Ended up reading a Hindi book after many years, &amp;lsquo;कथेतर&amp;rsquo; (non-fiction, new word learnt!) on that.
Little Background I haven&amp;rsquo;t followed Kejriwal&amp;rsquo;s or Anna&amp;rsquo;s movement from the beginning. I first gave serious attention when AAP managed to win a substantial number of seats in Delhi last December. Since then, I have come to admire Kejriwal&amp;rsquo;s clarity of thought, his ideas and his mission, all of which can be ascertained in any of his recent interviews or QA&amp;rsquo;s with audience where neither the interviewer nor the public leave any stone unturned to grill him.</description></item><item><title>Week 1 at Bangalore and Work</title><link>techglider.in/post/2013/07/21/week-1-at-bangalore-and-work/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2013 14:53:31 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2013/07/21/week-1-at-bangalore-and-work/</guid><description>I landed at Bangalore airport last week flying on an indiGo for the first time; found the experience better than JetKonnect from my first flight.
Next day (Sunday) started early with a walk to Oracle Tech Park and back to get myself familiarized with the area before first day at work. A much-needed haircut followed.
Having caught cold with the change in weather, I had to miss the Goodreads meetup planned at Brigade Road during the day, which I was eagerly awaiting to attend with a friend.</description></item><item><title>Of FOSSMeets at NIT Calicut</title><link>techglider.in/post/2013/04/14/of-fossmeets-at-nit-calicut/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 08:33:41 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2013/04/14/of-fossmeets-at-nit-calicut/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been over a month and a half since the last edition of FOSSMeet at NIT Calicut. As an active member of organizing team for FOSSMeets &amp;lsquo;10 and &amp;lsquo;11 and a keen but silent observer for the 2013 edition, I want to share some history, some ideas &amp;amp; few observations with this post. The intent is to generate discussion among people who have been part of earlier FOSSMeets and to leave some things to ponder about (and act on) for juniors.</description></item><item><title>Ponderings of the Year Past: Part 1</title><link>techglider.in/post/2012/03/26/ponderings-of-the-year-past-part-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2012 19:59:28 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2012/03/26/ponderings-of-the-year-past-part-1/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been long since I wrote something. To be frank, it was last July in which I actually spoke out my mind. Of course, I wished to write a lot more (who doesn&amp;rsquo;t). This one is going to be long, so I decided to partition it.
The following are few important lessons I learnt over the gone year - 2011:
Computer Science != Computer Engineering Vineeth Sir always calls it Computing Science, we even had a discussion over it, perhaps over a year back( and once again recently); the doubt got cleared up only after I looked up ACM&amp;rsquo;s Computing Curricula Recommendations which defines five sub-disciplines of computing: Computer Science, Computer Engineering, Information Systems, Information Technology, and Software Engineering (they have pretty decent comparisons among these disciplines using pictures and charts).</description></item><item><title>Disconnect - An Experiment</title><link>techglider.in/post/2011/07/10/disconnect-an-experiment/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2011 18:37:01 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2011/07/10/disconnect-an-experiment/</guid><description>This will be short.
A small announcement: I will be out of touch for about a week on the Internet. Disconnected on all social networks (including twitter) and off-line on chats (including GMail chat) and unavailable on SMS. I have already disabled all email and SMS notifications from the social networks. This is just for the sake of experimenting to see if I can still live without social media, so don&amp;rsquo;t get weird ideas about this.</description></item><item><title>7 Commandments of the Personal Computer Revolution</title><link>techglider.in/quote/2011/04/22/7-commandments-of-the-personal-computer-revolution/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2011 13:11:08 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/quote/2011/04/22/7-commandments-of-the-personal-computer-revolution/</guid><description>7 Commandments of the Personal Computer Revolution:
Access to Computers - and anything that might teach you something about the way the world works - should be unlimited and total. Always yield to the Hands-on Imperative. All information should be free. Mistrust authority - promote decentralization. Hackers should be judged by their hacking, not bogus criteria such as degrees, age, race,or position. You can create art and beauty on a computer.</description></item><item><title>The Hacker Attitude</title><link>techglider.in/quote/2011/03/10/the-hacker-attitude/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2011 09:03:29 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/quote/2011/03/10/the-hacker-attitude/</guid><description>The Hacker Attitude:
The world is full of fascinating problems waiting to be solved. No problem should ever have to be solved twice. Boredom and drudgery are evil. Freedom is good. Attitude is no substitute for competence. &amp;mdash;Eric Steven Raymond at How To Become A Hacker</description></item><item><title>I am free no matter what rules surround...</title><link>techglider.in/quote/2011/03/06/i-am-free-no-matter-what-rules-surround/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2011 09:17:47 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/quote/2011/03/06/i-am-free-no-matter-what-rules-surround/</guid><description>I am free, no matter what rules surround me. If I find them tolerable, I tolerate them; if I find them too obnoxious, I break them. I am free because I know that I alone am morally responsible for everything I do.
&amp;mdash;Robert A. Heinlein, &amp;ldquo;The Moon Is a Harsh Mistress&amp;rdquo;, 1966. Source: http://en.wikiquote.org/wiki/The_Moon_Is_a_Harsh_Mistress</description></item><item><title>Software Freedom Day 2010 at NIT Calicut</title><link>techglider.in/post/2010/09/18/software-freedom-day-2010-at-nit-calicut/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2010 21:55:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2010/09/18/software-freedom-day-2010-at-nit-calicut/</guid><description>I am a member of the Free and Open Source Software Users group - FOSSCell - at my college - NIT Calicut. We celebrated Software Freedom Day yesterday for the first time.
We started planning for the celebration on our mailing list 5 days ago. Amid a lot of heated discussions we kept on updating the FOSSCell wiki ( http://fosscell.nitc.ac.in/wiki ) with our ideas, plans, suggestions, names of attendees and volunteers.</description></item><item><title>List of Books Read So Far</title><link>techglider.in/post/2008/09/08/list-of-books-read-so-far/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2008 01:50:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2008/09/08/list-of-books-read-so-far/</guid><description>This is a list of books I used to maintain at The TechGlider Forums, imported here for keeping it updated.
Here I list the books I have read (only those whose names I remember) so far (in finishing order):
Harry Potter and the Philosopher&amp;rsquo;s Stone, by J K Rowling
Harry Potter and the Chamber of Secrets, by J K Rowling
Harry Potter and the Prisoner of Azkaban, by J K Rowling</description></item></channel></rss>