<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>xps on The TechGlider</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/tags/xps/</link><description>Recent content in xps on The TechGlider</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2013 15:55:08 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/tags/xps/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Quickly Check Temperature Values of Hardware Components in Ubuntu</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2013/02/06/quickly-check-temperature-values-of-hardware-components-in-ubuntu/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2013 15:55:08 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2013/02/06/quickly-check-temperature-values-of-hardware-components-in-ubuntu/</guid><description>So, I missed posting yesterday. Hope this doesn&amp;rsquo;t repeat.
Today I am sharing a small bash script I wrote to check the temperatures recorded by various sensors in my laptop. Nothing incredibly smart here, just a quick but useful hack.
I am one of those unhappy Linux users who suffer from lack of driver support for their hardware. Due to some weird kernel bug or messy graphics driver, which led to incredibly high temperatures on my laptop, I spent about a year using Linux as a VirtualBox guest in Windows; this was before Ubuntu 12.</description></item><item><title>Use rfkill to Enable/Disable Wireless on your Linux Laptop</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2011/06/29/use-rfkill-to-enabledisable-wireless-on-your-linux-laptop/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2011 18:30:56 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2011/06/29/use-rfkill-to-enabledisable-wireless-on-your-linux-laptop/</guid><description>Imagine a situation when you have to book an air/train ticket in a jiffy, or check an important mail quickly and the only option you have is a wi-fi connection from either your smart phone or surroundings, and you have only some Linux variant installed on your system. And even after installing all the necessary drivers, you are unable to get the wi-fi on your laptop working? Frustrating right? If yes, then you might want to read on about this useful utility called rfkill which you can keep in handy for those weary situations.</description></item><item><title>Replaced my Studio XPS screen and palm rest</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2010/12/23/replaced-my-studio-xps-screen-and-palm-rest/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2010 11:47:26 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2010/12/23/replaced-my-studio-xps-screen-and-palm-rest/</guid><description>Got my laptop screen and palm rest, touch pad replaced :) But all my stickers - Drupal, Hacker Logo, Python, Firefox, Core i7, Windows 7 - and RMS&amp;rsquo; signature are gone :(</description></item></channel></rss>