<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>On the Web on The TechGlider</title><link>techglider.in/categories/on-the-web/</link><description>Recent content in On the Web on The TechGlider</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2011 17:37:37 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="techglider.in/categories/on-the-web/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Good Bye TechGlider Forums, Ta-Ta NITC Wiki</title><link>techglider.in/post/2011/07/10/good-bye-techglider-forums-ta-ta-nitc-wiki/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2011 17:37:37 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2011/07/10/good-bye-techglider-forums-ta-ta-nitc-wiki/</guid><description>Today I bid adieu to The TechGlider Forums which used to reside at https://techglider.in/forums Started in August of 2008, it was my attempt to build a tech support community around my friends and visitors of my website - TechGlider.in. This decision comes at a time when I have realized it&amp;rsquo;s no longer a good idea to build a community like this on phpBB, with the advent of platforms like facebook and twitter (and Google+ more recently) and their penetrations in our lives.</description></item><item><title>Bash Script to Download MIT OCW Videos</title><link>techglider.in/post/2011/03/27/bash-script-to-download-mit-ocw-videos/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2011 08:28:01 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2011/03/27/bash-script-to-download-mit-ocw-videos/</guid><description>Some months back in November, I had used many variants of the following script to automate the download of MIT OCW videos:
#!/bin/bash baseurl=&amp;#34;http://www.archive.org/download/MIT_Structure_of_Computer_Programs_1986/lec&amp;#34; urlend=&amp;#34;b_512kb.mp4&amp;#34; log=&amp;#34;log_b&amp;#34; for i in {1..7} do nohup wget -c &amp;#34;${baseurl}$i${urlend}&amp;#34; &amp;gt; &amp;#34;${log}$i&amp;#34; &amp;amp; done It doesn&amp;rsquo;t really do much, just put the baseurl and urlend properly which should be common for similar links and run a for loop.
Sharing so that it may come handy to some others in similar needs.</description></item><item><title>Simple script to install essential packages in Ubuntu 10.04 Lucid 64-bit</title><link>techglider.in/post/2010/05/05/simple-script-to-install-essential-packages-in-ubuntu-10-04-lucid-64-bit/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2010 07:16:11 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2010/05/05/simple-script-to-install-essential-packages-in-ubuntu-10-04-lucid-64-bit/</guid><description>Please note that this script has been tested only with a lucid 64-bit installation. It requires an active internet connection to download packages (a broadband connection, otherwise it will seem to take forever to finish):
#!/bin/bash # Adding Medibuntu Repositories sudo wget http://www.medibuntu.org/sources.list.d/$(lsb_release -cs).list --output-document=/etc/apt/sources.list.d/medibuntu.list sudo aptitude update &amp;amp;&amp;amp; sudo aptitude install medibuntu-keyring &amp;amp;&amp;amp; sudo aptitude update sudo update-apt-xapian-index # Install multimedia codecs sudo apt-get remove gnash gnash-common libflashsupport mozilla-plugin-gnash swfdec-mozilla sudo apt-get install gstreamer0.</description></item><item><title>Missing writing on the blog</title><link>techglider.in/post/2010/03/27/missing-writing-on-the-blog/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2010 08:50:12 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2010/03/27/missing-writing-on-the-blog/</guid><description>You may have noticed I have written almost nothing after November last year.
The main reason has been some or other problem with my website&amp;rsquo;s hosting server until it was shifted to another one in early Feb. But after this happened it&amp;rsquo;s some strange problem in the campus network that my website is only accessible at certain unexpected times as now. While writing this I am not sure, I will be able to publish this post or not, as the site seems accessible at completely random times and duration.</description></item><item><title>Testing GScribble</title><link>techglider.in/post/2010/02/26/testing-gscribble/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2010 18:10:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2010/02/26/testing-gscribble/</guid><description>Posting a blog post using a desktop client GScribble. GScribble is the first open source project I am testing. Let&amp;rsquo;s see maybe I go into its development.
Disclaimer: This is just a test post.
Posted from GScribble.</description></item><item><title>Easter egg on Google: New Year 2010 Countdown</title><link>techglider.in/post/2009/12/31/easter-egg-on-google-new-year-2010-countdown/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2009 10:30:30 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2009/12/31/easter-egg-on-google-new-year-2010-countdown/</guid><description>My friend Amit had just created an account on GMail and logged out after that. Just then, he opened Google and was going to search something when I mentioned I&amp;rsquo;m Feeling Lucky to him. He asked what is that to which I thought of replying by showing him the official explanation by Google, so I clicked on &amp;rsquo;the&amp;rsquo; button without any search string. And voila! It showed this:
After scratching my head for few seconds, it occurred to me that it could be the countdown to welcome the new year 2010.</description></item><item><title>A Simple Tic Tac Toe Game in C</title><link>techglider.in/post/2009/11/12/a-simple-tic-tac-toe-game-in-c/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2009 13:24:53 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2009/11/12/a-simple-tic-tac-toe-game-in-c/</guid><description>Tic Tac Toe (T3), a two-player game developed in C/C++ in 2006-2007
For the school project in C++ in standard 11, I chose to make a game. Although the game doesn&amp;rsquo;t feature AI, it demonstrates the graphics and sound capabilities of C/C++ with Turbo C++ compiler.
Here is the link to the code (I can&amp;rsquo;t support it any more, so please don&amp;rsquo;t ask if you are unable to run it.):</description></item><item><title>The TechGlider Blog is now Kartik Scribbles...</title><link>techglider.in/post/2009/11/08/the-techglider-blog-is-now-kartik-scribbles/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2009 11:28:34 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2009/11/08/the-techglider-blog-is-now-kartik-scribbles/</guid><description>This change is something I wanted to incorporate since I restored this blog in the beginning of last month. Finally, the change is here.
The main reason why I changed the name of the blog is simple. &amp;lsquo;The TechGlider Blog&amp;rsquo; sounds like the official blog of my site - TechGlider.com which, in its actuality, is not that. This is my blog, Kartik&amp;rsquo;s. So, the name Kartik Scribbles&amp;hellip;
More personalized, more sensible, more fun, more readable.</description></item><item><title>Why I use Twitter? And why not Orkut or Facebook?</title><link>techglider.in/post/2009/10/11/why-i-use-twitter-and-why-not-orkut-or-facebook/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2009 16:05:28 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2009/10/11/why-i-use-twitter-and-why-not-orkut-or-facebook/</guid><description>So, it all started in 2006 when I was in class 11. The wave of orkut. I still remember, how I missed all the fun, when during the vacations after class X boards, most of my friends got broadband connections at their homes and started using orkut and became so close with each other and even with girls. I came to know of orkut only when it was too late sometime at the end of August 2006.</description></item><item><title>The TechGlider Blog is back</title><link>techglider.in/post/2009/10/03/the-techglider-blog-is-back/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2009 09:11:09 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2009/10/03/the-techglider-blog-is-back/</guid><description>I am really happy to announce that I have been able to restore the TGB successfully (after fiddling with the backups for almost a month). This period of two and a half months without my blog was really unbearable for me; the only thing that helped me bear this pain was what was happening in my real life. A lot of wonderful events have changed my life (e.g. I have taken admission in BTech CSE at NIT Calicut).</description></item><item><title>Essential software for a working Ubuntu 9.04 Desktop</title><link>techglider.in/post/2009/09/19/essential-software-for-a-working-ubuntu-9-04-desktop/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2009 15:08:30 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2009/09/19/essential-software-for-a-working-ubuntu-9-04-desktop/</guid><description>These are the steps to follow if you want your latest Ubuntu install to have all the essential software and codecs installed so that you can use your Ubuntu linux system as a/an replacement/addition of windows operating system.
You should be connected to internet to follow these steps. You can use Ctrl+Shift+V to paste the copied code in Terminal, which can be accessed as Applications-&amp;gt;Accessories-&amp;gt;Terminal.
First of all, choose the best server in System-&amp;gt;Administration-&amp;gt;Software Sources.</description></item><item><title>Just upgraded to WordPress 2.7</title><link>techglider.in/post/2009/05/09/just-upgraded-to-wordpress-27/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2009 09:45:26 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2009/05/09/just-upgraded-to-wordpress-27/</guid><description>Well it&amp;rsquo;s an all new world here in the administration side of this blog as I have upgraded to the latest version of WordPress.
It will take me time to explore the new interface and understand the new capabilities and features that this version 2.7.1 has to offer. And then will follow some new additions to The TechGlider Blog and maybe even a change of theme.
Just wait for me as I do these changes and write a new post about my first voting experience.</description></item><item><title>Checking BSNL broadband usage</title><link>techglider.in/post/2008/12/07/checking-bsnl-broadband-usage/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2008 13:34:03 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2008/12/07/checking-bsnl-broadband-usage/</guid><description>On older connections (before december 2007) broadband usage check can be done on one of the following IP addresses:
http://10.240.64.195
http://10.240.89.199
http://10.240.128.195
http://10.240.16.195
http://10.240.144.195
If one address doesn&amp;rsquo;t work, you can try another one. I happened to use the 4th IP address for a lot of months and one day it stopped working; now I am using the 2nd IP address from the above list.</description></item><item><title>On Deepawali and the change of theme</title><link>techglider.in/post/2008/10/28/on-deepawali-and-theme-change/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2008 17:09:34 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2008/10/28/on-deepawali-and-theme-change/</guid><description>This is today that somebody pointed out: &amp;ldquo;Your blog is not looking that fine&amp;rdquo;. And I realize why I lost interest in writing on this blog.
Following the suggestion I have changed the blog&amp;rsquo;s theme again. Tell me, if this one feels fine enough.
Today is Deepawali, the so-called biggest festival of India. Everybody out there is celebrating, burning crackers, or making merry; and here I am writing on my blog after a long break (my biggest break ever), amid the sounds of ladis, bombs, rockets, whistlers.</description></item><item><title>Welcome to the All New TechGlider Blog</title><link>techglider.in/post/2008/10/06/welcome-to-the-all-new-techglider-blog/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2008 23:46:23 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2008/10/06/welcome-to-the-all-new-techglider-blog/</guid><description>This is my first post on WordPress and through this I welcome you to the all new TechGlider Blog.
I am finally finished with moving the TGB to WordPress. WordPress offers a plethora of plugins to customize one&amp;rsquo;s blog and I am trying to choose what are those that I need for the TGB. As pointed out in my last post, this change hasn&amp;rsquo;t been easy. I almost lost all of my previous posts for there was no efficient way to import the posts from my b2evolution installation to WordPress, so I had to do it manually and took a whole day for that (these type of repetitive works are really a pain in the neck for me).</description></item><item><title>How to become a Hacker?</title><link>techglider.in/post/2008/10/05/how-to-become-a-hacker/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2008 08:21:49 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2008/10/05/how-to-become-a-hacker/</guid><description>A lot of people ask me &amp;ldquo;how can I become a hacker&amp;rdquo;?
I ask them to differentiate between a hacker and a cracker first and specify what do they actually want to become. If the answer is a hacker, I need to direct them to this page (perhaps the best page on the net for a guide to becoming a hacker): http://www.catb.org/~esr/faqs/hacker-howto.html
For crackers-to-be I don&amp;rsquo;t have very-healthy feelings and ask them to correct their mindsets.</description></item><item><title>TechGlider logo, finally designed</title><link>techglider.in/post/2008/09/30/techglider-logo-finally-designed/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2008 04:48:54 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2008/09/30/techglider-logo-finally-designed/</guid><description>I am happy :-) to inform all of you that I have finally designed a logo for the TechGlider:
Although I am not that satisfied with the logo, but I think it will do for the time being. Any suggestions for improvement of the logo are welcome.
I couldn&amp;rsquo;t finish the development of TechGlider this week (designing a logo really takes too much of time ;-)</description></item><item><title>Mainstream development of TechGlider in full flow</title><link>techglider.in/post/2008/09/23/mainstream-development-of-techglider-in-full-flow/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2008 00:31:45 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2008/09/23/mainstream-development-of-techglider-in-full-flow/</guid><description>And, I came back earlier by a week from the schedule.
I am happy to announce that the start of the next week (hopefully) will see the rise of TechGlider in its full avatar; fully loaded with most of stuff I have to offer.
I have got certain idea of what is going to be the logo for the TechGlider and will be designing it on paper in this week. The main site is no longer hidden: you are no longer directed to this TechGlider Blog on typing www.</description></item><item><title>Watch Zeitgeist to know the biggest secrets of mankind</title><link>techglider.in/post/2008/09/22/watch-zeitgeist-to-know-the-biggest-secrets-of-mankind/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2008 08:10:38 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2008/09/22/watch-zeitgeist-to-know-the-biggest-secrets-of-mankind/</guid><description>From Wikipedia:
Zeitgeist, the Movie is a 2007 documentary film, produced by Peter Joseph about the Jesus myth hypothesis, the attacks of 9/11, and the Federal Reserve Bank as well as a number of conspiracy theories related to those three main topics. It was released free online via Google Video in June 2007. A remastered version was presented as a global premiere on November 10, 2007 at the 4th Annual Artivist Film Festival &amp;amp; Artivist Awards.</description></item><item><title>Testing websites with IE on linux</title><link>techglider.in/post/2008/09/21/testing-websites-with-ie-on-linux/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2008 16:14:22 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2008/09/21/testing-websites-with-ie-on-linux/</guid><description>Just found this great tool IEs4Linux for testing websites under Internet Explorer 6, 5.5 and 5 on linux. It currently doesn&amp;rsquo;t support IE7 but that feature is in development beta. Find more info here: http://www.tatanka.com.br/ies4linux/page/Main_Page
Update (Jun 23, 2011):
IEs4Linux now also supports IE7, IE8 and IE9 in beta.
&amp;ndash;
Kartik - The TechGlider Guy
http://www.techglider.in</description></item><item><title>What to do after a new Ubuntu 8.04 Hardy Heron installation?</title><link>techglider.in/post/2008/09/08/what-to-do-after-a-new-ubuntu-8-04-hardy-heron-installation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2008 10:52:09 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2008/09/08/what-to-do-after-a-new-ubuntu-8-04-hardy-heron-installation/</guid><description>After Install Tasks Have your internet connection ready. If you have ADSL (BSNL, Airtel broadband) connection, and you are used connecting using a username and password in windows, then, open up a Terminal (Applications-&amp;gt;Accessories) and give the following command: ``` sudo pppoeconf ``` You will prompted for your password. Then a wizard runs and detects your connection (usually eth0). Accept all the default settings and when prompted type your connection username and password.</description></item><item><title>Fedora 9 Installation Screenshots uploaded</title><link>techglider.in/post/2008/09/05/fedora-9-installation-screenshots-uploaded/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2008 12:59:14 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2008/09/05/fedora-9-installation-screenshots-uploaded/</guid><description>:phew: Finally, the screenshots for Fedora 9 installation have been uploaded (with great difficulty and mess up of my system and internet connection in the last few days).
To view a slide show follow the link: http://www.flickr.com/photos/techglider/sets/72157607119105020/show/
Hope to write a &amp;ldquo;full guide to installing Fedora 9 on your PC&amp;rdquo; by Sunday.</description></item><item><title>It's a Monthiversary!!</title><link>techglider.in/post/2008/08/31/its-a-monthiversary/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Aug 2008 00:03:57 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2008/08/31/its-a-monthiversary/</guid><description>Today, it&amp;rsquo;s been a month I started out posting on this blog.
And I feel happy about it. 11 posts in a month; it may seem too less to some of you, but, for me: I suppose I have been keeping up to my goal of writing regularly (and improving by the day :-) ).
I know I haven&amp;rsquo;t been able to fulfill certain promises I made on the blog viz: guide to installing Ubuntu and unveiling the main TechGlider site.</description></item><item><title>Broadband runs slow?</title><link>techglider.in/post/2008/08/23/broadband-runs-slow/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2008 16:29:19 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2008/08/23/broadband-runs-slow/</guid><description>If you have a broadband connection and find it taking too much time to load websites, you can try this method to make it a lot faster.
As you might be knowing, the web address you type in your browser to visit a particular site first gets resolved into a unique IP address by a DNS server. The default DNS servers your OS uses tend to be very slow. And here&amp;rsquo;s an alternative - OpenDNS.</description></item><item><title>Recommended Addons for Mozilla Firefox</title><link>techglider.in/post/2008/08/17/recommended-addons-for-mozilla-firefox/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2008 07:28:58 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2008/08/17/recommended-addons-for-mozilla-firefox/</guid><description>Here&amp;rsquo;s a list of recommended addons for our favorite Mozilla Firefox web browser: (But first upgrade to latest version of Firefox if you haven&amp;rsquo;t done it yet:http://www.mozilla.com/en-US/firefox/ 8-)
For blocking ads, flash animations and scripts:
Adblock Plus (Don&amp;rsquo;t forget to subscribe to Easylist USA list in the window that pops-up after restarting Firefox) Flashblock NoScript For making your web experience easier:
Download Statusbar DownloadHelper Image Zoom Save Session Taboo For web development:</description></item><item><title>3rd Anniversary of my Gmail experience</title><link>techglider.in/post/2008/08/16/3rd-anniversary-of-my-gmail-experience/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2008 03:28:42 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2008/08/16/3rd-anniversary-of-my-gmail-experience/</guid><description>Today, it&amp;rsquo;s 3 years since the day I opened my Gmail account.
I remember those days when Gmail was in beta (although it&amp;rsquo;s still in beta as the Gmail logo says) and signup for a Gmail account was only by invitation. It was like a privilege to have a Gmail account B). Then, came an invitation from my cousin and I became a proud owner of my Gmail account.
Gmail gave me a lot of things I always desired from using the e-mail:</description></item><item><title>The TechGlider Forums are now active.</title><link>techglider.in/post/2008/08/14/the-techglider-forums-are-now-active/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2008 00:31:56 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2008/08/14/the-techglider-forums-are-now-active/</guid><description>I am glad to inform you that finally the The TechGlider Forums have been activated on techglider.in. :-)
To visit the forums you can go to http://forums.techglider.in. Please read the first topic &amp;ldquo;General Rules&amp;rdquo; before posting anything on the forums.
You can register yourself on the forums by clicking on the &amp;ldquo;Register&amp;rdquo; link at the top-right of the page. After you become a member, you can ask questions, get answers, start new topics for discussions under the given categories and post about anything you like.</description></item><item><title>Tutorials on TechGlider site are fully functional now!</title><link>techglider.in/post/2008/08/11/tutorials-on-techglider-site-are-fully-functional-now/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2008 00:23:26 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2008/08/11/tutorials-on-techglider-site-are-fully-functional-now/</guid><description>After a lot of requests from my friends and those who visited the Tutorials section in the test version of TechGlider site, I have finally uploaded all the available tutorials and this means they are downloadable now!
Visit http://www.techglider.in/tutorials for all available tutorials.
I will publish many more (free) tutorials in that section with some of those written by myself. ;-)
Feel free to post comments if you face any problems.</description></item><item><title>Download whole websites for offline browsing</title><link>techglider.in/post/2008/08/10/download-whole-websites-for-offline-browsing/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2008 03:22:49 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2008/08/10/download-whole-websites-for-offline-browsing/</guid><description>How many times has it happened that you witnessed some great and very useful pages (e.g. tutorials) on some website and had an instant urge if they could be downloaded on your computer so that you don&amp;rsquo;t have to be connected to the net to read them?
Here&amp;rsquo;s a solution for this frequent desire. There&amp;rsquo;s a good tool that can just make this happen :): HTTrack Website Copier
Available for almost all of major Desktop platforms including windows, linux and mac, it&amp;rsquo;s an easy to use tool to make websites run offline on your PC.</description></item><item><title>Various Sources of Getting Linux</title><link>techglider.in/post/2008/08/09/various-sources-of-getting-linux/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2008 03:39:59 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2008/08/09/various-sources-of-getting-linux/</guid><description>Here&amp;rsquo;s a list of various ways following which you can get a linux distro:
The best way, if you have unlimited internet (broadband) access, is to download the ISO image (usually 700 MB in size) from the website of the particular linux distribution and burn it on to a CD or DVD (in case of a DVD image) to install linux. e.g. visit http://www.ubuntu.com/getubuntu/download to choose and download the particular version of Ubuntu for your requirement.</description></item><item><title>Test version of main TechGlider.com site is out!</title><link>techglider.in/post/2008/08/06/test-version-of-main-techglidercom-site-is-out/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2008 16:35:47 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2008/08/06/test-version-of-main-techglidercom-site-is-out/</guid><description>I am pleased to inform you all that I have finally uploaded a test version of the main TechGlider.com site. :-)
As I have mentioned that it&amp;rsquo;s a test version, a lot of download links and the forums link are not working and I am very sorry for that. The main purpose of the test site is to showcase the main design and structure of the future TechGlider site.
You can view the site by clicking on the &amp;ldquo;Visit the main TechGlider site&amp;rdquo; link at the above navigation bar.</description></item></channel></rss>