<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>hugo on The TechGlider</title><link>techglider.in/tags/hugo/</link><description>Recent content in hugo on The TechGlider</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2015 15:42:00 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="techglider.in/tags/hugo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Testing Automatic Deployment with Wercker</title><link>techglider.in/status/2015/03/16/testing-automatic-deployment-with-wercker/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2015 15:42:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/status/2015/03/16/testing-automatic-deployment-with-wercker/</guid><description>While reiniting this website, I had some requirements in mind for easy workflow of adding a post. Yesterday, I spent some time on the awesome tutorial on Automated deployments with Wercker for Hugo contributed by Arjen Schwarz, which seemed promising.
Apart from a tiny status update, this is a test post I am writing using the familiar GitHub&amp;rsquo;s online editor. Let&amp;rsquo;s see how it goes&amp;hellip;
EDIT: Couple of minutes later:</description></item><item><title>Posts from The TechGlider Blog Migrated</title><link>techglider.in/post/2014/10/27/posts-from-the-techglider-blog-migrated/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2014 01:30:58 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2014/10/27/posts-from-the-techglider-blog-migrated/</guid><description>Just a quick note that I have successfully migrated all posts from the original TechGlider Blog which used to reside at http://techglider.in/kartik/blog couple of years ago.
This completes migration of all my written content. Fixing broken links, images, etc. is the major work that remains.
Aside:
I ended up skimming through much of my old content, feels very childish now; my friends from that time might get a laugh or two reading about memories recorded in here.</description></item><item><title>reinit</title><link>techglider.in/post/2014/10/26/reinit/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2014 15:04:13 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2014/10/26/reinit/</guid><description>Today I am relaunching my website - http://techglider.in - in a new avatar. This, in the form of techglider.com, used to be my first website on the Internet until the .com domain was stolen by a domain shark. Sometime later, I switched to writing on wordpress.com and stopped maintaining this site.
A constant feeling of not having an official web home and a permanent place to put my thoughts out for the world has been nagging me for months, this reinit is the first step in solving this problem.</description></item></channel></rss>