<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>post on The TechGlider</title><link>https://techglider.in/categories/post/</link><description>Recent content in post on The TechGlider</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2014 17:53:41 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://techglider.in/categories/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Swaraj by Arvind Kejriwal - A Review</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2014/03/20/swaraj-by-arvind-kejriwal-a-review/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2014 17:53:41 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2014/03/20/swaraj-by-arvind-kejriwal-a-review/</guid><description>Swaraj by Arvind Kejriwal
My rating: 4 of 5 stars
Ended up reading a Hindi book after many years, &amp;lsquo;कथेतर&amp;rsquo; (non-fiction, new word learnt!) on that.
Little Background I haven&amp;rsquo;t followed Kejriwal&amp;rsquo;s or Anna&amp;rsquo;s movement from the beginning. I first gave serious attention when AAP managed to win a substantial number of seats in Delhi last December. Since then, I have come to admire Kejriwal&amp;rsquo;s clarity of thought, his ideas and his mission, all of which can be ascertained in any of his recent interviews or QA&amp;rsquo;s with audience where neither the interviewer nor the public leave any stone unturned to grill him.</description></item><item><title>Week 1 at Bangalore and Work</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2013/07/21/week-1-at-bangalore-and-work/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2013 14:53:31 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2013/07/21/week-1-at-bangalore-and-work/</guid><description>I landed at Bangalore airport last week flying on an indiGo for the first time; found the experience better than JetKonnect from my first flight.
Next day (Sunday) started early with a walk to Oracle Tech Park and back to get myself familiarized with the area before first day at work. A much-needed haircut followed.
Having caught cold with the change in weather, I had to miss the Goodreads meetup planned at Brigade Road during the day, which I was eagerly awaiting to attend with a friend.</description></item><item><title>Of FOSSMeets at NIT Calicut</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2013/04/14/of-fossmeets-at-nit-calicut/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 08:33:41 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2013/04/14/of-fossmeets-at-nit-calicut/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been over a month and a half since the last edition of FOSSMeet at NIT Calicut. As an active member of organizing team for FOSSMeets &amp;lsquo;10 and &amp;lsquo;11 and a keen but silent observer for the 2013 edition, I want to share some history, some ideas &amp;amp; few observations with this post. The intent is to generate discussion among people who have been part of earlier FOSSMeets and to leave some things to ponder about (and act on) for juniors.</description></item><item><title>LaTeX Project Report Template Updated</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2013/02/15/latex-project-report-template-updated/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2013 14:36:40 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2013/02/15/latex-project-report-template-updated/</guid><description>The LaTeX logo (Photo credit: Wikipedia)
This will be quite short.
Many have told me they found the LaTeX Project Report Template that I published about two years back pretty useful. Today, I am releasing an update for the same. This includes a fix for a nasty bug in the original template apart from some layout changes.
Fork it from Github at https://github.com/k4rtik/latex-project-report-template to start creating your project reports.Visit http://k4rtik.</description></item><item><title>Musing over The Challenge</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2013/02/11/musing-over-the-challenge/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2013 07:28:32 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2013/02/11/musing-over-the-challenge/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been 10 days since I started this challenge. Up to now, I seem to be failing in living up to the daily requirement in the Fibonacci order (0, 1, 1, 2 - the day gaps); of course, I don&amp;rsquo;t want the sequence to continue.
In retrospect, I can see what stopped me in the days I missed - once it was just a tiring day, someday it was work/extended meeting, some day just plain lack of creativity.</description></item><item><title>Quickly Check Temperature Values of Hardware Components in Ubuntu</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2013/02/06/quickly-check-temperature-values-of-hardware-components-in-ubuntu/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2013 15:55:08 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2013/02/06/quickly-check-temperature-values-of-hardware-components-in-ubuntu/</guid><description>So, I missed posting yesterday. Hope this doesn&amp;rsquo;t repeat.
Today I am sharing a small bash script I wrote to check the temperatures recorded by various sensors in my laptop. Nothing incredibly smart here, just a quick but useful hack.
I am one of those unhappy Linux users who suffer from lack of driver support for their hardware. Due to some weird kernel bug or messy graphics driver, which led to incredibly high temperatures on my laptop, I spent about a year using Linux as a VirtualBox guest in Windows; this was before Ubuntu 12.</description></item><item><title>Logicomix: An Epic Search for Truth</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2013/02/03/logicomix-an-epic-search-for-truth/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2013 18:52:40 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2013/02/03/logicomix-an-epic-search-for-truth/</guid><description>This one needs to be quick, 14 minutes until midnight.
Logicomix (Photo credit: Wikipedia)
In this post I want to introduce a graphic novel which I read about a year back - Logicomix: An Epic Search for Truth.
How I ended up reading this is an interesting story in itself. Let me try to recite in minimum possible words. During that time (Sem 6) I had enrolled for a course called Computational Complexity by Murali sir.</description></item><item><title>My First and Last 3D SketchUp</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2013/02/02/my-first-and-last-3d-sketchup/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2013 18:25:07 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2013/02/02/my-first-and-last-3d-sketchup/</guid><description>So, here is the first one.
[gallery type=&amp;ldquo;slideshow&amp;rdquo; ids=&amp;ldquo;512,513,514,515,516&amp;rdquo;]
I had created this long back in Decemeber of 2006. The file cab.skp (Google SketchUp file) was lying in my system since ages. Tried opening it today, discovered there is no Linux support for its viewer/editor (you listening Google?). After some fiddling with Wine and finally resorting to spend some time on a friend&amp;rsquo;s Windows Laptop, here we are. Quite a piece of art, ain&amp;rsquo;t it?</description></item><item><title>28 Days Challenge</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2013/02/01/28-days-challenge/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 16:30:02 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2013/02/01/28-days-challenge/</guid><description>Inspired long back by Oliver Emberton&amp;rsquo;s herculian 30 Day Challenger, I have decided to try it out for myself this month. Feb being the smallest month should serve as the easiest possible start. ;-)
The motivation for doing this are similar - stretching myself to give up on a bad habit, get the most out of my day, or being more productive in general.
Given that I have a lot to say, things that keep on forming virtual blog posts in my mind - some of which are technical, some about my dream college, some advice for juniors, some worldly pondering, some internal struggles - I have decided on my first challenge:</description></item><item><title>Best Tool for Downloading YouTube Videos and Playlists</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2012/07/13/best-tool-for-downloading-youtube-videos-and-playlists/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2012 18:30:17 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2012/07/13/best-tool-for-downloading-youtube-videos-and-playlists/</guid><description>How many times does it happen that you stumble upon an awesome youtube video, you make up your mind to download it but fail short to find a good tool which actually works?
In this post I want to introduce one of the best tools for downloading videos from YouTube and other video platforms - youtube-dl. This command line tool is basically just a python script released by its developers in public domain and it works on any platform that supports Python 2.</description></item><item><title>A Fun Security Weekend with null and sCTF</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2012/06/22/a-fun-security-weekend-with-null-and-sctf/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2012 19:39:05 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2012/06/22/a-fun-security-weekend-with-null-and-sctf/</guid><description>I know it&amp;rsquo;s quite late to post about the last weekend when another weekend is around the corner, but couldn&amp;rsquo;t control myself as the last one was so eventful. :)
It was almost 2 weeks back that I got to know about sCTF 2012. I have always wanted to learn about computer security (and the darker side of hacking), but haven&amp;rsquo;t been able to give time it to it. What followed was a quick search for team members from among my batch via FB - Nithin immediately showed interest, we pulled Jerrin in too.</description></item><item><title>(Bangalore) Summer of '12... with BeagleBone</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2012/06/13/bangalore-summer-of-12-with-beaglebone/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2012 16:42:13 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2012/06/13/bangalore-summer-of-12-with-beaglebone/</guid><description>This post will be slightly long. Lots of exciting things happening over a Bangalore summer this year for me. :D
Somehow I always wanted to learn more about hardware and with a mentor like Khasim the road seems a lot more exciting. I first met him when he came to conduct a workshop on BeagleBoard during Tathva 2009 at my college - NIT Calicut. I was just a fresher then and have since regretted that I could not attend that workshop completely (due to my participation in various CS related competitions).</description></item><item><title>Ponderings of the Year Past: Part 2</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2012/03/26/ponderings-of-the-year-past-part-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2012 21:03:03 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2012/03/26/ponderings-of-the-year-past-part-2/</guid><description>The following are few important lessons I learnt over the gone year – 2011 (see Part 1 here):
Friends To be very frank (and you can call me weird), I didn&amp;rsquo;t know the meaning of a close friend until about early 2011. As far as I remember, until first semester, definition of a friend for me was somebody who shared similar interests, mutual respect, and trust. I remember objecting to Rama to call him names (in return of his such various favors) by saying &amp;ldquo;dude, I respect you!</description></item><item><title>Ponderings of the Year Past: Part 1</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2012/03/26/ponderings-of-the-year-past-part-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2012 19:59:28 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2012/03/26/ponderings-of-the-year-past-part-1/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been long since I wrote something. To be frank, it was last July in which I actually spoke out my mind. Of course, I wished to write a lot more (who doesn&amp;rsquo;t). This one is going to be long, so I decided to partition it.
The following are few important lessons I learnt over the gone year - 2011:
Computer Science != Computer Engineering Vineeth Sir always calls it Computing Science, we even had a discussion over it, perhaps over a year back( and once again recently); the doubt got cleared up only after I looked up ACM&amp;rsquo;s Computing Curricula Recommendations which defines five sub-disciplines of computing: Computer Science, Computer Engineering, Information Systems, Information Technology, and Software Engineering (they have pretty decent comparisons among these disciplines using pictures and charts).</description></item><item><title>Control All Computers in a Lab from a Single System</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2012/02/12/control-all-computers-in-a-lab-from-a-single-system/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2012 03:10:21 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2012/02/12/control-all-computers-in-a-lab-from-a-single-system/</guid><description>Quoting Dhandeep, our super-cool lab-admin:
now , all 70 systems in the lab can be switched on and switched off by single commands from the hostel&amp;hellip;
Yes, that and a lot more is possible in our Software Systems Lab now. How? Read on&amp;hellip;
The Setup We have over 70 systems with Ubuntu 10.04 LTS installed on them. There is an administrative account (let&amp;rsquo;s call it admin for this post) and a guest (limited privilege) account on each.</description></item><item><title>Build EiskaltDC++ on Fedora 15 Lovelock 64-bit</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2011/10/06/build-eiskaltdc-on-fedora-16-lovelock-64-bit/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2011 07:19:04 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2011/10/06/build-eiskaltdc-on-fedora-16-lovelock-64-bit/</guid><description>EiskaltDC++ is a cross-platform program that uses the Direct Connect and ADC protocol. The direct connect client LinuxDC++ available in rpmfusion repos doesn&amp;rsquo;t yet support ADC protocol and hence doesn&amp;rsquo;t work with the DC++ Hub that has been setup in our hostel. I had to compile Eiskalt from the sources. Posting here the steps I had to follow for a rather painful build.
I am using Fedora 15 64-bit with GNOME 3 desktop.</description></item><item><title>Of Corruption, India, and My First Bribe</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2011/07/15/of-corruption-india-and-my-first-bribe/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2011 12:50:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2011/07/15/of-corruption-india-and-my-first-bribe/</guid><description>It was this Monday when I visited Rath mam with my friend Arvis. Rath mam had just returned from US after visiting both her children who are well settled in US working in IT companies. Somehow that day our discussion went on to what me and Arvis plan to do in the future after college. Mam was telling us why we should think about moving outside India for higher studies. She stated three important reasons why India is not yet the best place to lead life for those with some moral support system:</description></item><item><title>Remove Orphaned Actions in Drupal 7</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2011/07/14/remove-orphaned-actions-in-drupal-7/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2011 16:41:53 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2011/07/14/remove-orphaned-actions-in-drupal-7/</guid><description>I recently discovered this weird behaviour by drush when I disabled Comment module in Drupal 7 - drush was giving the following warning whenever I tried enabling/disabling any module:
WD actions: 3 orphaned actions (comment_publish_action, comment_save_action, comment_unpublish_action) exist in the actions table. Remove orphaned actions After some scrounging on drupal.org (where most solutions were meant for Drupal 6), I found the solution at http://blog.devkinetic.com/node/9 Just execute the following once:
drush php-eval &amp;#34;actions_synchronize(actions_list(), TRUE);&amp;#34;</description></item><item><title>Disconnect - An Experiment</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2011/07/10/disconnect-an-experiment/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2011 18:37:01 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2011/07/10/disconnect-an-experiment/</guid><description>This will be short.
A small announcement: I will be out of touch for about a week on the Internet. Disconnected on all social networks (including twitter) and off-line on chats (including GMail chat) and unavailable on SMS. I have already disabled all email and SMS notifications from the social networks. This is just for the sake of experimenting to see if I can still live without social media, so don&amp;rsquo;t get weird ideas about this.</description></item><item><title>The Great Indian Jugaad</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2011/05/30/the-great-indian-jugaad/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2011 15:08:26 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2011/05/30/the-great-indian-jugaad/</guid><description>Just spotted this unique and innovative use of cheap UPS batteries in the local vegetable market (sabzi mandi) near my home at Ghaziabad. I could see dozens of these lamps in a row in the market. At a place like ours with such severe power cuts, this seems like a good alternative for the vegetable vendors.</description></item><item><title>Choosing an Android Phone - Not an Easy Job</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2011/05/23/choosing-an-android-phone-not-an-easy-job/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2011 16:42:51 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2011/05/23/choosing-an-android-phone-not-an-easy-job/</guid><description>Little background It&amp;rsquo;s almost a month now since I sold my old Nokia N72 (fondly named PlatiniumJunior by me), hoping to buy an Android-based smartphone soon. Since then, I have realized how dependent I was on the phone - thinking of taking a quick snap and realizing I don&amp;rsquo;t have a camera anymore is disappointing, same is getting stuck at a word while reading and missing that MSDict software on my phone which was always ready as a quick reference, similar is being jobless at places I am forced to visit at times (or when there were power outages of countless hours at home, more on this in another post) and missing the phone again which I could use to read some or other ebook.</description></item><item><title>The Next Generation of Makers</title><link>https://techglider.in/quote/2011/04/08/the-next-generation-of-makers-2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2011 09:49:41 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/quote/2011/04/08/the-next-generation-of-makers-2/</guid><description>I know the future is what I make it.
I believe I can make the world better.
I understand I need knowledge and passion.
I choose to participate, not observe.
I work with my hands and my mind.
I pursue beauty in what I produce.
I see art in science and science in art.
I value skills.
I am the next generation of Maker!
&amp;mdash;Source: http://www.</description></item><item><title>Really Achieving Your Childhood Dreams - The Last Lecture</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2011/03/09/really-achieving-your-childhood-dreams-the-last-lecture/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2011 19:01:21 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2011/03/09/really-achieving-your-childhood-dreams-the-last-lecture/</guid><description>I finally got a chance to watch this wonderful talk (by Randy Pausch) popularly known as The Last Lecture. I wanted to watch this for a long time - since Anjhan mentioned about it in his keynote at foss.in and since Prateek Kalyankar had recommended this to me in Jan.
A really nice watch for anyone who has ever dreamed and thought of fulfilling them. I was particularly amazed to see a youthful, energetic, handsome Randy deliver that talk in such a cheerful, darkly funny way, while being just a few months away from his death (and knowing it!</description></item><item><title>The Branch Tour 2011 and me (Part 2)</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2011/03/01/the-branch-tour-2011-and-me-part-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 02:30:42 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2011/03/01/the-branch-tour-2011-and-me-part-2/</guid><description>This is second and the last part of my earlier post - The Branch Tour 2011 and me. Please read my last post before reading this.
Disclaimer: The following post is dedicated to all my branch mates and is a little more on the personal side. Additionally, the post is too long and may not be of any relevance for those who seek to attain any bit of technical nirvana from this blog.</description></item><item><title>Building a Modern Computer in 12 Steps - A Perfect Elective Course for Sem 3 of CSE</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2011/02/28/building-a-modern-computer-in-12-steps-a-perfect-elective-course-for-sem-3-of-cse/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2011 17:01:40 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2011/02/28/building-a-modern-computer-in-12-steps-a-perfect-elective-course-for-sem-3-of-cse/</guid><description>Just watched this Google Tech Talk on From Nand to Tetris in 12 steps by Shimon Schocken introducing a course he developed along with Noam Nisan:
A must watch for all CS faculty of hardware, algorithms and systems.
The course covers 12 projects to be done over a single semester covering building everything from basic logic gates to computer architecture, and from machine language to an operating system starting from a False and a NAND using a custom HDL.</description></item><item><title>The Branch Tour 2011 and me (Part 1)</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2011/02/28/the-branch-tour-2011-and-me-part-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2011 02:30:13 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2011/02/28/the-branch-tour-2011-and-me-part-1/</guid><description>Disclaimer: The following post is dedicated to all my branch mates and is a little more on the personal side. Additionally, the post is too long and may not be of any relevance for those who seek to attain any bit of technical nirvana from this blog. So, you may happily TLDR this post.
Many have asked me why I decided to go for branch tour when almost none of the northies were ready to go.</description></item><item><title>Input/Output using Text Files Without Diving into File Handling</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2011/02/10/inputoutput-using-text-files-without-diving-into-file-handling/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2011 10:18:08 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2011/02/10/inputoutput-using-text-files-without-diving-into-file-handling/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s quite easy to use text files as input source or to redirect the output of programs to files if you happen to do programming on a unix/linux terminal.
Let&amp;rsquo;s take an example of a usual random number generator:
// random.c #include &amp;lt;stdio.h&amp;gt;#include &amp;lt;stdlib.h&amp;gt;int main () { int i, count=99999999; for (i = 0; i &amp;lt; count; i += 1) printf(&amp;#34;%d\n&amp;#34;, (int)random()); return 0; } Let&amp;rsquo;s generate an executable by the name random.</description></item><item><title>Accessing NIT Calicut's Ubuntu Mirror (in the campus)</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2011/02/01/accessing-nit-calicuts-ubuntu-mirror-in-the-campus/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 01:20:47 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2011/02/01/accessing-nit-calicuts-ubuntu-mirror-in-the-campus/</guid><description>As the FOSSCell webserver has been facing troubles these days, the instructions to use the Ubuntu Mirror of NIT Calicut that were available on the FOSSCell wiki are being missed by many. Here they are though not in the informative way as were given on the wiki:
Add the following to your /etc/apt/sources.list and comment out other similar repos.
deb http://192.168.40.97/ubuntu lucid-updates main multiverse restricted universe deb http://192.168.40.97/ubuntu lucid-security main multiverse restricted universe deb http://192.</description></item><item><title>Drupal 7 Exploration</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2011/01/23/drupal-7-exploration/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Jan 2011 12:51:45 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2011/01/23/drupal-7-exploration/</guid><description>I finally managed to install Drupal 7 on my Arch Linux Desktop after some difficulty, but feels like I learned a lot in the meantime.</description></item><item><title>The Pleasure of Finding Things Out</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2011/01/05/the-pleasure-of-finding-things-out/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2011 20:25:41 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2011/01/05/the-pleasure-of-finding-things-out/</guid><description>Just watched this video whose link I got from Anjhan&amp;rsquo;s blog, an interview of Richard Feynman. I started out to watch only the first 10 minutes but really couldn&amp;rsquo;t stop myself to watch the whole thing (although I have to attend class at 8 AM). Must watch for the curious thinker, the scientist, the hacker.</description></item><item><title>One last post on my Posterous</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2010/12/24/one-last-post-on-my-posterous/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Dec 2010 21:07:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2010/12/24/one-last-post-on-my-posterous/</guid><description>I started out with Posterous 6 months back mainly to just try it out. After inactivity for about 3 months, I started posting regularly here. I have tried different kinds of posts in this period - with photos, code listings, even other type of attachments. But after my last post I was rather disappointed with Posterous and decided to move on to some other blogging platform. So, this is the last post here and I want to present my observations.</description></item><item><title>Replaced my Studio XPS screen and palm rest</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2010/12/23/replaced-my-studio-xps-screen-and-palm-rest/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2010 11:47:26 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2010/12/23/replaced-my-studio-xps-screen-and-palm-rest/</guid><description>Got my laptop screen and palm rest, touch pad replaced :) But all my stickers - Drupal, Hacker Logo, Python, Firefox, Core i7, Windows 7 - and RMS&amp;rsquo; signature are gone :(</description></item><item><title>LaTeX Project Report Template</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2010/11/13/latex-project-report-template/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2010 05:39:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2010/11/13/latex-project-report-template/</guid><description>UPDATE RELEASED - Please use the latest version for all the LaTeX goodness.
Last week, starting from Sunday was spent in preparing my first project report in college and first using LaTeX. It took me over four days to finish the work. The end result was quite good and impressive. (See the attached report.pdf if you want to take a look).I abstracted a template from the report for future use. Hope it may be find some use for other NITCians or in general for everyone.</description></item><item><title>Recover files deleted from GNU/Linux</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2010/11/06/recover-files-deleted-from-gnulinux/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Nov 2010 15:43:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2010/11/06/recover-files-deleted-from-gnulinux/</guid><description>It was an embarassing today that after making a presentation on Drupal and promising the audience to distribute the presentation file after the session, I deleted it accidentally.
And all my fears regarding Linux being so different when it came to file recovery (unlike Windows, where you had a choice of many recovery software) and it was next to impossible to undelete files from linux, seemed to come true. A quick search in Ubuntu Software Center listed a software called &amp;lsquo;recover&amp;rsquo; which was meant only for ext2 partitions, and mine being ext4 I was hopeless.</description></item><item><title>First Hands-on with Assembly Language Programming</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2010/10/25/first-hands-on-with-assembly-language-programming/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2010 09:46:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2010/10/25/first-hands-on-with-assembly-language-programming/</guid><description>I always wanted to learn assembly language programming. I had never tried do it myself and was disappointed to know that it was not there in our Logic Design course this semester (this because it was mentioned in the syllabus and I had taken pains to find good books on assembly from the library and get them issued, just to return them after learning that the syllabus for the course was too less compared to what was given on the department&amp;rsquo;s website).</description></item><item><title>Installing 64-bit version of Flash Player on Fedora 13</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2010/10/16/installing-64-bit-version-of-flash-player-on-fedora-13/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Oct 2010 17:18:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2010/10/16/installing-64-bit-version-of-flash-player-on-fedora-13/</guid><description>I have been using Fedora 64-bit KDE for many months now, but was too lazy to install flash player (I don&amp;rsquo;t usually need it as I am no YouTube junkie) until now. But today I had to visit some sites whose content seemed next to none without flash plugin on my browser. This forced me to install flash player finally.
Such a person who always wants to remain at the cutting edge as I am, I tried installing the latest Flash Player &amp;ldquo;Square&amp;rdquo; Preview Release 64-bit available from Adobe Labs.</description></item><item><title>Using gdb to see through your program flow!</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2010/10/05/using-gdb-to-see-through-your-program-flow/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2010 11:37:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2010/10/05/using-gdb-to-see-through-your-program-flow/</guid><description>Using GDB was something I wanted to learn since I started programming in GNU/Linux environment. I read through man pages, info pages, and some vague guides on the net over the weeks but couldn&amp;rsquo;t figure out why wasn&amp;rsquo;t I able to use it properly.
Then somehow I found this: RMS&amp;rsquo;s gdb Debugger Tutorial and learned that the I was making a very small mistake every time while compiling the code.</description></item><item><title>Ubuntu Tips and Tricks - Part 1</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2010/09/25/ubuntu-tips-and-tricks-part-1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Sep 2010 09:53:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2010/09/25/ubuntu-tips-and-tricks-part-1/</guid><description>Just learned some new commands on Ubuntu:
If sometime you get into a (big!) trouble such as the Gnome panels not loading but the desktop is visible, you can open the gnome-terminal using the key combination Ctrl + Alt + T (of course this is a good shortcut for normal desktop usage too).
Because of the above problem, you may want to create a bootable drive to reinstall Ubuntu, but how do you do that as you cannot load the Ubuntu Startup Disk Creator?</description></item><item><title>Software Freedom Day 2010 at NIT Calicut</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2010/09/18/software-freedom-day-2010-at-nit-calicut/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2010 21:55:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2010/09/18/software-freedom-day-2010-at-nit-calicut/</guid><description>I am a member of the Free and Open Source Software Users group - FOSSCell - at my college - NIT Calicut. We celebrated Software Freedom Day yesterday for the first time.
We started planning for the celebration on our mailing list 5 days ago. Amid a lot of heated discussions we kept on updating the FOSSCell wiki ( http://fosscell.nitc.ac.in/wiki ) with our ideas, plans, suggestions, names of attendees and volunteers.</description></item><item><title>My first Posterous Blog post</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2010/06/18/my-first-posterous-blog-post/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2010 04:23:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2010/06/18/my-first-posterous-blog-post/</guid><description>Now this seems quite interesting. I had been noticing posterous here and there for a lot of time but never cared to look what it is about. But just now I followed the link in an RT posted by Atul Chitnis on twitter that led me to learn the concept behind this service. The link was:
I laughed at Posterous, but they proved me wrong - http://blog.dustincurtis.com/i-dont-laugh-at-startup-ideas-anymore
Got some lesson to learn from the story of posterous.</description></item><item><title>My Old Projects</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2009/11/08/my-old-projects/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2009 11:00:33 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2009/11/08/my-old-projects/</guid><description>DAV Public School Website - Done in class 9 (2004) This website was done by me when I was studying in standard 9. As a product of an inter house web design competition (which yours truly won while facing other participants who were all seniors ranging from classes 10 to 12), this website inspired me to step further into web design. Download zip (598.81 KB) | Browse here
DAV Public School Website - Done in class 10 (2005) This was just a renovated version of the older site but with a lot of loaded content, included some videos of the school.</description></item><item><title>Use the World Class IDE and Compiler for C++ for Free</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2008/03/24/use-the-world-class-ide-and-compiler-for-c-for-free/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2008 23:17:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2008/03/24/use-the-world-class-ide-and-compiler-for-c-for-free/</guid><description>I know you have been using around 20 years old Borland Turbo C++ IDE for quiet a lot of time now. The one with blue screen and big characters that runs on DOS environment. Its editor is sometimes a pain in the neck and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t run on Vista. Well let&amp;rsquo;s get back to the present. Who needs to use Turbo C++ (Ver 3.0) when a world class IDE like Microsoft Visual Studio 2008 Express Edition is available for free.</description></item><item><title>Use Dictionary and Pronunciation Guide on your PC</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2008/03/12/use-dictionary-and-pronunciation-guide-on-your-pc/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2008 20:55:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2008/03/12/use-dictionary-and-pronunciation-guide-on-your-pc/</guid><description>This is for those of you interested in improving their English skills and find it cumbersome to searching for meanings of words by turning over the pages of dictionary. If you work on your PC most of the time, then you can utilize it to improve on your vocabulary and pronunciation skills:
If you have a net connection and are online most of the time, then the best option is to use Google as a dictionary tool:</description></item><item><title>My First Post and Myself Poured Out for the Day</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2008/03/11/my-first-post-and-myself-poured-out-for-the-day/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2008 00:23:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2008/03/11/my-first-post-and-myself-poured-out-for-the-day/</guid><description>Well, just letting this start off. My desire to have a blog is pushing me to start it now; just in the middle of my XII Class Boards Examinations. Just had my English paper today; went bad somehow. May be I was just thinking of myself as a great writer who can never fail. But all just went bad and I don&amp;rsquo;t know. I completed all the stuff that was asked in the paper but don&amp;rsquo;t know why I didn&amp;rsquo;t get the feeling of satisfaction after the examination was over.</description></item></channel></rss>