<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>foss on The TechGlider</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/tags/foss/</link><description>Recent content in foss on The TechGlider</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 10:51:01 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/tags/foss/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Things I wish I knew in College</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2016/10/01/things-i-wish-i-knew-in-college/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 10:51:01 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2016/10/01/things-i-wish-i-knew-in-college/</guid><description>Meta About a month ago, I asked the following question to the NIT Calicut CSE student body:
If you could ask only one question to an NITC CSE alumnus with diverse experience in industry, higher studies, and research, what would you?
The most raised concerns were:
How to decide between higher studies and industry as your next career move? What are the limitations of an NITC CSE education and how to succeed in the field despite them?</description></item><item><title>Of FOSSMeets at NIT Calicut</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2013/04/14/of-fossmeets-at-nit-calicut/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 08:33:41 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2013/04/14/of-fossmeets-at-nit-calicut/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been over a month and a half since the last edition of FOSSMeet at NIT Calicut. As an active member of organizing team for FOSSMeets &amp;lsquo;10 and &amp;lsquo;11 and a keen but silent observer for the 2013 edition, I want to share some history, some ideas &amp;amp; few observations with this post. The intent is to generate discussion among people who have been part of earlier FOSSMeets and to leave some things to ponder about (and act on) for juniors.</description></item><item><title>LaTeX Project Report Template Updated</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2013/02/15/latex-project-report-template-updated/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2013 14:36:40 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2013/02/15/latex-project-report-template-updated/</guid><description>The LaTeX logo (Photo credit: Wikipedia)
This will be quite short.
Many have told me they found the LaTeX Project Report Template that I published about two years back pretty useful. Today, I am releasing an update for the same. This includes a fix for a nasty bug in the original template apart from some layout changes.
Fork it from Github at https://github.com/k4rtik/latex-project-report-template to start creating your project reports.Visit http://k4rtik.</description></item><item><title>Easiest Way to Setup a Web Development Environment on Ubuntu-based Distros</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2011/07/08/easiest-way-to-setup-a-web-development-environment-on-ubuntu-based-distros/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2011 18:30:21 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2011/07/08/easiest-way-to-setup-a-web-development-environment-on-ubuntu-based-distros/</guid><description>Did you know how easy it is to get a basic web development environment on your Ubuntu-based Linux distribution? Guess what, it just takes 2 commands on the Terminal:
sudo apt-get install tasksel This will install a small utility which lets you install a lot packages grouped together as software collections.
sudo tasksel Launch tasksel and select &amp;lsquo;LAMP server&amp;rsquo; by pressing the SPACE key, press ENTER when you are done (see attached screenshot).</description></item><item><title>Root Samsung Galaxy S i9000 running GINGERBREAD.DDJV6 using Ubuntu Linux</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2011/06/21/root-samsung-galaxy-s-i9000-running-gingerbread-ddjv6-using-ubuntu-linux/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2011 17:01:54 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2011/06/21/root-samsung-galaxy-s-i9000-running-gingerbread-ddjv6-using-ubuntu-linux/</guid><description>I bought a Samsung Galaxy S i9000 just last month. The most prominent reason to buy an Android phone was that it&amp;rsquo;s based on Linux and I love the UNIX-based OS. Besides, Android as a platform provides so many opportunities into application development (and even kernel hacking) that I was simply tempted to buy one since last year.
I have explored the phone since I got my hands on it - trying various apps, playing with 3G internet speeds (3.</description></item><item><title>Recover files deleted from GNU/Linux</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2010/11/06/recover-files-deleted-from-gnulinux/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Nov 2010 15:43:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2010/11/06/recover-files-deleted-from-gnulinux/</guid><description>It was an embarassing today that after making a presentation on Drupal and promising the audience to distribute the presentation file after the session, I deleted it accidentally.
And all my fears regarding Linux being so different when it came to file recovery (unlike Windows, where you had a choice of many recovery software) and it was next to impossible to undelete files from linux, seemed to come true. A quick search in Ubuntu Software Center listed a software called &amp;lsquo;recover&amp;rsquo; which was meant only for ext2 partitions, and mine being ext4 I was hopeless.</description></item><item><title>Software Freedom Day 2010 at NIT Calicut</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2010/09/18/software-freedom-day-2010-at-nit-calicut/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2010 21:55:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2010/09/18/software-freedom-day-2010-at-nit-calicut/</guid><description>I am a member of the Free and Open Source Software Users group - FOSSCell - at my college - NIT Calicut. We celebrated Software Freedom Day yesterday for the first time.
We started planning for the celebration on our mailing list 5 days ago. Amid a lot of heated discussions we kept on updating the FOSSCell wiki ( http://fosscell.nitc.ac.in/wiki ) with our ideas, plans, suggestions, names of attendees and volunteers.</description></item><item><title>FOSS and LAMP Workshop at ABES by ILUG-D</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2008/08/27/foss-and-lamp-workshop-at-abes-by-ilug-d/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2008 16:15:45 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2008/08/27/foss-and-lamp-workshop-at-abes-by-ilug-d/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been more than 10 days since I last posted &amp;lsquo;cause I was (and am) following a very busy schedule.
A lot happened in these days. The most prominent event among many was the LAMP workshop by the India Linux Users&amp;rsquo; Group, Delhi held on August 23, 2008 at ABES Engineering College.
I was trying to get a fully working linux distro installed on my PC since I first assembled my PC back in December 2006.</description></item></channel></rss>