<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>In Real Life on The TechGlider</title><link>https://techglider.in/categories/in-real-life/</link><description>Recent content in In Real Life on The TechGlider</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2011 05:41:22 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://techglider.in/categories/in-real-life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Story of the TechGlider</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2011/03/26/the-story-of-the-techglider/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2011 05:41:22 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2011/03/26/the-story-of-the-techglider/</guid><description>Hi all, In this post I will be sharing some interesting points that fell along during realization of my idea of the TechGlider.First of all I am sharing some initial hand-drawn logos for the site. These were shared with my friend Arvis on June 28, 2009 for his comments.
The following was the outcome of earlier designs on July 5, 2009:
The following is a screenshot of StudenTech.</description></item><item><title>...and, we're back!</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2011/03/13/and-we-are-back/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2011 07:43:51 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2011/03/13/and-we-are-back/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been so long - missing the TechGlider - my dream, my hard work of over 2 years was gone. Started in July 2008, gone in July 2010. :(
The reason of this long absence: I lost the ownership of the domain techglider.com - partly because of my own carelessness, and partly because of my webhost Four &amp;lsquo;S&amp;rsquo; Tech&amp;rsquo;s troubles. In the process, I did learn a few interesting things like the concept of drop catching, how the companies like GoDaddy make so much money; and more importantly how not to lose my domain again.</description></item><item><title>The Story of the LAN at A</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2010/07/02/the-story-of-the-lan-at-a/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2010 04:46:38 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2010/07/02/the-story-of-the-lan-at-a/</guid><description>The following post was supposed to be published on Feb 28, 2010. But due to my procrastination and the importance of this I am finally publishing it now after so much time has passed.
So, finally, the much awaited (and the answer to the most asked question to me: Abe, kab aa raha hai&amp;hellip;?) - LAN is here at A Hostel, my hostel at NIT Calicut.
It all started with a challenge I accepted from Aakash to bring the LAN to A Hostel within month of starting of second sem.</description></item><item><title>My Airtel Woes</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2010/04/03/my-airtel-woes/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2010 18:29:11 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2010/04/03/my-airtel-woes/</guid><description>I had bought a new Airtel SIM on Feb 8, just after FOSSMeet was over. Why? Because my previous SIM was incompatible with my N72 (Platinium Junior, let&amp;rsquo;s call it PJ for convenience). How? It said &amp;lsquo;Invalid SIM&amp;rsquo; on switching it on with the SIM (although somehow I had managed one whole semester with the same SIM in the PJ as the damned thing worked on restarting the phone 2-3 times, but in December I realized, the SIM can&amp;rsquo;t go far with PJ anymore).</description></item><item><title>Missing writing on the blog</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2010/03/27/missing-writing-on-the-blog/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2010 08:50:12 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2010/03/27/missing-writing-on-the-blog/</guid><description>You may have noticed I have written almost nothing after November last year.
The main reason has been some or other problem with my website&amp;rsquo;s hosting server until it was shifted to another one in early Feb. But after this happened it&amp;rsquo;s some strange problem in the campus network that my website is only accessible at certain unexpected times as now. While writing this I am not sure, I will be able to publish this post or not, as the site seems accessible at completely random times and duration.</description></item><item><title>Adventure on our first visit to an airport</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2010/03/09/adventure-on-our-first-visit-to-an-airport/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2010 13:09:34 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2010/03/09/adventure-on-our-first-visit-to-an-airport/</guid><description>On Friday, I along with my friend Amit (aka Pandey) went to the Kozhikode airport to receive the guest Mr. Aditya Sengupta of FOSSEE, IIT Bombay. This was our first chance to visit an airport. We went in a taxi provided by IEEE Students Branch of our college. The peculiar thing about the taxi was its name: Taxi Kinglikutty (pardon me if I am messing up the name).
We reached 15 minutes earlier than the scheduled time of arrival and found that the flight was delayed by 20 minutes.</description></item><item><title>Status Update: Feb 26, 2010</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2010/02/26/status-update-feb-26-2010/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2010 08:15:14 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2010/02/26/status-update-feb-26-2010/</guid><description>BUSY: Setting up LAN at A Hostel (yay!)
BUSY: Exams start on Wednesday March 3; worrying when to start study ;)
BUSY: Trying to design a database to be used in CSED&amp;rsquo;s website
BUSY: Thinking when to read the book The Hitchhiker&amp;rsquo;s Guide to the Galaxy by Douglas Adams which has been chosen by me for a review
BUSY: Thinking what date to reserve train tickets to home after end sems</description></item><item><title>Going home after 135 days</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2009/11/29/going-home-after-135-days/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2009 17:23:55 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2009/11/29/going-home-after-135-days/</guid><description>This post will be short.
After spending more than 4 months here at NIT Calicut, I am finally going back home.
This period starting from AIEEE 2009 counseling in July has been an amazing roller coaster ride for me. Many wonderful things happened with me. I got admission to a college whose image I had always seen in my dreams. That too in the same branch, i.e. Computer Science &amp;amp; Engineering, except for which I knew I could never excel in any other engineering branch.</description></item><item><title>Tathva and the Seniors - Part 1</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2009/11/20/tathva-and-the-seniors-part-1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2009 17:55:21 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2009/11/20/tathva-and-the-seniors-part-1/</guid><description>OK, I agree, it&amp;rsquo;s been too late to post about Tathva. But I had this post in mind since the end of Tathva on October 25, 2009. This is the time, when I am quitting my procrastination and I am free from the daily schedule and writing this post.
First of all, let me talk about the Lecture Series at Tathva &amp;lsquo;09. It started with Dr. APJ Abdul Kalam visiting the campus, and continued with talks by Dr.</description></item><item><title>This is How a Budding Engineer Searches for his Glasses</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2009/11/15/this-is-how-a-budding-engineer-searches-for-his-glasses/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2009 08:34:33 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2009/11/15/this-is-how-a-budding-engineer-searches-for-his-glasses/</guid><description>Just spotted this on the unofficial Notice Board of Hostel A (my hostel at NIT Calicut). Please click on the pics to enlarge:
Disclaimer: The names and other sensitive info has been smudged to preserve the person&amp;rsquo;s privacy.
This left me wondering of the creative minds of my hostel mates. And yeah, if you find his specs, please return them. You can post a comment here and ask me to help you return the glasses ;).</description></item><item><title>Dr. APJ Abdul Kalam's visit to NIT Calicut</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2009/10/15/dr-apj-abdul-kalams-visit-to-nit-calicut/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2009 16:29:33 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2009/10/15/dr-apj-abdul-kalams-visit-to-nit-calicut/</guid><description>It was this day, that I was waiting for almost a month now. Dr. APJ Abdul Kalam visiting the campus of National Institute of Technology Calicut, my college.
And, it was just yesternight and today&amp;rsquo;s morning, that I was so excited to get his one glimpse in front of my eyes. Everything in the campus seemed so good yesterday, with all the decorations, lightings and preparations in Open Air Theatre (OAT) and near Aryabhatta Hall.</description></item><item><title>Why I use Twitter? And why not Orkut or Facebook?</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2009/10/11/why-i-use-twitter-and-why-not-orkut-or-facebook/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2009 16:05:28 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2009/10/11/why-i-use-twitter-and-why-not-orkut-or-facebook/</guid><description>So, it all started in 2006 when I was in class 11. The wave of orkut. I still remember, how I missed all the fun, when during the vacations after class X boards, most of my friends got broadband connections at their homes and started using orkut and became so close with each other and even with girls. I came to know of orkut only when it was too late sometime at the end of August 2006.</description></item><item><title>Wish I was at Shaastra 2009 HackFest</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2009/10/03/wish-i-was-at-shaastra-2009-hackfest/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2009 16:37:42 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2009/10/03/wish-i-was-at-shaastra-2009-hackfest/</guid><description>Was just reading my twitter timeline when my eyes dropped on this tweet by Atul Chitnis:
achitnis: Small report about my talk at the IITM on the 1st: http://tinyurl.com/yaa58xe
The link points to Shaastra 2009 Hackfest – Day 1. After reading this page, I realize I have missed a great chance.
It was this last Saturady, I was trying so hard to get a railway ticket to Chennai to visit Shaastra 2009 at IIT Madras.</description></item><item><title>The TechGlider Blog is back</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2009/10/03/the-techglider-blog-is-back/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2009 09:11:09 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2009/10/03/the-techglider-blog-is-back/</guid><description>I am really happy to announce that I have been able to restore the TGB successfully (after fiddling with the backups for almost a month). This period of two and a half months without my blog was really unbearable for me; the only thing that helped me bear this pain was what was happening in my real life. A lot of wonderful events have changed my life (e.g. I have taken admission in BTech CSE at NIT Calicut).</description></item><item><title>Chhole Bekaar Waale...??</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2009/07/16/chhole-bekaar-waale/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2009 23:14:21 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2009/07/16/chhole-bekaar-waale/</guid><description>Just spotted on this in Navyug Market (Ghaziabad) yesterday:
I visited Navyug Market yesterday with Mukul for some quick and cheap photostats (@ Rs. 0.75 per page). After coming out of the shop, Mukul pointed towards this vendor which caught my eye.
I was bit in a hurry but couldn&amp;rsquo;t stop the temptation of taking a snap. I asked the vendor whether I could take a photo. The Chhole Wala (in the center) agreed with a smile and said &amp;ldquo;Arrey kyun nahin?</description></item><item><title>No! Not again!</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2009/05/22/no-not-again/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2009 05:16:56 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2009/05/22/no-not-again/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s just been a week, since I set up my PlatiniumV2 in the working order by installing Windows 7 Release Candidate and Ubuntu 9.04 after getting my graphics card (A Palit ATi Radeon X800 GTO, 256 MB DDR) repaired. And, it seems like I am going to be in trouble again.
What actually happened before:
When I previously installed Windows 7 Beta, around at the starting of March, I noticed that in a few days a weird kind of horizontal lines started appearing on my screen.</description></item><item><title>And hence, I used my right to vote</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2009/05/11/and-hence-i-used-my-right-to-vote/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2009 04:15:51 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2009/05/11/and-hence-i-used-my-right-to-vote/</guid><description>So I did it, and for the first time. You won&amp;rsquo;t believe when I write that I was way too excited to do this for almost a month.
Ok let me make things clear: I voted for the first time.
I am 19 and as many other adolescents was excited to be able to vote after turning 18. But last year I didn&amp;rsquo;t get my EPIC (Elector&amp;rsquo;s Photo Identity Card) as you are supposed to be 18 on January 1st of the year to be eligible for voting.</description></item><item><title>Surprise and some news</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2009/04/30/surprise-and-some-news/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2009 05:15:42 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2009/04/30/surprise-and-some-news/</guid><description>Hi, there!
I am back. I am feeling very glad to write after this long period of 3 months.
First of all I would like to tell you about a surprise I got today. I was just checking out the stats of techglider.in to see what are the pages that are popular and being most viewed. One nifty feature of the statistics program I use is that it shows the search phrases that lead to my website.</description></item><item><title>Too busy to write a post</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2009/01/30/too-busy-to-write-a-post/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2009 02:23:02 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2009/01/30/too-busy-to-write-a-post/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a lot of time (53 days, to be exact) since I last wrote.
But it&amp;rsquo;s how it is, I have been busy and I am busy with studies atleast for another 3 months. And I am happy about it.
A lot has happened in between - that includes my leaving the room at Kalu Sarai (and start of the &amp;ldquo;then usual&amp;rdquo; up-downs from home to IIT Gate for classes); a lot of AITS tests which went bad as compared to my standards, leaving me bewildered at my scores; and some blows on my face that got me right on track.</description></item><item><title>I have found Happiness</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2008/12/09/i-have-found-happiness/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2008 16:27:07 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2008/12/09/i-have-found-happiness/</guid><description>It was this time that I spent a whole 8 days continuously at Kalu Sarai, not coming back to my home for the weekend. Now, I am back and I remember how these days went by&amp;hellip;
Thursday, November 27 - Friday, December 5 The Situation: We have our first All India Test Series exam on Sunday, the 30th.
The Scene: I have decided not to take a look at Calculus; for I had just given a Phase Test on the topic last Sunday.</description></item><item><title>It's decided: IIT first, Web Development later</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2008/11/22/its-decided-iit-first-web-development-later/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2008 05:15:06 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2008/11/22/its-decided-iit-first-web-development-later/</guid><description>Why? It&amp;rsquo;s the time I have decided to stop thinking about the development of TechGlider.com as for the last 2 months I haven&amp;rsquo;t been able to do any remarkable work mostly because of being unable to organize my ideas and put them into practice in short periods of 1-2 days I get home for in a week.
The burden of study is more and I need to focus on that, forgetting everything else in the world now (after all JEE-2009 is less than 5 months ahead).</description></item><item><title>When I wrote my first bash script...</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2008/11/11/when-i-wrote-my-first-bash-script/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2008 04:32:36 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2008/11/11/when-i-wrote-my-first-bash-script/</guid><description>Yesterday, I was searching for LOGO (the programming language with a turtle) that works on Ubuntu for I have installed Ubuntu on my little brother&amp;rsquo;s PC and I wanted to show him that he can use Ubuntu for his regular computer study too; he&amp;rsquo;s in 3rd grade and learning LOGO at school.
So, I found one kturtle using Synaptic Package Manager and tried to test it on my own PC. My bad luck, it was like logo but had a different syntax.</description></item><item><title>On Deepawali and the change of theme</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2008/10/28/on-deepawali-and-theme-change/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2008 17:09:34 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2008/10/28/on-deepawali-and-theme-change/</guid><description>This is today that somebody pointed out: &amp;ldquo;Your blog is not looking that fine&amp;rdquo;. And I realize why I lost interest in writing on this blog.
Following the suggestion I have changed the blog&amp;rsquo;s theme again. Tell me, if this one feels fine enough.
Today is Deepawali, the so-called biggest festival of India. Everybody out there is celebrating, burning crackers, or making merry; and here I am writing on my blog after a long break (my biggest break ever), amid the sounds of ladis, bombs, rockets, whistlers.</description></item><item><title>Watch Zeitgeist to know the biggest secrets of mankind</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2008/09/22/watch-zeitgeist-to-know-the-biggest-secrets-of-mankind/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2008 08:10:38 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2008/09/22/watch-zeitgeist-to-know-the-biggest-secrets-of-mankind/</guid><description>From Wikipedia:
Zeitgeist, the Movie is a 2007 documentary film, produced by Peter Joseph about the Jesus myth hypothesis, the attacks of 9/11, and the Federal Reserve Bank as well as a number of conspiracy theories related to those three main topics. It was released free online via Google Video in June 2007. A remastered version was presented as a global premiere on November 10, 2007 at the 4th Annual Artivist Film Festival &amp;amp; Artivist Awards.</description></item><item><title>Back with a blast (actually 5) ...</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2008/09/14/back-with-a-blast-actually-5/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2008 11:52:29 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2008/09/14/back-with-a-blast-actually-5/</guid><description>Finally, I came back for the weekend, yesterday.
Slept late at night (around 1:30 AM), the night before yesterday, so was late for the morning journey.
Something unusual happened during my journey in the DTC bus, that I may not be able forget easily. While traveling with my friend Manoj in the bus, I pointed out to him the message written on the back of every seat:
Apni seat ke neeche dekhiye.</description></item><item><title>Going away from home....</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2008/09/08/going-away-from-home/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2008 17:24:44 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2008/09/08/going-away-from-home/</guid><description>Though not that far away, but it&amp;rsquo;s finally here. I will be living in some other place for the first time ever in my life. I want to admit, if I had not dropped the year, this may have happened more than a month ago (moving into hostel of some great college, I would have taken admission into).
So, what has happened is that due to LARGE commuting time for attending classes at FIITJEE (5 hours commute time for a 4 hour session), I have been forced to take up a room at Delhi and reside there.</description></item><item><title>FOSS and LAMP Workshop at ABES by ILUG-D</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2008/08/27/foss-and-lamp-workshop-at-abes-by-ilug-d/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2008 16:15:45 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2008/08/27/foss-and-lamp-workshop-at-abes-by-ilug-d/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been more than 10 days since I last posted &amp;lsquo;cause I was (and am) following a very busy schedule.
A lot happened in these days. The most prominent event among many was the LAMP workshop by the India Linux Users&amp;rsquo; Group, Delhi held on August 23, 2008 at ABES Engineering College.
I was trying to get a fully working linux distro installed on my PC since I first assembled my PC back in December 2006.</description></item><item><title>Programming on your S60 phone!</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2008/08/20/programming-on-your-s60-phone/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2008 00:44:11 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2008/08/20/programming-on-your-s60-phone/</guid><description>How many of you know that you can actually use your S60 phone (that includes all N-Series Nokia phones and certain others) to do programming? :?:
I just tried to this yesterday on my N72 and want to tell you that it&amp;rsquo;s a great fun to do and a finer way to cut time we waste in commuting (than listening to music or playing games on our mobile).
Of course you need to know programming in order to utilize your phone in this manner.</description></item><item><title>My PC's configuration</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2008/08/16/my-pcs-configuration/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2008 11:09:09 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2008/08/16/my-pcs-configuration/</guid><description>My Platinium V2 (that&amp;rsquo;s the name of my PC) features:
Intel Core 2 Duo E6400 2.13 GHz processor
MSI P965 Neo MS-7235 mainboard
1.5 GB DDR2 SDRAM 667 MHz (512 MB Transcend, 1 GB Kingston)
Seagate Barracuda 7200.10 ST3320620AS 320 GB SATA hard disk
Palit ATi Radeon X800 GTO Graphics Card (256 MB) -&amp;gt; Sapphire ATi Radeon HD4670 Graphics Card (512 MB GDDR3, HDMI On-board)</description></item><item><title>That hard and tiring day of July 31</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2008/08/05/that-hard-and-tiring-day-of-july-31/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2008 14:22:47 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2008/08/05/that-hard-and-tiring-day-of-july-31/</guid><description>I mentioned about this day in my post of August 1.
I started the day at night by wishing a friend birthday, eventually making her wakeup at midnight. Then, came the inauguration of my website with my first post on The TechGlider Blog at 6 in the morning. This was the easy part of the day.
I reached the Ghaziabad Railway Station at 7:50 to board the train to Tilak Bridge at Delhi, for I use to go to South Delhi to attend FIITJEE classes for IIT-JEE preparation.</description></item></channel></rss>