<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Fun on The TechGlider</title><link>techglider.in/categories/fun/</link><description>Recent content in Fun on The TechGlider</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2011 05:41:22 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="techglider.in/categories/fun/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Story of the TechGlider</title><link>techglider.in/post/2011/03/26/the-story-of-the-techglider/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2011 05:41:22 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2011/03/26/the-story-of-the-techglider/</guid><description>Hi all, In this post I will be sharing some interesting points that fell along during realization of my idea of the TechGlider.First of all I am sharing some initial hand-drawn logos for the site. These were shared with my friend Arvis on June 28, 2009 for his comments.
The following was the outcome of earlier designs on July 5, 2009:
The following is a screenshot of StudenTech.</description></item><item><title>The Story of the LAN at A</title><link>techglider.in/post/2010/07/02/the-story-of-the-lan-at-a/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2010 04:46:38 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2010/07/02/the-story-of-the-lan-at-a/</guid><description>The following post was supposed to be published on Feb 28, 2010. But due to my procrastination and the importance of this I am finally publishing it now after so much time has passed.
So, finally, the much awaited (and the answer to the most asked question to me: Abe, kab aa raha hai&amp;hellip;?) - LAN is here at A Hostel, my hostel at NIT Calicut.
It all started with a challenge I accepted from Aakash to bring the LAN to A Hostel within month of starting of second sem.</description></item><item><title>My Airtel Woes</title><link>techglider.in/post/2010/04/03/my-airtel-woes/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2010 18:29:11 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2010/04/03/my-airtel-woes/</guid><description>I had bought a new Airtel SIM on Feb 8, just after FOSSMeet was over. Why? Because my previous SIM was incompatible with my N72 (Platinium Junior, let&amp;rsquo;s call it PJ for convenience). How? It said &amp;lsquo;Invalid SIM&amp;rsquo; on switching it on with the SIM (although somehow I had managed one whole semester with the same SIM in the PJ as the damned thing worked on restarting the phone 2-3 times, but in December I realized, the SIM can&amp;rsquo;t go far with PJ anymore).</description></item><item><title>Adventure on our first visit to an airport</title><link>techglider.in/post/2010/03/09/adventure-on-our-first-visit-to-an-airport/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2010 13:09:34 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2010/03/09/adventure-on-our-first-visit-to-an-airport/</guid><description>On Friday, I along with my friend Amit (aka Pandey) went to the Kozhikode airport to receive the guest Mr. Aditya Sengupta of FOSSEE, IIT Bombay. This was our first chance to visit an airport. We went in a taxi provided by IEEE Students Branch of our college. The peculiar thing about the taxi was its name: Taxi Kinglikutty (pardon me if I am messing up the name).
We reached 15 minutes earlier than the scheduled time of arrival and found that the flight was delayed by 20 minutes.</description></item><item><title>Status Update: Feb 26, 2010</title><link>techglider.in/post/2010/02/26/status-update-feb-26-2010/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2010 08:15:14 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2010/02/26/status-update-feb-26-2010/</guid><description>BUSY: Setting up LAN at A Hostel (yay!)
BUSY: Exams start on Wednesday March 3; worrying when to start study ;)
BUSY: Trying to design a database to be used in CSED&amp;rsquo;s website
BUSY: Thinking when to read the book The Hitchhiker&amp;rsquo;s Guide to the Galaxy by Douglas Adams which has been chosen by me for a review
BUSY: Thinking what date to reserve train tickets to home after end sems</description></item><item><title>Easter egg on Google: New Year 2010 Countdown</title><link>techglider.in/post/2009/12/31/easter-egg-on-google-new-year-2010-countdown/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2009 10:30:30 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2009/12/31/easter-egg-on-google-new-year-2010-countdown/</guid><description>My friend Amit had just created an account on GMail and logged out after that. Just then, he opened Google and was going to search something when I mentioned I&amp;rsquo;m Feeling Lucky to him. He asked what is that to which I thought of replying by showing him the official explanation by Google, so I clicked on &amp;rsquo;the&amp;rsquo; button without any search string. And voila! It showed this:
After scratching my head for few seconds, it occurred to me that it could be the countdown to welcome the new year 2010.</description></item><item><title>This is How a Budding Engineer Searches for his Glasses</title><link>techglider.in/post/2009/11/15/this-is-how-a-budding-engineer-searches-for-his-glasses/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2009 08:34:33 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2009/11/15/this-is-how-a-budding-engineer-searches-for-his-glasses/</guid><description>Just spotted this on the unofficial Notice Board of Hostel A (my hostel at NIT Calicut). Please click on the pics to enlarge:
Disclaimer: The names and other sensitive info has been smudged to preserve the person&amp;rsquo;s privacy.
This left me wondering of the creative minds of my hostel mates. And yeah, if you find his specs, please return them. You can post a comment here and ask me to help you return the glasses ;).</description></item><item><title>A Simple Tic Tac Toe Game in C</title><link>techglider.in/post/2009/11/12/a-simple-tic-tac-toe-game-in-c/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2009 13:24:53 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2009/11/12/a-simple-tic-tac-toe-game-in-c/</guid><description>Tic Tac Toe (T3), a two-player game developed in C/C++ in 2006-2007
For the school project in C++ in standard 11, I chose to make a game. Although the game doesn&amp;rsquo;t feature AI, it demonstrates the graphics and sound capabilities of C/C++ with Turbo C++ compiler.
Here is the link to the code (I can&amp;rsquo;t support it any more, so please don&amp;rsquo;t ask if you are unable to run it.):</description></item><item><title>Chhole Bekaar Waale...??</title><link>techglider.in/post/2009/07/16/chhole-bekaar-waale/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2009 23:14:21 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2009/07/16/chhole-bekaar-waale/</guid><description>Just spotted on this in Navyug Market (Ghaziabad) yesterday:
I visited Navyug Market yesterday with Mukul for some quick and cheap photostats (@ Rs. 0.75 per page). After coming out of the shop, Mukul pointed towards this vendor which caught my eye.
I was bit in a hurry but couldn&amp;rsquo;t stop the temptation of taking a snap. I asked the vendor whether I could take a photo. The Chhole Wala (in the center) agreed with a smile and said &amp;ldquo;Arrey kyun nahin?</description></item><item><title>No! Not again!</title><link>techglider.in/post/2009/05/22/no-not-again/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2009 05:16:56 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2009/05/22/no-not-again/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s just been a week, since I set up my PlatiniumV2 in the working order by installing Windows 7 Release Candidate and Ubuntu 9.04 after getting my graphics card (A Palit ATi Radeon X800 GTO, 256 MB DDR) repaired. And, it seems like I am going to be in trouble again.
What actually happened before:
When I previously installed Windows 7 Beta, around at the starting of March, I noticed that in a few days a weird kind of horizontal lines started appearing on my screen.</description></item><item><title>I have found Happiness</title><link>techglider.in/post/2008/12/09/i-have-found-happiness/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2008 16:27:07 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2008/12/09/i-have-found-happiness/</guid><description>It was this time that I spent a whole 8 days continuously at Kalu Sarai, not coming back to my home for the weekend. Now, I am back and I remember how these days went by&amp;hellip;
Thursday, November 27 - Friday, December 5 The Situation: We have our first All India Test Series exam on Sunday, the 30th.
The Scene: I have decided not to take a look at Calculus; for I had just given a Phase Test on the topic last Sunday.</description></item><item><title>On Deepawali and the change of theme</title><link>techglider.in/post/2008/10/28/on-deepawali-and-theme-change/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2008 17:09:34 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2008/10/28/on-deepawali-and-theme-change/</guid><description>This is today that somebody pointed out: &amp;ldquo;Your blog is not looking that fine&amp;rdquo;. And I realize why I lost interest in writing on this blog.
Following the suggestion I have changed the blog&amp;rsquo;s theme again. Tell me, if this one feels fine enough.
Today is Deepawali, the so-called biggest festival of India. Everybody out there is celebrating, burning crackers, or making merry; and here I am writing on my blog after a long break (my biggest break ever), amid the sounds of ladis, bombs, rockets, whistlers.</description></item><item><title>Welcome to the All New TechGlider Blog</title><link>techglider.in/post/2008/10/06/welcome-to-the-all-new-techglider-blog/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2008 23:46:23 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2008/10/06/welcome-to-the-all-new-techglider-blog/</guid><description>This is my first post on WordPress and through this I welcome you to the all new TechGlider Blog.
I am finally finished with moving the TGB to WordPress. WordPress offers a plethora of plugins to customize one&amp;rsquo;s blog and I am trying to choose what are those that I need for the TGB. As pointed out in my last post, this change hasn&amp;rsquo;t been easy. I almost lost all of my previous posts for there was no efficient way to import the posts from my b2evolution installation to WordPress, so I had to do it manually and took a whole day for that (these type of repetitive works are really a pain in the neck for me).</description></item><item><title>Fedora 9 Installation Screenshots uploaded</title><link>techglider.in/post/2008/09/05/fedora-9-installation-screenshots-uploaded/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2008 12:59:14 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2008/09/05/fedora-9-installation-screenshots-uploaded/</guid><description>:phew: Finally, the screenshots for Fedora 9 installation have been uploaded (with great difficulty and mess up of my system and internet connection in the last few days).
To view a slide show follow the link: http://www.flickr.com/photos/techglider/sets/72157607119105020/show/
Hope to write a &amp;ldquo;full guide to installing Fedora 9 on your PC&amp;rdquo; by Sunday.</description></item><item><title>It's a Monthiversary!!</title><link>techglider.in/post/2008/08/31/its-a-monthiversary/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Aug 2008 00:03:57 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2008/08/31/its-a-monthiversary/</guid><description>Today, it&amp;rsquo;s been a month I started out posting on this blog.
And I feel happy about it. 11 posts in a month; it may seem too less to some of you, but, for me: I suppose I have been keeping up to my goal of writing regularly (and improving by the day :-) ).
I know I haven&amp;rsquo;t been able to fulfill certain promises I made on the blog viz: guide to installing Ubuntu and unveiling the main TechGlider site.</description></item><item><title>FOSS and LAMP Workshop at ABES by ILUG-D</title><link>techglider.in/post/2008/08/27/foss-and-lamp-workshop-at-abes-by-ilug-d/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2008 16:15:45 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2008/08/27/foss-and-lamp-workshop-at-abes-by-ilug-d/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been more than 10 days since I last posted &amp;lsquo;cause I was (and am) following a very busy schedule.
A lot happened in these days. The most prominent event among many was the LAMP workshop by the India Linux Users&amp;rsquo; Group, Delhi held on August 23, 2008 at ABES Engineering College.
I was trying to get a fully working linux distro installed on my PC since I first assembled my PC back in December 2006.</description></item><item><title>Programming on your S60 phone!</title><link>techglider.in/post/2008/08/20/programming-on-your-s60-phone/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2008 00:44:11 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2008/08/20/programming-on-your-s60-phone/</guid><description>How many of you know that you can actually use your S60 phone (that includes all N-Series Nokia phones and certain others) to do programming? :?:
I just tried to this yesterday on my N72 and want to tell you that it&amp;rsquo;s a great fun to do and a finer way to cut time we waste in commuting (than listening to music or playing games on our mobile).
Of course you need to know programming in order to utilize your phone in this manner.</description></item><item><title>The TechGlider Forums are now active.</title><link>techglider.in/post/2008/08/14/the-techglider-forums-are-now-active/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2008 00:31:56 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2008/08/14/the-techglider-forums-are-now-active/</guid><description>I am glad to inform you that finally the The TechGlider Forums have been activated on techglider.in. :-)
To visit the forums you can go to http://forums.techglider.in. Please read the first topic &amp;ldquo;General Rules&amp;rdquo; before posting anything on the forums.
You can register yourself on the forums by clicking on the &amp;ldquo;Register&amp;rdquo; link at the top-right of the page. After you become a member, you can ask questions, get answers, start new topics for discussions under the given categories and post about anything you like.</description></item><item><title>Download whole websites for offline browsing</title><link>techglider.in/post/2008/08/10/download-whole-websites-for-offline-browsing/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2008 03:22:49 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2008/08/10/download-whole-websites-for-offline-browsing/</guid><description>How many times has it happened that you witnessed some great and very useful pages (e.g. tutorials) on some website and had an instant urge if they could be downloaded on your computer so that you don&amp;rsquo;t have to be connected to the net to read them?
Here&amp;rsquo;s a solution for this frequent desire. There&amp;rsquo;s a good tool that can just make this happen :): HTTrack Website Copier
Available for almost all of major Desktop platforms including windows, linux and mac, it&amp;rsquo;s an easy to use tool to make websites run offline on your PC.</description></item><item><title>That hard and tiring day of July 31</title><link>techglider.in/post/2008/08/05/that-hard-and-tiring-day-of-july-31/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2008 14:22:47 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2008/08/05/that-hard-and-tiring-day-of-july-31/</guid><description>I mentioned about this day in my post of August 1.
I started the day at night by wishing a friend birthday, eventually making her wakeup at midnight. Then, came the inauguration of my website with my first post on The TechGlider Blog at 6 in the morning. This was the easy part of the day.
I reached the Ghaziabad Railway Station at 7:50 to board the train to Tilak Bridge at Delhi, for I use to go to South Delhi to attend FIITJEE classes for IIT-JEE preparation.</description></item></channel></rss>