<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Disk partitioning on The TechGlider</title><link>https://techglider.in/tags/disk-partitioning/</link><description>Recent content in Disk partitioning on The TechGlider</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2013 12:16:13 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://techglider.in/tags/disk-partitioning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>It feels so relieving to get your lost...</title><link>https://techglider.in/status/2013/04/20/it-feels-so-relieving-to-get-your-lost/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2013 12:16:13 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/status/2013/04/20/it-feels-so-relieving-to-get-your-lost/</guid><description>It feels so relieving to get your lost data back!
After trying multiple file recovery tools like TestDisk/PhotoRec, Recuva, etc. I had ran chkdsk (of course, from Windows) as a last resort on that particular partition last night. Since, Windows doesn&amp;rsquo;t show protected system files easily I couldn&amp;rsquo;t see the content of found.000 directory that got created in the said partition. I made a mental note of checking this directory out later from Linux.</description></item><item><title>Another strange thing and a big lesson learned...</title><link>https://techglider.in/status/2013/04/19/another-strange-thing-and-a-big-lesson-learned/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2013 14:55:02 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/status/2013/04/19/another-strange-thing-and-a-big-lesson-learned/</guid><description>Another strange thing and a big lesson learned today was regarding disk handling by Windows and Linux. I had been observing missing files from my hard disk for a few weeks now, always suspected it was due to bad sectors but tests didn&amp;rsquo;t turn up anything positive. When I took the backup of my old Ubuntu home directory to an NTFS partition, installed Linux Mint and then tried to access the backup I was left with a shock - the whole backup was gone!</description></item><item><title>Restore GRUB in Ubuntu after installing Windows</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2011/06/25/restore-grub-in-ubuntu-after-installing-windows/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2011 18:30:44 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2011/06/25/restore-grub-in-ubuntu-after-installing-windows/</guid><description>So, you had Ubuntu (or any of its derivative) installed on your system and then decided to install Windows with it? And after installing Windows, you can&amp;rsquo;t load Ubuntu again, just follow the steps to get this working:
Boot the system using a Ubuntu Live disk.
After you reach the desktop, open Terminal (press Alt+F2, type &amp;ldquo;gnome-terminal&amp;rdquo; without quotes and press enter).
Execute:
``` sudo fdisk -l ``` Execute (after replacing sda7 with your corresponding linux root partition, which you will be able to identify from the output of the previous command - it&amp;rsquo;s usually marked as Linux): ``` sudo mount /dev/sda7 /mnt ``` Just check whether you got the root partition right, if you have more than 1 linux partition on your hard disk: ``` cd /mnt ls ``` If the listing contains names like bin, boot, dev, etc, home, tmp, usr, var, et cetera then you are in the right partition.</description></item><item><title>Recommended Linux Partitioning Scheme</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2011/06/23/recommended-linux-partitioning-scheme/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2011 18:30:18 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2011/06/23/recommended-linux-partitioning-scheme/</guid><description>Partitioning Basics: When we need to install linux on our systems, we need to partition our hard disk as we do for windows. In the case of windows, partitions are called as c: ,d:, e:, etc. But on linux they are represented in the form of following (there are many others, but these are the most essential):
swap: This is meant for use by the system when it runs out of memory (RAM); it&amp;rsquo;s much like virtual memory in windows where the system utilizes that space as extra memory.</description></item></channel></rss>