<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ubuntu on The TechGlider</title><link>techglider.in/tags/ubuntu/</link><description>Recent content in ubuntu on The TechGlider</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2013 14:39:46 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="techglider.in/tags/ubuntu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Found the culprit for a long standing problem...</title><link>techglider.in/status/2013/04/19/found-the-culprit-for-a-long-standing-problem/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2013 14:39:46 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/status/2013/04/19/found-the-culprit-for-a-long-standing-problem/</guid><description>Found the culprit for a long standing problem with Linux install disk booting on my Dell Studio XPS 1645 today at http://forums.linuxmint.com/viewtopic.php?f=46&amp;amp;t=126993#p692786 - it was my wireless card. Was facing this problem at least since last October when I tried to install latest editions of Fedora and ArchLinux but couldn&amp;rsquo;t. On Linux Mint 14 Cinnamon now.</description></item><item><title>LaTeX Project Report Template Updated</title><link>techglider.in/post/2013/02/15/latex-project-report-template-updated/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2013 14:36:40 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2013/02/15/latex-project-report-template-updated/</guid><description>The LaTeX logo (Photo credit: Wikipedia)
This will be quite short.
Many have told me they found the LaTeX Project Report Template that I published about two years back pretty useful. Today, I am releasing an update for the same. This includes a fix for a nasty bug in the original template apart from some layout changes.
Fork it from Github at https://github.com/k4rtik/latex-project-report-template to start creating your project reports.Visit http://k4rtik.</description></item><item><title>Quickly Check Temperature Values of Hardware Components in Ubuntu</title><link>techglider.in/post/2013/02/06/quickly-check-temperature-values-of-hardware-components-in-ubuntu/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2013 15:55:08 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2013/02/06/quickly-check-temperature-values-of-hardware-components-in-ubuntu/</guid><description>So, I missed posting yesterday. Hope this doesn&amp;rsquo;t repeat.
Today I am sharing a small bash script I wrote to check the temperatures recorded by various sensors in my laptop. Nothing incredibly smart here, just a quick but useful hack.
I am one of those unhappy Linux users who suffer from lack of driver support for their hardware. Due to some weird kernel bug or messy graphics driver, which led to incredibly high temperatures on my laptop, I spent about a year using Linux as a VirtualBox guest in Windows; this was before Ubuntu 12.</description></item><item><title>Best Tool for Downloading YouTube Videos and Playlists</title><link>techglider.in/post/2012/07/13/best-tool-for-downloading-youtube-videos-and-playlists/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2012 18:30:17 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2012/07/13/best-tool-for-downloading-youtube-videos-and-playlists/</guid><description>How many times does it happen that you stumble upon an awesome youtube video, you make up your mind to download it but fail short to find a good tool which actually works?
In this post I want to introduce one of the best tools for downloading videos from YouTube and other video platforms - youtube-dl. This command line tool is basically just a python script released by its developers in public domain and it works on any platform that supports Python 2.</description></item><item><title>Control All Computers in a Lab from a Single System</title><link>techglider.in/post/2012/02/12/control-all-computers-in-a-lab-from-a-single-system/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2012 03:10:21 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2012/02/12/control-all-computers-in-a-lab-from-a-single-system/</guid><description>Quoting Dhandeep, our super-cool lab-admin:
now , all 70 systems in the lab can be switched on and switched off by single commands from the hostel&amp;hellip;
Yes, that and a lot more is possible in our Software Systems Lab now. How? Read on&amp;hellip;
The Setup We have over 70 systems with Ubuntu 10.04 LTS installed on them. There is an administrative account (let&amp;rsquo;s call it admin for this post) and a guest (limited privilege) account on each.</description></item><item><title>Configuring Apache for Developing Multiple Websites under Ubuntu Linux</title><link>techglider.in/post/2011/08/18/configuring-apache-for-developing-multiple-websites-under-ubuntu-linux/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2011 18:30:13 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2011/08/18/configuring-apache-for-developing-multiple-websites-under-ubuntu-linux/</guid><description>Are you a beginner in web development with LAMP environment, or a CS/IT student overwhelmed with setting up LAMP and configuring it for your web-related academic project? If yes, then you are at the right place.
We have discussed earlier how easy it is to setup a web development environment on your Ubuntu desktop. In this article we will try to have a more customized setup of this environment for easily working with multiple websites.</description></item><item><title>Easiest Way to Setup a Web Development Environment on Ubuntu-based Distros</title><link>techglider.in/post/2011/07/08/easiest-way-to-setup-a-web-development-environment-on-ubuntu-based-distros/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2011 18:30:21 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2011/07/08/easiest-way-to-setup-a-web-development-environment-on-ubuntu-based-distros/</guid><description>Did you know how easy it is to get a basic web development environment on your Ubuntu-based Linux distribution? Guess what, it just takes 2 commands on the Terminal:
sudo apt-get install tasksel This will install a small utility which lets you install a lot packages grouped together as software collections.
sudo tasksel Launch tasksel and select &amp;lsquo;LAMP server&amp;rsquo; by pressing the SPACE key, press ENTER when you are done (see attached screenshot).</description></item><item><title>Use rfkill to Enable/Disable Wireless on your Linux Laptop</title><link>techglider.in/post/2011/06/29/use-rfkill-to-enabledisable-wireless-on-your-linux-laptop/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2011 18:30:56 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2011/06/29/use-rfkill-to-enabledisable-wireless-on-your-linux-laptop/</guid><description>Imagine a situation when you have to book an air/train ticket in a jiffy, or check an important mail quickly and the only option you have is a wi-fi connection from either your smart phone or surroundings, and you have only some Linux variant installed on your system. And even after installing all the necessary drivers, you are unable to get the wi-fi on your laptop working? Frustrating right? If yes, then you might want to read on about this useful utility called rfkill which you can keep in handy for those weary situations.</description></item><item><title>Restore GRUB in Ubuntu after installing Windows</title><link>techglider.in/post/2011/06/25/restore-grub-in-ubuntu-after-installing-windows/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2011 18:30:44 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2011/06/25/restore-grub-in-ubuntu-after-installing-windows/</guid><description>So, you had Ubuntu (or any of its derivative) installed on your system and then decided to install Windows with it? And after installing Windows, you can&amp;rsquo;t load Ubuntu again, just follow the steps to get this working:
Boot the system using a Ubuntu Live disk.
After you reach the desktop, open Terminal (press Alt+F2, type &amp;ldquo;gnome-terminal&amp;rdquo; without quotes and press enter).
Execute:
``` sudo fdisk -l ``` Execute (after replacing sda7 with your corresponding linux root partition, which you will be able to identify from the output of the previous command - it&amp;rsquo;s usually marked as Linux): ``` sudo mount /dev/sda7 /mnt ``` Just check whether you got the root partition right, if you have more than 1 linux partition on your hard disk: ``` cd /mnt ls ``` If the listing contains names like bin, boot, dev, etc, home, tmp, usr, var, et cetera then you are in the right partition.</description></item><item><title>Recommended Linux Partitioning Scheme</title><link>techglider.in/post/2011/06/23/recommended-linux-partitioning-scheme/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2011 18:30:18 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2011/06/23/recommended-linux-partitioning-scheme/</guid><description>Partitioning Basics: When we need to install linux on our systems, we need to partition our hard disk as we do for windows. In the case of windows, partitions are called as c: ,d:, e:, etc. But on linux they are represented in the form of following (there are many others, but these are the most essential):
swap: This is meant for use by the system when it runs out of memory (RAM); it&amp;rsquo;s much like virtual memory in windows where the system utilizes that space as extra memory.</description></item><item><title>Root Samsung Galaxy S i9000 running GINGERBREAD.DDJV6 using Ubuntu Linux</title><link>techglider.in/post/2011/06/21/root-samsung-galaxy-s-i9000-running-gingerbread-ddjv6-using-ubuntu-linux/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2011 17:01:54 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2011/06/21/root-samsung-galaxy-s-i9000-running-gingerbread-ddjv6-using-ubuntu-linux/</guid><description>I bought a Samsung Galaxy S i9000 just last month. The most prominent reason to buy an Android phone was that it&amp;rsquo;s based on Linux and I love the UNIX-based OS. Besides, Android as a platform provides so many opportunities into application development (and even kernel hacking) that I was simply tempted to buy one since last year.
I have explored the phone since I got my hands on it - trying various apps, playing with 3G internet speeds (3.</description></item><item><title>Accessing NIT Calicut's Ubuntu Mirror (in the campus)</title><link>techglider.in/post/2011/02/01/accessing-nit-calicuts-ubuntu-mirror-in-the-campus/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 01:20:47 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2011/02/01/accessing-nit-calicuts-ubuntu-mirror-in-the-campus/</guid><description>As the FOSSCell webserver has been facing troubles these days, the instructions to use the Ubuntu Mirror of NIT Calicut that were available on the FOSSCell wiki are being missed by many. Here they are though not in the informative way as were given on the wiki:
Add the following to your /etc/apt/sources.list and comment out other similar repos.
deb http://192.168.40.97/ubuntu lucid-updates main multiverse restricted universe deb http://192.168.40.97/ubuntu lucid-security main multiverse restricted universe deb http://192.</description></item><item><title>Recover files deleted from GNU/Linux</title><link>techglider.in/post/2010/11/06/recover-files-deleted-from-gnulinux/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Nov 2010 15:43:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2010/11/06/recover-files-deleted-from-gnulinux/</guid><description>It was an embarassing today that after making a presentation on Drupal and promising the audience to distribute the presentation file after the session, I deleted it accidentally.
And all my fears regarding Linux being so different when it came to file recovery (unlike Windows, where you had a choice of many recovery software) and it was next to impossible to undelete files from linux, seemed to come true. A quick search in Ubuntu Software Center listed a software called &amp;lsquo;recover&amp;rsquo; which was meant only for ext2 partitions, and mine being ext4 I was hopeless.</description></item><item><title>First Hands-on with Assembly Language Programming</title><link>techglider.in/post/2010/10/25/first-hands-on-with-assembly-language-programming/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2010 09:46:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2010/10/25/first-hands-on-with-assembly-language-programming/</guid><description>I always wanted to learn assembly language programming. I had never tried do it myself and was disappointed to know that it was not there in our Logic Design course this semester (this because it was mentioned in the syllabus and I had taken pains to find good books on assembly from the library and get them issued, just to return them after learning that the syllabus for the course was too less compared to what was given on the department&amp;rsquo;s website).</description></item><item><title>Ubuntu Tips and Tricks - Part 1</title><link>techglider.in/post/2010/09/25/ubuntu-tips-and-tricks-part-1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Sep 2010 09:53:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2010/09/25/ubuntu-tips-and-tricks-part-1/</guid><description>Just learned some new commands on Ubuntu:
If sometime you get into a (big!) trouble such as the Gnome panels not loading but the desktop is visible, you can open the gnome-terminal using the key combination Ctrl + Alt + T (of course this is a good shortcut for normal desktop usage too).
Because of the above problem, you may want to create a bootable drive to reinstall Ubuntu, but how do you do that as you cannot load the Ubuntu Startup Disk Creator?</description></item><item><title>Simple script to install essential packages in Ubuntu 10.04 Lucid 64-bit</title><link>techglider.in/post/2010/05/05/simple-script-to-install-essential-packages-in-ubuntu-10-04-lucid-64-bit/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2010 07:16:11 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2010/05/05/simple-script-to-install-essential-packages-in-ubuntu-10-04-lucid-64-bit/</guid><description>Please note that this script has been tested only with a lucid 64-bit installation. It requires an active internet connection to download packages (a broadband connection, otherwise it will seem to take forever to finish):
#!/bin/bash # Adding Medibuntu Repositories sudo wget http://www.medibuntu.org/sources.list.d/$(lsb_release -cs).list --output-document=/etc/apt/sources.list.d/medibuntu.list sudo aptitude update &amp;amp;&amp;amp; sudo aptitude install medibuntu-keyring &amp;amp;&amp;amp; sudo aptitude update sudo update-apt-xapian-index # Install multimedia codecs sudo apt-get remove gnash gnash-common libflashsupport mozilla-plugin-gnash swfdec-mozilla sudo apt-get install gstreamer0.</description></item><item><title>Recommended software for a new Ubuntu install</title><link>techglider.in/post/2010/04/30/recommended-software-for-a-new-ubuntu-install/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2010 15:35:38 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2010/04/30/recommended-software-for-a-new-ubuntu-install/</guid><description>Here&amp;rsquo;s my list of recommended software to install after doing a fresh Ubuntu installation:
netspeed ntfs-config gparted gnome-do wine vlc gimp filezilla stardict bluefish ccsm opera google chrome chm viewer or chmsee inkscape sunjava acroread python3 screem virtualbox &amp;ndash;
Kartik - The TechGlider Guy
http://www.techglider.in</description></item><item><title>A Brief Overview of Ubuntu 9.10 Karmic Koala</title><link>techglider.in/post/2009/10/30/a-brief-overview-of-ubuntu-9-10-karmic-koala/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2009 17:06:05 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2009/10/30/a-brief-overview-of-ubuntu-9-10-karmic-koala/</guid><description>Just got my hands on to latest version of Ubuntu 9.10 Karmic Koala around 5 hours ago. So, this will be a very brief overview of Ubuntu&amp;rsquo;s latest version.
Me being Ubuntu crazy, just started exploring it after downloading it. I setup my 8 GB Corsair Flash Voyager as a bootable Ubuntu 9.10 drive using USB Startup Disk Creator available in Jaunty.
Booting into the live system was similar as before except for the color and design of the Ubuntu logo on bootup has changed.</description></item><item><title>Essential software for a working Ubuntu 9.04 Desktop</title><link>techglider.in/post/2009/09/19/essential-software-for-a-working-ubuntu-9-04-desktop/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2009 15:08:30 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2009/09/19/essential-software-for-a-working-ubuntu-9-04-desktop/</guid><description>These are the steps to follow if you want your latest Ubuntu install to have all the essential software and codecs installed so that you can use your Ubuntu linux system as a/an replacement/addition of windows operating system.
You should be connected to internet to follow these steps. You can use Ctrl+Shift+V to paste the copied code in Terminal, which can be accessed as Applications-&amp;gt;Accessories-&amp;gt;Terminal.
First of all, choose the best server in System-&amp;gt;Administration-&amp;gt;Software Sources.</description></item><item><title>Surprise and some news</title><link>techglider.in/post/2009/04/30/surprise-and-some-news/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2009 05:15:42 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2009/04/30/surprise-and-some-news/</guid><description>Hi, there!
I am back. I am feeling very glad to write after this long period of 3 months.
First of all I would like to tell you about a surprise I got today. I was just checking out the stats of techglider.in to see what are the pages that are popular and being most viewed. One nifty feature of the statistics program I use is that it shows the search phrases that lead to my website.</description></item><item><title>Back to linux and switching to WordPress...</title><link>techglider.in/post/2008/10/05/back-to-linux-and-switching-to-wordpress/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2008 12:36:38 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2008/10/05/back-to-linux-and-switching-to-wordpress/</guid><description>I am glad to tell you that I have got rid of windows XP (again!) after muddling my head for 2 days trying to make it stable on my system. Now, I feel better that I gave it up in just 4 days of use and got rid of shame (read about it here) I was feeling that I installed XP again. I now have 2 variants of linux viz. Ubuntu 8.</description></item><item><title>Testing websites with IE on linux</title><link>techglider.in/post/2008/09/21/testing-websites-with-ie-on-linux/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2008 16:14:22 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2008/09/21/testing-websites-with-ie-on-linux/</guid><description>Just found this great tool IEs4Linux for testing websites under Internet Explorer 6, 5.5 and 5 on linux. It currently doesn&amp;rsquo;t support IE7 but that feature is in development beta. Find more info here: http://www.tatanka.com.br/ies4linux/page/Main_Page
Update (Jun 23, 2011):
IEs4Linux now also supports IE7, IE8 and IE9 in beta.
&amp;ndash;
Kartik - The TechGlider Guy
http://www.techglider.in</description></item><item><title>What to do after a new Ubuntu 8.04 Hardy Heron installation?</title><link>techglider.in/post/2008/09/08/what-to-do-after-a-new-ubuntu-8-04-hardy-heron-installation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2008 10:52:09 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2008/09/08/what-to-do-after-a-new-ubuntu-8-04-hardy-heron-installation/</guid><description>After Install Tasks Have your internet connection ready. If you have ADSL (BSNL, Airtel broadband) connection, and you are used connecting using a username and password in windows, then, open up a Terminal (Applications-&amp;gt;Accessories) and give the following command: ``` sudo pppoeconf ``` You will prompted for your password. Then a wizard runs and detects your connection (usually eth0). Accept all the default settings and when prompted type your connection username and password.</description></item><item><title>A Guide to Installing Fedora 9: Part 2</title><link>techglider.in/post/2008/09/07/a-guide-to-installing-fedora-9-part-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2008 14:52:21 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2008/09/07/a-guide-to-installing-fedora-9-part-2/</guid><description>So, you have already booted up with the live DVD. Follow this part to actually install Fedora on your system&amp;hellip;
The Main Installation of Fedora: After reaching to the Fedora Desktop (if you don&amp;rsquo;t know how, follow the first part of this guide), use the &amp;ldquo;Install to Hard Drive&amp;rdquo; icon to start the Fedora installer. You will be greeted with the following window: Click &amp;lsquo;Next&amp;rsquo;. Select the layout of your keyboard from the list that appears (usually US English).</description></item><item><title>A Guide to Installing Fedora 9: Part 1</title><link>techglider.in/post/2008/09/06/a-guide-to-installing-fedora-9-part-1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2008 01:50:41 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2008/09/06/a-guide-to-installing-fedora-9-part-1/</guid><description>This is a beginner&amp;rsquo;s tutorial to installing Fedora 9 on your PC. In a recent survey I found that Fedora is more popular in India than Ubuntu (my personal favorite) so I decided to give a installation guide for Fedora instead of Ubuntu (read: https://techglider.in/blog/blog1.php/20 &amp;hellip; thiversary).
Prerequisites: You will need
Fedora 9 installation DVD (to know how to get one, visit: https://techglider.in/blog/blog1.php/20 &amp;hellip; ting-linux)
A PC system with atleast 9 GB of free space and minimum of 256 MB of RAM</description></item><item><title>Various Sources of Getting Linux</title><link>techglider.in/post/2008/08/09/various-sources-of-getting-linux/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2008 03:39:59 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2008/08/09/various-sources-of-getting-linux/</guid><description>Here&amp;rsquo;s a list of various ways following which you can get a linux distro:
The best way, if you have unlimited internet (broadband) access, is to download the ISO image (usually 700 MB in size) from the website of the particular linux distribution and burn it on to a CD or DVD (in case of a DVD image) to install linux. e.g. visit http://www.ubuntu.com/getubuntu/download to choose and download the particular version of Ubuntu for your requirement.</description></item><item><title>My entry into the open world of linux</title><link>techglider.in/post/2008/08/03/my-entry-into-the-open-world-of-linux/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2008 00:31:32 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2008/08/03/my-entry-into-the-open-world-of-linux/</guid><description>July 30, 2008, the day I decided to completely scrap off Windows XP and switched to linux as my only operating system. Now, after a successful transition from the proprietary to the open source, I am all happy and a lot more secure and satisfied :-), for the world of linux provides complete relief from the hassles of spyware, viruses and usual breakdowns of windows.
For those who don&amp;rsquo;t know about linux, it is an operating system platform which is free and open (in the sense that you can see its code, modify it, distribute it and do a lot more).</description></item></channel></rss>