<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>new theme on The TechGlider</title><link>techglider.in/tags/new-theme/</link><description>Recent content in new theme on The TechGlider</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2011 07:43:51 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="techglider.in/tags/new-theme/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>...and, we're back!</title><link>techglider.in/post/2011/03/13/and-we-are-back/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2011 07:43:51 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2011/03/13/and-we-are-back/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been so long - missing the TechGlider - my dream, my hard work of over 2 years was gone. Started in July 2008, gone in July 2010. :(
The reason of this long absence: I lost the ownership of the domain techglider.com - partly because of my own carelessness, and partly because of my webhost Four &amp;lsquo;S&amp;rsquo; Tech&amp;rsquo;s troubles. In the process, I did learn a few interesting things like the concept of drop catching, how the companies like GoDaddy make so much money; and more importantly how not to lose my domain again.</description></item><item><title>And hence, I used my right to vote</title><link>techglider.in/post/2009/05/11/and-hence-i-used-my-right-to-vote/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2009 04:15:51 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2009/05/11/and-hence-i-used-my-right-to-vote/</guid><description>So I did it, and for the first time. You won&amp;rsquo;t believe when I write that I was way too excited to do this for almost a month.
Ok let me make things clear: I voted for the first time.
I am 19 and as many other adolescents was excited to be able to vote after turning 18. But last year I didn&amp;rsquo;t get my EPIC (Elector&amp;rsquo;s Photo Identity Card) as you are supposed to be 18 on January 1st of the year to be eligible for voting.</description></item><item><title>On Deepawali and the change of theme</title><link>techglider.in/post/2008/10/28/on-deepawali-and-theme-change/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2008 17:09:34 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2008/10/28/on-deepawali-and-theme-change/</guid><description>This is today that somebody pointed out: &amp;ldquo;Your blog is not looking that fine&amp;rdquo;. And I realize why I lost interest in writing on this blog.
Following the suggestion I have changed the blog&amp;rsquo;s theme again. Tell me, if this one feels fine enough.
Today is Deepawali, the so-called biggest festival of India. Everybody out there is celebrating, burning crackers, or making merry; and here I am writing on my blog after a long break (my biggest break ever), amid the sounds of ladis, bombs, rockets, whistlers.</description></item></channel></rss>