<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Brown University on The TechGlider</title><link>techglider.in/tags/brown-university/</link><description>Recent content in Brown University on The TechGlider</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 10:51:01 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="techglider.in/tags/brown-university/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Things I wish I knew in College</title><link>techglider.in/post/2016/10/01/things-i-wish-i-knew-in-college/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 10:51:01 -0400</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2016/10/01/things-i-wish-i-knew-in-college/</guid><description>Meta About a month ago, I asked the following question to the NIT Calicut CSE student body:
If you could ask only one question to an NITC CSE alumnus with diverse experience in industry, higher studies, and research, what would you?
The most raised concerns were:
How to decide between higher studies and industry as your next career move? What are the limitations of an NITC CSE education and how to succeed in the field despite them?</description></item><item><title>Reflections on the Facebook Sannyasa</title><link>techglider.in/post/2016/04/24/reflections-on-the-facebook-sannyasa/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2016 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2016/04/24/reflections-on-the-facebook-sannyasa/</guid><description>As some of you reading this might be aware I have been away for a while.
I deactivated my Facebook account sometime in the first week of Feb; it has been over 75 days. I did try activating it once after 30 days were over and realized within a couple of hours, how ugly and consumeristic this part of the Internet is and since then had not tried logging in again until last night.</description></item><item><title>Reenix</title><link>techglider.in/status/2016/03/28/reenix/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2016 21:37:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/status/2016/03/28/reenix/</guid><description>http://cs.brown.edu/research/pubs/theses/ugrad/2015/light.alex.pdf
Abstract This paper describes the experience, problems and successes found in implementing a unix-like operating system kernel in rust. Using the basic design and much of the lowest-level support code from the Weenix operating system written for CS167/9 I was able to create a basic kernel supporting multiple kernel processes scheduled cooperatively, drivers for the basic devices and the beginnings of a virtual file system. I made note of where the rust programming language, and its safety and type systems, helped and hindered my work and made some, tentative, performance comparisons between the rust and C implementations of this kernel.</description></item><item><title>Yay! David just gave a small tour of the ...</title><link>techglider.in/status/2016/03/25/yay-david-just-gave-a-small-tour-of-the-.../</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2016 21:23:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/status/2016/03/25/yay-david-just-gave-a-small-tour-of-the-.../</guid><description>Yay! David just gave a small tour of the Robotics Lab, that’s a Baxter emoting.
Note: This is an archived post from my unmaintained Tumblr blog https://k4rtik.tumblr.com</description></item><item><title>Java</title><link>techglider.in/post/2016/01/02/java/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2016 22:51:18 -0500</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2016/01/02/java/</guid><description>I don&amp;rsquo;t really recall why I avoided Java all this while.
Few weeks after arriving here at Brown, I learnt Brown is, what they call, a Java school. That&amp;rsquo;s probably not completely true, but for a vast majority of students that take Andy&amp;rsquo;s intro class, CS15, it is. I have come to realize it is not such a bad thing (quite the opposite).
I remember my first few weeks at college when I was trying to teach myself Java in the CC (whoa, they have a website now!</description></item><item><title>Relearning Computer Science</title><link>techglider.in/post/2015/10/28/relearning-computer-science/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2015 11:35:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2015/10/28/relearning-computer-science/</guid><description>Awakening I was awaken from a long sleep of ignorance with some events that occurred in the last couple of weeks. A sudden surge of conscientiousness about taking my education in my hands was one of the immediate results.
The inflection point was getting to hear Bryan Cantrill in person and interviewing with him the next day. I didn’t do my best, but was humbled by Cantrill into realizing how much I had to learn.</description></item></channel></rss>