<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>travel on The TechGlider</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/tags/travel/</link><description>Recent content in travel on The TechGlider</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 May 2015 18:27:30 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/tags/travel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Review of Around India in 80 Trains</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2015/05/03/review-of-around-india-in-80-trains/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2015 18:27:30 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2015/05/03/review-of-around-india-in-80-trains/</guid><description>Around India in 80 Trains by Monisha Rajesh
My rating: 3 of 5 stars
Got my hands on this book about two years ago when Amazon.in was launched and they were giving away some free Kindle books. Started reading it only when the Goodreads Indian Readers group picked this book as their April 2015 read.
Review This was the first time I read a travelogue and cannot say if I like the genre.</description></item><item><title>Week 1 at Bangalore and Work</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2013/07/21/week-1-at-bangalore-and-work/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2013 14:53:31 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2013/07/21/week-1-at-bangalore-and-work/</guid><description>I landed at Bangalore airport last week flying on an indiGo for the first time; found the experience better than JetKonnect from my first flight.
Next day (Sunday) started early with a walk to Oracle Tech Park and back to get myself familiarized with the area before first day at work. A much-needed haircut followed.
Having caught cold with the change in weather, I had to miss the Goodreads meetup planned at Brigade Road during the day, which I was eagerly awaiting to attend with a friend.</description></item><item><title>A Fun Security Weekend with null and sCTF</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2012/06/22/a-fun-security-weekend-with-null-and-sctf/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2012 19:39:05 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2012/06/22/a-fun-security-weekend-with-null-and-sctf/</guid><description>I know it&amp;rsquo;s quite late to post about the last weekend when another weekend is around the corner, but couldn&amp;rsquo;t control myself as the last one was so eventful. :)
It was almost 2 weeks back that I got to know about sCTF 2012. I have always wanted to learn about computer security (and the darker side of hacking), but haven&amp;rsquo;t been able to give time it to it. What followed was a quick search for team members from among my batch via FB - Nithin immediately showed interest, we pulled Jerrin in too.</description></item><item><title>(Bangalore) Summer of '12... with BeagleBone</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2012/06/13/bangalore-summer-of-12-with-beaglebone/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2012 16:42:13 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2012/06/13/bangalore-summer-of-12-with-beaglebone/</guid><description>This post will be slightly long. Lots of exciting things happening over a Bangalore summer this year for me. :D
Somehow I always wanted to learn more about hardware and with a mentor like Khasim the road seems a lot more exciting. I first met him when he came to conduct a workshop on BeagleBoard during Tathva 2009 at my college - NIT Calicut. I was just a fresher then and have since regretted that I could not attend that workshop completely (due to my participation in various CS related competitions).</description></item><item><title>The Branch Tour 2011 and me (Part 2)</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2011/03/01/the-branch-tour-2011-and-me-part-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 02:30:42 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2011/03/01/the-branch-tour-2011-and-me-part-2/</guid><description>This is second and the last part of my earlier post - The Branch Tour 2011 and me. Please read my last post before reading this.
Disclaimer: The following post is dedicated to all my branch mates and is a little more on the personal side. Additionally, the post is too long and may not be of any relevance for those who seek to attain any bit of technical nirvana from this blog.</description></item><item><title>The Branch Tour 2011 and me (Part 1)</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2011/02/28/the-branch-tour-2011-and-me-part-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2011 02:30:13 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2011/02/28/the-branch-tour-2011-and-me-part-1/</guid><description>Disclaimer: The following post is dedicated to all my branch mates and is a little more on the personal side. Additionally, the post is too long and may not be of any relevance for those who seek to attain any bit of technical nirvana from this blog. So, you may happily TLDR this post.
Many have asked me why I decided to go for branch tour when almost none of the northies were ready to go.</description></item></channel></rss>