<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>graphic novels on The TechGlider</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/tags/graphic-novels/</link><description>Recent content in graphic novels on The TechGlider</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2014 19:20:13 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/tags/graphic-novels/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Habibi by Craig Thompson - A Review</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2014/11/09/habibi-by-craig-thompson-a-review/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2014 19:20:13 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2014/11/09/habibi-by-craig-thompson-a-review/</guid><description>Habibi by Craig Thompson
My rating: 5 of 5 stars
At 672 pages, this is probably the longest graphic novel I have read, but one can&amp;rsquo;t go just by the page count, I finished it within 24 hours of acquiring the book from a friend. Yes, it was that engaging.
The book portrays the complicated relationship of two child slaves who meet by chance, grow up together, get separated and meet again, all this while craving for each other&amp;rsquo;s company while facing the hardship of the world.</description></item><item><title>Review of Fun Home: A Family Tragicomic</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2014/01/11/review-of-fun-home-a-family-tragicomic/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2014 12:38:12 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2014/01/11/review-of-fun-home-a-family-tragicomic/</guid><description>Fun Home: A Family Tragicomic by Alison Bechdel
My rating: 5 of 5 stars
Didn&amp;rsquo;t realize the author is a woman before reading the first chapter and looking up her name on Google. Neither did I know she is the one behind Bechdel test (used for identifying gender bias in movies and other works of fiction).
Combining both the genres I like - (auto)biographies and graphic novels, it was a worthy read, similar to the only other autobiographical graphic novel I have read: Art Spiegelman&amp;rsquo;s Maus.</description></item><item><title>Logicomix: An Epic Search for Truth</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2013/02/03/logicomix-an-epic-search-for-truth/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2013 18:52:40 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2013/02/03/logicomix-an-epic-search-for-truth/</guid><description>This one needs to be quick, 14 minutes until midnight.
Logicomix (Photo credit: Wikipedia)
In this post I want to introduce a graphic novel which I read about a year back - Logicomix: An Epic Search for Truth.
How I ended up reading this is an interesting story in itself. Let me try to recite in minimum possible words. During that time (Sem 6) I had enrolled for a course called Computational Complexity by Murali sir.</description></item></channel></rss>