<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Work on The TechGlider</title><link>https://techglider.in/tags/work/</link><description>Recent content in Work on The TechGlider</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2016 06:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://techglider.in/tags/work/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Reflections on the Facebook Sannyasa</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2016/04/24/reflections-on-the-facebook-sannyasa/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2016 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2016/04/24/reflections-on-the-facebook-sannyasa/</guid><description>As some of you reading this might be aware I have been away for a while.
I deactivated my Facebook account sometime in the first week of Feb; it has been over 75 days. I did try activating it once after 30 days were over and realized within a couple of hours, how ugly and consumeristic this part of the Internet is and since then had not tried logging in again until last night.</description></item><item><title>Relearning Computer Science</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2015/10/28/relearning-computer-science/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2015 11:35:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2015/10/28/relearning-computer-science/</guid><description>Awakening I was awaken from a long sleep of ignorance with some events that occurred in the last couple of weeks. A sudden surge of conscientiousness about taking my education in my hands was one of the immediate results.
The inflection point was getting to hear Bryan Cantrill in person and interviewing with him the next day. I didn’t do my best, but was humbled by Cantrill into realizing how much I had to learn.</description></item><item><title>You literally ought to be asking yourself all...</title><link>https://techglider.in/quote/2013/11/13/you-literally-ought-to-be-asking-yourself-all/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2013 15:48:09 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/quote/2013/11/13/you-literally-ought-to-be-asking-yourself-all/</guid><description>You literally ought to be asking yourself all of the time - what&amp;rsquo;s the most important thing I could be working on in the world right now; and if you are not working on that, why aren&amp;rsquo;t you?
&amp;mdash;Aaron Swartz, as quoted by @TarenSK in the upcoming documentary on Swartz (Source: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3izOJ7zX5I0)</description></item><item><title>Your work is going to fill a large...</title><link>https://techglider.in/quote/2013/10/17/your-work-is-going-to-fill-a-large/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2013 10:01:53 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/quote/2013/10/17/your-work-is-going-to-fill-a-large/</guid><description>Your work is going to fill a large part of your life, and the only way to be truly satisfied is to do what you believe is great work. And the only way to do great work is to love what you do. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t found it yet, keep looking. Don&amp;rsquo;t settle. As with all matters of the heart, you&amp;rsquo;ll know when you find it. And, like any great relationship, it just gets better and better as the years roll on.</description></item><item><title>Week 1 at Bangalore and Work</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2013/07/21/week-1-at-bangalore-and-work/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2013 14:53:31 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2013/07/21/week-1-at-bangalore-and-work/</guid><description>I landed at Bangalore airport last week flying on an indiGo for the first time; found the experience better than JetKonnect from my first flight.
Next day (Sunday) started early with a walk to Oracle Tech Park and back to get myself familiarized with the area before first day at work. A much-needed haircut followed.
Having caught cold with the change in weather, I had to miss the Goodreads meetup planned at Brigade Road during the day, which I was eagerly awaiting to attend with a friend.</description></item><item><title>Work Like It’s Your Money</title><link>https://techglider.in/status/2013/05/25/work-like-its-your-money/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2013 12:37:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/status/2013/05/25/work-like-its-your-money/</guid><description>https://medium.com/i-m-h-o/f6413278c0f5
The first thing I learned when I got to college was that I needed to start criticizing things, and quickly. My tendency to smile marked me a…
Points 1 and 3 totally apply to me for my first startup internship.
Note: This is an archived post from my unmaintained Tumblr blog https://k4rtik.tumblr.com</description></item></channel></rss>