<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>NIT Calicut on The TechGlider</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/tags/nit-calicut/</link><description>Recent content in NIT Calicut on The TechGlider</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 10:51:01 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/tags/nit-calicut/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Things I wish I knew in College</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2016/10/01/things-i-wish-i-knew-in-college/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 10:51:01 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2016/10/01/things-i-wish-i-knew-in-college/</guid><description>Meta About a month ago, I asked the following question to the NIT Calicut CSE student body:
If you could ask only one question to an NITC CSE alumnus with diverse experience in industry, higher studies, and research, what would you?
The most raised concerns were:
How to decide between higher studies and industry as your next career move? What are the limitations of an NITC CSE education and how to succeed in the field despite them?</description></item><item><title>Of FOSSMeets at NIT Calicut</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2013/04/14/of-fossmeets-at-nit-calicut/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 08:33:41 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2013/04/14/of-fossmeets-at-nit-calicut/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been over a month and a half since the last edition of FOSSMeet at NIT Calicut. As an active member of organizing team for FOSSMeets &amp;lsquo;10 and &amp;lsquo;11 and a keen but silent observer for the 2013 edition, I want to share some history, some ideas &amp;amp; few observations with this post. The intent is to generate discussion among people who have been part of earlier FOSSMeets and to leave some things to ponder about (and act on) for juniors.</description></item><item><title>LaTeX Project Report Template Updated</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2013/02/15/latex-project-report-template-updated/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2013 14:36:40 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2013/02/15/latex-project-report-template-updated/</guid><description>The LaTeX logo (Photo credit: Wikipedia)
This will be quite short.
Many have told me they found the LaTeX Project Report Template that I published about two years back pretty useful. Today, I am releasing an update for the same. This includes a fix for a nasty bug in the original template apart from some layout changes.
Fork it from Github at https://github.com/k4rtik/latex-project-report-template to start creating your project reports.Visit http://k4rtik.</description></item><item><title>Even after giving enough time to that someone...</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/status/2013/02/08/even-after-giving-enough-time-to-that-someone/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2013 17:50:21 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/status/2013/02/08/even-after-giving-enough-time-to-that-someone/</guid><description>Even after giving enough time to that someone you are pissed off with, you can&amp;rsquo;t always expect to be impressed. Perhaps Randy was wrong. I held this view for a very long time; but time has taken such a turn in last few months that I am only left wondering what Randy exactly meant by enough time.</description></item><item><title>Logicomix: An Epic Search for Truth</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2013/02/03/logicomix-an-epic-search-for-truth/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2013 18:52:40 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2013/02/03/logicomix-an-epic-search-for-truth/</guid><description>This one needs to be quick, 14 minutes until midnight.
Logicomix (Photo credit: Wikipedia)
In this post I want to introduce a graphic novel which I read about a year back - Logicomix: An Epic Search for Truth.
How I ended up reading this is an interesting story in itself. Let me try to recite in minimum possible words. During that time (Sem 6) I had enrolled for a course called Computational Complexity by Murali sir.</description></item><item><title>28 Days Challenge</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2013/02/01/28-days-challenge/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 16:30:02 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2013/02/01/28-days-challenge/</guid><description>Inspired long back by Oliver Emberton&amp;rsquo;s herculian 30 Day Challenger, I have decided to try it out for myself this month. Feb being the smallest month should serve as the easiest possible start. ;-)
The motivation for doing this are similar - stretching myself to give up on a bad habit, get the most out of my day, or being more productive in general.
Given that I have a lot to say, things that keep on forming virtual blog posts in my mind - some of which are technical, some about my dream college, some advice for juniors, some worldly pondering, some internal struggles - I have decided on my first challenge:</description></item><item><title>Always code as if the guy who ends...</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/quote/2012/12/28/always-code-as-if-the-guy-who-ends/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2012 10:39:01 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/quote/2012/12/28/always-code-as-if-the-guy-who-ends/</guid><description>Always code as if the guy who ends up maintaining your code will be a violent psychopath who knows where you live. Code for readability.
&amp;mdash;John F Woods. Source: https://groups.google.com/d/msg/comp.lang.c++/rYCO5yn4lXw/oITtSkZOtoUJ (With special attribution to two juniors who posted this on homepage of CSEA&amp;rsquo;s upcoming website.)</description></item><item><title>It is necessary to work if not from...</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/quote/2012/07/18/it-is-necessary-to-work-if-not-from/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2012 08:29:33 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/quote/2012/07/18/it-is-necessary-to-work-if-not-from/</guid><description>It is necessary to work, if not from inclination, at least from despair. Everything considered, work is less boring than amusing oneself.
&amp;mdash;Charles Baudelaire (discovered this in Vinod Pathari Sir&amp;rsquo;s email signature and found it particularly interesting)</description></item><item><title>Ponderings of the Year Past: Part 2</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2012/03/26/ponderings-of-the-year-past-part-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2012 21:03:03 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2012/03/26/ponderings-of-the-year-past-part-2/</guid><description>The following are few important lessons I learnt over the gone year – 2011 (see Part 1 here):
Friends To be very frank (and you can call me weird), I didn&amp;rsquo;t know the meaning of a close friend until about early 2011. As far as I remember, until first semester, definition of a friend for me was somebody who shared similar interests, mutual respect, and trust. I remember objecting to Rama to call him names (in return of his such various favors) by saying &amp;ldquo;dude, I respect you!</description></item><item><title>Ponderings of the Year Past: Part 1</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2012/03/26/ponderings-of-the-year-past-part-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2012 19:59:28 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2012/03/26/ponderings-of-the-year-past-part-1/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been long since I wrote something. To be frank, it was last July in which I actually spoke out my mind. Of course, I wished to write a lot more (who doesn&amp;rsquo;t). This one is going to be long, so I decided to partition it.
The following are few important lessons I learnt over the gone year - 2011:
Computer Science != Computer Engineering Vineeth Sir always calls it Computing Science, we even had a discussion over it, perhaps over a year back( and once again recently); the doubt got cleared up only after I looked up ACM&amp;rsquo;s Computing Curricula Recommendations which defines five sub-disciplines of computing: Computer Science, Computer Engineering, Information Systems, Information Technology, and Software Engineering (they have pretty decent comparisons among these disciplines using pictures and charts).</description></item><item><title>Control All Computers in a Lab from a Single System</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2012/02/12/control-all-computers-in-a-lab-from-a-single-system/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2012 03:10:21 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2012/02/12/control-all-computers-in-a-lab-from-a-single-system/</guid><description>Quoting Dhandeep, our super-cool lab-admin:
now , all 70 systems in the lab can be switched on and switched off by single commands from the hostel&amp;hellip;
Yes, that and a lot more is possible in our Software Systems Lab now. How? Read on&amp;hellip;
The Setup We have over 70 systems with Ubuntu 10.04 LTS installed on them. There is an administrative account (let&amp;rsquo;s call it admin for this post) and a guest (limited privilege) account on each.</description></item><item><title>Bash Script to Download MIT OCW Videos</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2011/03/27/bash-script-to-download-mit-ocw-videos/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2011 08:28:01 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2011/03/27/bash-script-to-download-mit-ocw-videos/</guid><description>Some months back in November, I had used many variants of the following script to automate the download of MIT OCW videos:
#!/bin/bash baseurl=&amp;#34;http://www.archive.org/download/MIT_Structure_of_Computer_Programs_1986/lec&amp;#34; urlend=&amp;#34;b_512kb.mp4&amp;#34; log=&amp;#34;log_b&amp;#34; for i in {1..7} do nohup wget -c &amp;#34;${baseurl}$i${urlend}&amp;#34; &amp;gt; &amp;#34;${log}$i&amp;#34; &amp;amp; done It doesn&amp;rsquo;t really do much, just put the baseurl and urlend properly which should be common for similar links and run a for loop.
Sharing so that it may come handy to some others in similar needs.</description></item><item><title>And I successfully pulled out two consecutive all...</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/status/2011/03/06/and-i-successfully-pulled-out-two-consecutive-all/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2011 00:22:25 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/status/2011/03/06/and-i-successfully-pulled-out-two-consecutive-all/</guid><description>And I successfully pulled out two consecutive all-nighters - a first time in my life! For the record: my first all nighter in college was just in last sem (during which Jaseem had to kick me 2-3 times to keep me awake).
And these two were spent properly working on something I love and without facing any loss in productivity during the day. Congrats to myself!</description></item><item><title>The Branch Tour 2011 and me (Part 2)</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2011/03/01/the-branch-tour-2011-and-me-part-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 02:30:42 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2011/03/01/the-branch-tour-2011-and-me-part-2/</guid><description>This is second and the last part of my earlier post - The Branch Tour 2011 and me. Please read my last post before reading this.
Disclaimer: The following post is dedicated to all my branch mates and is a little more on the personal side. Additionally, the post is too long and may not be of any relevance for those who seek to attain any bit of technical nirvana from this blog.</description></item><item><title>Building a Modern Computer in 12 Steps - A Perfect Elective Course for Sem 3 of CSE</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2011/02/28/building-a-modern-computer-in-12-steps-a-perfect-elective-course-for-sem-3-of-cse/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2011 17:01:40 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2011/02/28/building-a-modern-computer-in-12-steps-a-perfect-elective-course-for-sem-3-of-cse/</guid><description>Just watched this Google Tech Talk on From Nand to Tetris in 12 steps by Shimon Schocken introducing a course he developed along with Noam Nisan:
A must watch for all CS faculty of hardware, algorithms and systems.
The course covers 12 projects to be done over a single semester covering building everything from basic logic gates to computer architecture, and from machine language to an operating system starting from a False and a NAND using a custom HDL.</description></item><item><title>The Branch Tour 2011 and me (Part 1)</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2011/02/28/the-branch-tour-2011-and-me-part-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2011 02:30:13 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2011/02/28/the-branch-tour-2011-and-me-part-1/</guid><description>Disclaimer: The following post is dedicated to all my branch mates and is a little more on the personal side. Additionally, the post is too long and may not be of any relevance for those who seek to attain any bit of technical nirvana from this blog. So, you may happily TLDR this post.
Many have asked me why I decided to go for branch tour when almost none of the northies were ready to go.</description></item><item><title>Accessing NIT Calicut's Ubuntu Mirror (in the campus)</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2011/02/01/accessing-nit-calicuts-ubuntu-mirror-in-the-campus/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 01:20:47 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2011/02/01/accessing-nit-calicuts-ubuntu-mirror-in-the-campus/</guid><description>As the FOSSCell webserver has been facing troubles these days, the instructions to use the Ubuntu Mirror of NIT Calicut that were available on the FOSSCell wiki are being missed by many. Here they are though not in the informative way as were given on the wiki:
Add the following to your /etc/apt/sources.list and comment out other similar repos.
deb http://192.168.40.97/ubuntu lucid-updates main multiverse restricted universe deb http://192.168.40.97/ubuntu lucid-security main multiverse restricted universe deb http://192.</description></item><item><title>Just finished reading Oral history inter...</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/status/2011/01/22/just-finished-reading-oral-history-inter/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2011 13:15:50 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/status/2011/01/22/just-finished-reading-oral-history-inter/</guid><description>Just finished reading Oral history interview with Edsger W. Dijkstra (transcript availabe on that link). This was suggested by Subhashree mam in our first lecture of Discrete Computational Structures course with her. An interesting read about Dijkstra&amp;rsquo;s life and history of the establishment of computing science as a discipline.</description></item><item><title>Discovered today the only two subjects I...</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/status/2011/01/20/discovered-today-the-only-two-subjects-i/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2011 15:07:21 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/status/2011/01/20/discovered-today-the-only-two-subjects-i/</guid><description>Discovered today the only two subjects I am really liking in my 4th sem of BTech:
Data Structures and Algorithms - no attendance, low strength, more discussion possible in Sudeep Sir&amp;rsquo;s class Computer Organization - I think I was always more inclined towards hardware and internals of computer system, assembly language programming comes as a bonus part with this course</description></item><item><title>Just installed QtSpim - the latest versi...</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/status/2011/01/14/just-installed-qtspim-the-latest-versi/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Jan 2011 04:34:22 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/status/2011/01/14/just-installed-qtspim-the-latest-versi/</guid><description>Just installed QtSpim - the latest version of SPIM MIPS Simulator, hope to do start with some assembly coding soon.</description></item><item><title>LaTeX Project Report Template</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2010/11/13/latex-project-report-template/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2010 05:39:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2010/11/13/latex-project-report-template/</guid><description>UPDATE RELEASED - Please use the latest version for all the LaTeX goodness.
Last week, starting from Sunday was spent in preparing my first project report in college and first using LaTeX. It took me over four days to finish the work. The end result was quite good and impressive. (See the attached report.pdf if you want to take a look).I abstracted a template from the report for future use. Hope it may be find some use for other NITCians or in general for everyone.</description></item><item><title>First Hands-on with Assembly Language Programming</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2010/10/25/first-hands-on-with-assembly-language-programming/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2010 09:46:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2010/10/25/first-hands-on-with-assembly-language-programming/</guid><description>I always wanted to learn assembly language programming. I had never tried do it myself and was disappointed to know that it was not there in our Logic Design course this semester (this because it was mentioned in the syllabus and I had taken pains to find good books on assembly from the library and get them issued, just to return them after learning that the syllabus for the course was too less compared to what was given on the department&amp;rsquo;s website).</description></item><item><title>Software Freedom Day 2010 at NIT Calicut</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2010/09/18/software-freedom-day-2010-at-nit-calicut/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2010 21:55:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2010/09/18/software-freedom-day-2010-at-nit-calicut/</guid><description>I am a member of the Free and Open Source Software Users group - FOSSCell - at my college - NIT Calicut. We celebrated Software Freedom Day yesterday for the first time.
We started planning for the celebration on our mailing list 5 days ago. Amid a lot of heated discussions we kept on updating the FOSSCell wiki ( http://fosscell.nitc.ac.in/wiki ) with our ideas, plans, suggestions, names of attendees and volunteers.</description></item><item><title>The Story of the LAN at A</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2010/07/02/the-story-of-the-lan-at-a/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2010 04:46:38 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2010/07/02/the-story-of-the-lan-at-a/</guid><description>The following post was supposed to be published on Feb 28, 2010. But due to my procrastination and the importance of this I am finally publishing it now after so much time has passed.
So, finally, the much awaited (and the answer to the most asked question to me: Abe, kab aa raha hai&amp;hellip;?) - LAN is here at A Hostel, my hostel at NIT Calicut.
It all started with a challenge I accepted from Aakash to bring the LAN to A Hostel within month of starting of second sem.</description></item><item><title>Missing writing on the blog</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2010/03/27/missing-writing-on-the-blog/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2010 08:50:12 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2010/03/27/missing-writing-on-the-blog/</guid><description>You may have noticed I have written almost nothing after November last year.
The main reason has been some or other problem with my website&amp;rsquo;s hosting server until it was shifted to another one in early Feb. But after this happened it&amp;rsquo;s some strange problem in the campus network that my website is only accessible at certain unexpected times as now. While writing this I am not sure, I will be able to publish this post or not, as the site seems accessible at completely random times and duration.</description></item><item><title>Adventure on our first visit to an airport</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2010/03/09/adventure-on-our-first-visit-to-an-airport/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2010 13:09:34 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2010/03/09/adventure-on-our-first-visit-to-an-airport/</guid><description>On Friday, I along with my friend Amit (aka Pandey) went to the Kozhikode airport to receive the guest Mr. Aditya Sengupta of FOSSEE, IIT Bombay. This was our first chance to visit an airport. We went in a taxi provided by IEEE Students Branch of our college. The peculiar thing about the taxi was its name: Taxi Kinglikutty (pardon me if I am messing up the name).
We reached 15 minutes earlier than the scheduled time of arrival and found that the flight was delayed by 20 minutes.</description></item><item><title>Status Update: Feb 26, 2010</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2010/02/26/status-update-feb-26-2010/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2010 08:15:14 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2010/02/26/status-update-feb-26-2010/</guid><description>BUSY: Setting up LAN at A Hostel (yay!)
BUSY: Exams start on Wednesday March 3; worrying when to start study ;)
BUSY: Trying to design a database to be used in CSED&amp;rsquo;s website
BUSY: Thinking when to read the book The Hitchhiker&amp;rsquo;s Guide to the Galaxy by Douglas Adams which has been chosen by me for a review
BUSY: Thinking what date to reserve train tickets to home after end sems</description></item><item><title>Going home after 135 days</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2009/11/29/going-home-after-135-days/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2009 17:23:55 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2009/11/29/going-home-after-135-days/</guid><description>This post will be short.
After spending more than 4 months here at NIT Calicut, I am finally going back home.
This period starting from AIEEE 2009 counseling in July has been an amazing roller coaster ride for me. Many wonderful things happened with me. I got admission to a college whose image I had always seen in my dreams. That too in the same branch, i.e. Computer Science &amp;amp; Engineering, except for which I knew I could never excel in any other engineering branch.</description></item><item><title>Tathva and the Seniors - Part 1</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2009/11/20/tathva-and-the-seniors-part-1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2009 17:55:21 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2009/11/20/tathva-and-the-seniors-part-1/</guid><description>OK, I agree, it&amp;rsquo;s been too late to post about Tathva. But I had this post in mind since the end of Tathva on October 25, 2009. This is the time, when I am quitting my procrastination and I am free from the daily schedule and writing this post.
First of all, let me talk about the Lecture Series at Tathva &amp;lsquo;09. It started with Dr. APJ Abdul Kalam visiting the campus, and continued with talks by Dr.</description></item><item><title>This is How a Budding Engineer Searches for his Glasses</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2009/11/15/this-is-how-a-budding-engineer-searches-for-his-glasses/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2009 08:34:33 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2009/11/15/this-is-how-a-budding-engineer-searches-for-his-glasses/</guid><description>Just spotted this on the unofficial Notice Board of Hostel A (my hostel at NIT Calicut). Please click on the pics to enlarge:
Disclaimer: The names and other sensitive info has been smudged to preserve the person&amp;rsquo;s privacy.
This left me wondering of the creative minds of my hostel mates. And yeah, if you find his specs, please return them. You can post a comment here and ask me to help you return the glasses ;).</description></item><item><title>Dr. APJ Abdul Kalam's visit to NIT Calicut</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2009/10/15/dr-apj-abdul-kalams-visit-to-nit-calicut/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2009 16:29:33 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2009/10/15/dr-apj-abdul-kalams-visit-to-nit-calicut/</guid><description>It was this day, that I was waiting for almost a month now. Dr. APJ Abdul Kalam visiting the campus of National Institute of Technology Calicut, my college.
And, it was just yesternight and today&amp;rsquo;s morning, that I was so excited to get his one glimpse in front of my eyes. Everything in the campus seemed so good yesterday, with all the decorations, lightings and preparations in Open Air Theatre (OAT) and near Aryabhatta Hall.</description></item><item><title>The TechGlider Blog is back</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2009/10/03/the-techglider-blog-is-back/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2009 09:11:09 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2009/10/03/the-techglider-blog-is-back/</guid><description>I am really happy to announce that I have been able to restore the TGB successfully (after fiddling with the backups for almost a month). This period of two and a half months without my blog was really unbearable for me; the only thing that helped me bear this pain was what was happening in my real life. A lot of wonderful events have changed my life (e.g. I have taken admission in BTech CSE at NIT Calicut).</description></item></channel></rss>