<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Hardware on The TechGlider</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/tags/hardware/</link><description>Recent content in Hardware on The TechGlider</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2015 16:58:36 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/tags/hardware/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Controlling iTunes using Android Wear</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2015/07/14/controlling-itunes-using-android-wear/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2015 16:58:36 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2015/07/14/controlling-itunes-using-android-wear/</guid><description>I happen to be surrounded by a lot of gadgets lately. One of them is a pretty Moto 360, one of the early Android Wear watches:
and another a MacBook Air (PlatiniumAir) which is about to celebrate its first anniversary:
This morning while walking-reading in my room, I had iTunes on the MacBook playing some tracks from one of the auto-generated Apple Music playlists. Now, it’s fairly easy to flick away mobile (lying away on my desk) notifications using my watch and not interrupt my reading for more than a couple seconds.</description></item><item><title>Found the culprit for a long standing problem...</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/status/2013/04/19/found-the-culprit-for-a-long-standing-problem/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2013 14:39:46 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/status/2013/04/19/found-the-culprit-for-a-long-standing-problem/</guid><description>Found the culprit for a long standing problem with Linux install disk booting on my Dell Studio XPS 1645 today at http://forums.linuxmint.com/viewtopic.php?f=46&amp;amp;t=126993#p692786 - it was my wireless card. Was facing this problem at least since last October when I tried to install latest editions of Fedora and ArchLinux but couldn&amp;rsquo;t. On Linux Mint 14 Cinnamon now.</description></item><item><title>Quickly Check Temperature Values of Hardware Components in Ubuntu</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2013/02/06/quickly-check-temperature-values-of-hardware-components-in-ubuntu/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2013 15:55:08 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2013/02/06/quickly-check-temperature-values-of-hardware-components-in-ubuntu/</guid><description>So, I missed posting yesterday. Hope this doesn&amp;rsquo;t repeat.
Today I am sharing a small bash script I wrote to check the temperatures recorded by various sensors in my laptop. Nothing incredibly smart here, just a quick but useful hack.
I am one of those unhappy Linux users who suffer from lack of driver support for their hardware. Due to some weird kernel bug or messy graphics driver, which led to incredibly high temperatures on my laptop, I spent about a year using Linux as a VirtualBox guest in Windows; this was before Ubuntu 12.</description></item><item><title>My First and Last 3D SketchUp</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2013/02/02/my-first-and-last-3d-sketchup/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2013 18:25:07 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2013/02/02/my-first-and-last-3d-sketchup/</guid><description>So, here is the first one.
[gallery type=&amp;ldquo;slideshow&amp;rdquo; ids=&amp;ldquo;512,513,514,515,516&amp;rdquo;]
I had created this long back in Decemeber of 2006. The file cab.skp (Google SketchUp file) was lying in my system since ages. Tried opening it today, discovered there is no Linux support for its viewer/editor (you listening Google?). After some fiddling with Wine and finally resorting to spend some time on a friend&amp;rsquo;s Windows Laptop, here we are. Quite a piece of art, ain&amp;rsquo;t it?</description></item><item><title>(Bangalore) Summer of '12... with BeagleBone</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2012/06/13/bangalore-summer-of-12-with-beaglebone/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2012 16:42:13 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2012/06/13/bangalore-summer-of-12-with-beaglebone/</guid><description>This post will be slightly long. Lots of exciting things happening over a Bangalore summer this year for me. :D
Somehow I always wanted to learn more about hardware and with a mentor like Khasim the road seems a lot more exciting. I first met him when he came to conduct a workshop on BeagleBoard during Tathva 2009 at my college - NIT Calicut. I was just a fresher then and have since regretted that I could not attend that workshop completely (due to my participation in various CS related competitions).</description></item><item><title>Use rfkill to Enable/Disable Wireless on your Linux Laptop</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2011/06/29/use-rfkill-to-enabledisable-wireless-on-your-linux-laptop/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2011 18:30:56 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2011/06/29/use-rfkill-to-enabledisable-wireless-on-your-linux-laptop/</guid><description>Imagine a situation when you have to book an air/train ticket in a jiffy, or check an important mail quickly and the only option you have is a wi-fi connection from either your smart phone or surroundings, and you have only some Linux variant installed on your system. And even after installing all the necessary drivers, you are unable to get the wi-fi on your laptop working? Frustrating right? If yes, then you might want to read on about this useful utility called rfkill which you can keep in handy for those weary situations.</description></item></channel></rss>