<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>lamp on The TechGlider</title><link>techglider.in/tags/lamp/</link><description>Recent content in lamp on The TechGlider</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2011 18:30:13 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="techglider.in/tags/lamp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Configuring Apache for Developing Multiple Websites under Ubuntu Linux</title><link>techglider.in/post/2011/08/18/configuring-apache-for-developing-multiple-websites-under-ubuntu-linux/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2011 18:30:13 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2011/08/18/configuring-apache-for-developing-multiple-websites-under-ubuntu-linux/</guid><description>Are you a beginner in web development with LAMP environment, or a CS/IT student overwhelmed with setting up LAMP and configuring it for your web-related academic project? If yes, then you are at the right place.
We have discussed earlier how easy it is to setup a web development environment on your Ubuntu desktop. In this article we will try to have a more customized setup of this environment for easily working with multiple websites.</description></item><item><title>Easiest Way to Setup a Web Development Environment on Ubuntu-based Distros</title><link>techglider.in/post/2011/07/08/easiest-way-to-setup-a-web-development-environment-on-ubuntu-based-distros/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2011 18:30:21 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2011/07/08/easiest-way-to-setup-a-web-development-environment-on-ubuntu-based-distros/</guid><description>Did you know how easy it is to get a basic web development environment on your Ubuntu-based Linux distribution? Guess what, it just takes 2 commands on the Terminal:
sudo apt-get install tasksel This will install a small utility which lets you install a lot packages grouped together as software collections.
sudo tasksel Launch tasksel and select &amp;lsquo;LAMP server&amp;rsquo; by pressing the SPACE key, press ENTER when you are done (see attached screenshot).</description></item><item><title>Welcome to the All New TechGlider Blog</title><link>techglider.in/post/2008/10/06/welcome-to-the-all-new-techglider-blog/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2008 23:46:23 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2008/10/06/welcome-to-the-all-new-techglider-blog/</guid><description>This is my first post on WordPress and through this I welcome you to the all new TechGlider Blog.
I am finally finished with moving the TGB to WordPress. WordPress offers a plethora of plugins to customize one&amp;rsquo;s blog and I am trying to choose what are those that I need for the TGB. As pointed out in my last post, this change hasn&amp;rsquo;t been easy. I almost lost all of my previous posts for there was no efficient way to import the posts from my b2evolution installation to WordPress, so I had to do it manually and took a whole day for that (these type of repetitive works are really a pain in the neck for me).</description></item><item><title>FOSS and LAMP Workshop at ABES by ILUG-D</title><link>techglider.in/post/2008/08/27/foss-and-lamp-workshop-at-abes-by-ilug-d/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2008 16:15:45 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2008/08/27/foss-and-lamp-workshop-at-abes-by-ilug-d/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been more than 10 days since I last posted &amp;lsquo;cause I was (and am) following a very busy schedule.
A lot happened in these days. The most prominent event among many was the LAMP workshop by the India Linux Users&amp;rsquo; Group, Delhi held on August 23, 2008 at ABES Engineering College.
I was trying to get a fully working linux distro installed on my PC since I first assembled my PC back in December 2006.</description></item></channel></rss>