<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>A Hostel on The TechGlider</title><link>https://techglider.in/tags/a-hostel/</link><description>Recent content in A Hostel on The TechGlider</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2010 04:46:38 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://techglider.in/tags/a-hostel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Story of the LAN at A</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2010/07/02/the-story-of-the-lan-at-a/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2010 04:46:38 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2010/07/02/the-story-of-the-lan-at-a/</guid><description>The following post was supposed to be published on Feb 28, 2010. But due to my procrastination and the importance of this I am finally publishing it now after so much time has passed.
So, finally, the much awaited (and the answer to the most asked question to me: Abe, kab aa raha hai&amp;hellip;?) - LAN is here at A Hostel, my hostel at NIT Calicut.
It all started with a challenge I accepted from Aakash to bring the LAN to A Hostel within month of starting of second sem.</description></item><item><title>Status Update: Feb 26, 2010</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2010/02/26/status-update-feb-26-2010/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2010 08:15:14 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2010/02/26/status-update-feb-26-2010/</guid><description>BUSY: Setting up LAN at A Hostel (yay!)
BUSY: Exams start on Wednesday March 3; worrying when to start study ;)
BUSY: Trying to design a database to be used in CSED&amp;rsquo;s website
BUSY: Thinking when to read the book The Hitchhiker&amp;rsquo;s Guide to the Galaxy by Douglas Adams which has been chosen by me for a review
BUSY: Thinking what date to reserve train tickets to home after end sems</description></item><item><title>This is How a Budding Engineer Searches for his Glasses</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2009/11/15/this-is-how-a-budding-engineer-searches-for-his-glasses/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2009 08:34:33 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2009/11/15/this-is-how-a-budding-engineer-searches-for-his-glasses/</guid><description>Just spotted this on the unofficial Notice Board of Hostel A (my hostel at NIT Calicut). Please click on the pics to enlarge:
Disclaimer: The names and other sensitive info has been smudged to preserve the person&amp;rsquo;s privacy.
This left me wondering of the creative minds of my hostel mates. And yeah, if you find his specs, please return them. You can post a comment here and ask me to help you return the glasses ;).</description></item></channel></rss>