<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>windows on The TechGlider</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/tags/windows/</link><description>Recent content in windows on The TechGlider</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2013 18:25:07 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/tags/windows/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>My First and Last 3D SketchUp</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2013/02/02/my-first-and-last-3d-sketchup/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2013 18:25:07 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2013/02/02/my-first-and-last-3d-sketchup/</guid><description>So, here is the first one.
[gallery type=&amp;ldquo;slideshow&amp;rdquo; ids=&amp;ldquo;512,513,514,515,516&amp;rdquo;]
I had created this long back in Decemeber of 2006. The file cab.skp (Google SketchUp file) was lying in my system since ages. Tried opening it today, discovered there is no Linux support for its viewer/editor (you listening Google?). After some fiddling with Wine and finally resorting to spend some time on a friend&amp;rsquo;s Windows Laptop, here we are. Quite a piece of art, ain&amp;rsquo;t it?</description></item><item><title>Restore GRUB in Ubuntu after installing Windows</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2011/06/25/restore-grub-in-ubuntu-after-installing-windows/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2011 18:30:44 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2011/06/25/restore-grub-in-ubuntu-after-installing-windows/</guid><description>So, you had Ubuntu (or any of its derivative) installed on your system and then decided to install Windows with it? And after installing Windows, you can&amp;rsquo;t load Ubuntu again, just follow the steps to get this working:
Boot the system using a Ubuntu Live disk.
After you reach the desktop, open Terminal (press Alt+F2, type &amp;ldquo;gnome-terminal&amp;rdquo; without quotes and press enter).
Execute:
``` sudo fdisk -l ``` Execute (after replacing sda7 with your corresponding linux root partition, which you will be able to identify from the output of the previous command - it&amp;rsquo;s usually marked as Linux): ``` sudo mount /dev/sda7 /mnt ``` Just check whether you got the root partition right, if you have more than 1 linux partition on your hard disk: ``` cd /mnt ls ``` If the listing contains names like bin, boot, dev, etc, home, tmp, usr, var, et cetera then you are in the right partition.</description></item><item><title>Sharing Internet Connection from my Laptop to my Android-based Phone</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2011/06/01/sharing-internet-connection-from-my-laptop-to-my-android-based-phone/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 19:56:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2011/06/01/sharing-internet-connection-from-my-laptop-to-my-android-based-phone/</guid><description>I was disheartened to know that my newly bought Samsung Galaxy S i9000 could not connect to an ad-hoc network created from my laptop.
After a little Googling, I found out the easiest way to turn a laptop into a WiFi Hot Spot (for uses such as sharing Internet connection with my Android phone) - Virtual Router and now I am enjoying fast internet on my phone.
As I call the above the easiest, it&amp;rsquo;s not the best method and doesn&amp;rsquo;t offer much features either.</description></item><item><title>Delaying Product Activation in Windows 7</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2010/05/28/delaying-product-activation-in-windows-7/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2010 02:16:52 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2010/05/28/delaying-product-activation-in-windows-7/</guid><description>We all know that we can use Windows 7 without entering a product key for 30 days. But do you know that the grace period until activation can be extended to a maximum of 150 days?
There is a way to do this and note that you should use this method when you have 2-3 days remaining for product activation as this method can work for a maximum of 4 times (30 days + 4 X 30 days = 150 days).</description></item></channel></rss>