<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Background on The TechGlider</title><link>techglider.in/categories/background/</link><description>Recent content in Background on The TechGlider</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2011 17:37:37 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="techglider.in/categories/background/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Good Bye TechGlider Forums, Ta-Ta NITC Wiki</title><link>techglider.in/post/2011/07/10/good-bye-techglider-forums-ta-ta-nitc-wiki/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2011 17:37:37 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2011/07/10/good-bye-techglider-forums-ta-ta-nitc-wiki/</guid><description>Today I bid adieu to The TechGlider Forums which used to reside at https://techglider.in/forums Started in August of 2008, it was my attempt to build a tech support community around my friends and visitors of my website - TechGlider.in. This decision comes at a time when I have realized it&amp;rsquo;s no longer a good idea to build a community like this on phpBB, with the advent of platforms like facebook and twitter (and Google+ more recently) and their penetrations in our lives.</description></item><item><title>The Story of the TechGlider</title><link>techglider.in/post/2011/03/26/the-story-of-the-techglider/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2011 05:41:22 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2011/03/26/the-story-of-the-techglider/</guid><description>Hi all, In this post I will be sharing some interesting points that fell along during realization of my idea of the TechGlider.First of all I am sharing some initial hand-drawn logos for the site. These were shared with my friend Arvis on June 28, 2009 for his comments.
The following was the outcome of earlier designs on July 5, 2009:
The following is a screenshot of StudenTech.</description></item><item><title>...and, we're back!</title><link>techglider.in/post/2011/03/13/and-we-are-back/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2011 07:43:51 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2011/03/13/and-we-are-back/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been so long - missing the TechGlider - my dream, my hard work of over 2 years was gone. Started in July 2008, gone in July 2010. :(
The reason of this long absence: I lost the ownership of the domain techglider.com - partly because of my own carelessness, and partly because of my webhost Four &amp;lsquo;S&amp;rsquo; Tech&amp;rsquo;s troubles. In the process, I did learn a few interesting things like the concept of drop catching, how the companies like GoDaddy make so much money; and more importantly how not to lose my domain again.</description></item><item><title>Going home after 135 days</title><link>techglider.in/post/2009/11/29/going-home-after-135-days/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2009 17:23:55 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2009/11/29/going-home-after-135-days/</guid><description>This post will be short.
After spending more than 4 months here at NIT Calicut, I am finally going back home.
This period starting from AIEEE 2009 counseling in July has been an amazing roller coaster ride for me. Many wonderful things happened with me. I got admission to a college whose image I had always seen in my dreams. That too in the same branch, i.e. Computer Science &amp;amp; Engineering, except for which I knew I could never excel in any other engineering branch.</description></item><item><title>Tathva and the Seniors - Part 1</title><link>techglider.in/post/2009/11/20/tathva-and-the-seniors-part-1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2009 17:55:21 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2009/11/20/tathva-and-the-seniors-part-1/</guid><description>OK, I agree, it&amp;rsquo;s been too late to post about Tathva. But I had this post in mind since the end of Tathva on October 25, 2009. This is the time, when I am quitting my procrastination and I am free from the daily schedule and writing this post.
First of all, let me talk about the Lecture Series at Tathva &amp;lsquo;09. It started with Dr. APJ Abdul Kalam visiting the campus, and continued with talks by Dr.</description></item><item><title>A Simple Tic Tac Toe Game in C</title><link>techglider.in/post/2009/11/12/a-simple-tic-tac-toe-game-in-c/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2009 13:24:53 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2009/11/12/a-simple-tic-tac-toe-game-in-c/</guid><description>Tic Tac Toe (T3), a two-player game developed in C/C++ in 2006-2007
For the school project in C++ in standard 11, I chose to make a game. Although the game doesn&amp;rsquo;t feature AI, it demonstrates the graphics and sound capabilities of C/C++ with Turbo C++ compiler.
Here is the link to the code (I can&amp;rsquo;t support it any more, so please don&amp;rsquo;t ask if you are unable to run it.):</description></item><item><title>The TechGlider Blog is now Kartik Scribbles...</title><link>techglider.in/post/2009/11/08/the-techglider-blog-is-now-kartik-scribbles/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2009 11:28:34 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2009/11/08/the-techglider-blog-is-now-kartik-scribbles/</guid><description>This change is something I wanted to incorporate since I restored this blog in the beginning of last month. Finally, the change is here.
The main reason why I changed the name of the blog is simple. &amp;lsquo;The TechGlider Blog&amp;rsquo; sounds like the official blog of my site - TechGlider.com which, in its actuality, is not that. This is my blog, Kartik&amp;rsquo;s. So, the name Kartik Scribbles&amp;hellip;
More personalized, more sensible, more fun, more readable.</description></item><item><title>Dr. APJ Abdul Kalam's visit to NIT Calicut</title><link>techglider.in/post/2009/10/15/dr-apj-abdul-kalams-visit-to-nit-calicut/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2009 16:29:33 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2009/10/15/dr-apj-abdul-kalams-visit-to-nit-calicut/</guid><description>It was this day, that I was waiting for almost a month now. Dr. APJ Abdul Kalam visiting the campus of National Institute of Technology Calicut, my college.
And, it was just yesternight and today&amp;rsquo;s morning, that I was so excited to get his one glimpse in front of my eyes. Everything in the campus seemed so good yesterday, with all the decorations, lightings and preparations in Open Air Theatre (OAT) and near Aryabhatta Hall.</description></item><item><title>Why I use Twitter? And why not Orkut or Facebook?</title><link>techglider.in/post/2009/10/11/why-i-use-twitter-and-why-not-orkut-or-facebook/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2009 16:05:28 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2009/10/11/why-i-use-twitter-and-why-not-orkut-or-facebook/</guid><description>So, it all started in 2006 when I was in class 11. The wave of orkut. I still remember, how I missed all the fun, when during the vacations after class X boards, most of my friends got broadband connections at their homes and started using orkut and became so close with each other and even with girls. I came to know of orkut only when it was too late sometime at the end of August 2006.</description></item><item><title>Wish I was at Shaastra 2009 HackFest</title><link>techglider.in/post/2009/10/03/wish-i-was-at-shaastra-2009-hackfest/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2009 16:37:42 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2009/10/03/wish-i-was-at-shaastra-2009-hackfest/</guid><description>Was just reading my twitter timeline when my eyes dropped on this tweet by Atul Chitnis:
achitnis: Small report about my talk at the IITM on the 1st: http://tinyurl.com/yaa58xe
The link points to Shaastra 2009 Hackfest – Day 1. After reading this page, I realize I have missed a great chance.
It was this last Saturady, I was trying so hard to get a railway ticket to Chennai to visit Shaastra 2009 at IIT Madras.</description></item><item><title>The TechGlider Blog is back</title><link>techglider.in/post/2009/10/03/the-techglider-blog-is-back/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2009 09:11:09 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2009/10/03/the-techglider-blog-is-back/</guid><description>I am really happy to announce that I have been able to restore the TGB successfully (after fiddling with the backups for almost a month). This period of two and a half months without my blog was really unbearable for me; the only thing that helped me bear this pain was what was happening in my real life. A lot of wonderful events have changed my life (e.g. I have taken admission in BTech CSE at NIT Calicut).</description></item><item><title>Just upgraded to WordPress 2.7</title><link>techglider.in/post/2009/05/09/just-upgraded-to-wordpress-27/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2009 09:45:26 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2009/05/09/just-upgraded-to-wordpress-27/</guid><description>Well it&amp;rsquo;s an all new world here in the administration side of this blog as I have upgraded to the latest version of WordPress.
It will take me time to explore the new interface and understand the new capabilities and features that this version 2.7.1 has to offer. And then will follow some new additions to The TechGlider Blog and maybe even a change of theme.
Just wait for me as I do these changes and write a new post about my first voting experience.</description></item><item><title>It's decided: IIT first, Web Development later</title><link>techglider.in/post/2008/11/22/its-decided-iit-first-web-development-later/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2008 05:15:06 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2008/11/22/its-decided-iit-first-web-development-later/</guid><description>Why? It&amp;rsquo;s the time I have decided to stop thinking about the development of TechGlider.com as for the last 2 months I haven&amp;rsquo;t been able to do any remarkable work mostly because of being unable to organize my ideas and put them into practice in short periods of 1-2 days I get home for in a week.
The burden of study is more and I need to focus on that, forgetting everything else in the world now (after all JEE-2009 is less than 5 months ahead).</description></item><item><title>How to become a Hacker?</title><link>techglider.in/post/2008/10/05/how-to-become-a-hacker/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2008 08:21:49 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2008/10/05/how-to-become-a-hacker/</guid><description>A lot of people ask me &amp;ldquo;how can I become a hacker&amp;rdquo;?
I ask them to differentiate between a hacker and a cracker first and specify what do they actually want to become. If the answer is a hacker, I need to direct them to this page (perhaps the best page on the net for a guide to becoming a hacker): http://www.catb.org/~esr/faqs/hacker-howto.html
For crackers-to-be I don&amp;rsquo;t have very-healthy feelings and ask them to correct their mindsets.</description></item><item><title>It's a Monthiversary!!</title><link>techglider.in/post/2008/08/31/its-a-monthiversary/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Aug 2008 00:03:57 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2008/08/31/its-a-monthiversary/</guid><description>Today, it&amp;rsquo;s been a month I started out posting on this blog.
And I feel happy about it. 11 posts in a month; it may seem too less to some of you, but, for me: I suppose I have been keeping up to my goal of writing regularly (and improving by the day :-) ).
I know I haven&amp;rsquo;t been able to fulfill certain promises I made on the blog viz: guide to installing Ubuntu and unveiling the main TechGlider site.</description></item><item><title>My PC's configuration</title><link>techglider.in/post/2008/08/16/my-pcs-configuration/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2008 11:09:09 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2008/08/16/my-pcs-configuration/</guid><description>My Platinium V2 (that&amp;rsquo;s the name of my PC) features:
Intel Core 2 Duo E6400 2.13 GHz processor
MSI P965 Neo MS-7235 mainboard
1.5 GB DDR2 SDRAM 667 MHz (512 MB Transcend, 1 GB Kingston)
Seagate Barracuda 7200.10 ST3320620AS 320 GB SATA hard disk
Palit ATi Radeon X800 GTO Graphics Card (256 MB) -&amp;gt; Sapphire ATi Radeon HD4670 Graphics Card (512 MB GDDR3, HDMI On-board)</description></item><item><title>All about TechGlider</title><link>techglider.in/post/2008/08/01/all-about-techglider/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2008 02:12:02 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2008/08/01/all-about-techglider/</guid><description>So, I am back. (That was a hard and very tiring day, yesterday, so couldn&amp;rsquo;t keep up to my promise of writing this post yesternight, :-( apologies)
TechGlider.com as its name suggests would take you gliding into the world of tech. The main focus would be on free and open source software but that doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean I won&amp;rsquo;t focus on Windows or computer hardware or mobile phones for that matter. In short there would be stuff related to all things tech.</description></item></channel></rss>