<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>website on The TechGlider</title><link>https://techglider.in/tags/website/</link><description>Recent content in website on The TechGlider</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2015 15:41:42 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://techglider.in/tags/website/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Exploring Medium</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2015/06/29/exploring-medium/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2015 15:41:42 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2015/06/29/exploring-medium/</guid><description>I am considering writing more often, more personal posts on Medium at https://medium.com/@k4rtik. Here&amp;rsquo;s first one among them:</description></item><item><title>Testing Automatic Deployment with Wercker</title><link>https://techglider.in/status/2015/03/16/testing-automatic-deployment-with-wercker/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2015 15:42:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/status/2015/03/16/testing-automatic-deployment-with-wercker/</guid><description>While reiniting this website, I had some requirements in mind for easy workflow of adding a post. Yesterday, I spent some time on the awesome tutorial on Automated deployments with Wercker for Hugo contributed by Arjen Schwarz, which seemed promising.
Apart from a tiny status update, this is a test post I am writing using the familiar GitHub&amp;rsquo;s online editor. Let&amp;rsquo;s see how it goes&amp;hellip;
EDIT: Couple of minutes later:</description></item><item><title>2014: Year in Review</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2014/12/31/2014-year-in-review/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 23:59:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2014/12/31/2014-year-in-review/</guid><description>Books If I had to describe what my year was about in just one word, it would be these. I was surrounded by books, all sorts of them, throughout the year. I had set out a goal to read 26 full-length books, ie, one per fortnight over the year. I was following the plan until May, when I rediscoverd my love for comic books with the launch of Amar Chitra Katha Android app and the 12 comic books that came free with it.</description></item><item><title>reinit</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2014/10/26/reinit/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2014 15:04:13 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2014/10/26/reinit/</guid><description>Today I am relaunching my website - https://techglider.in - in a new avatar. This, in the form of techglider.com, used to be my first website on the Internet until the .com domain was stolen by a domain shark. Sometime later, I switched to writing on wordpress.com and stopped maintaining this site.
A constant feeling of not having an official web home and a permanent place to put my thoughts out for the world has been nagging me for months, this reinit is the first step in solving this problem.</description></item><item><title>Good Bye TechGlider Forums, Ta-Ta NITC Wiki</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2011/07/10/good-bye-techglider-forums-ta-ta-nitc-wiki/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2011 17:37:37 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2011/07/10/good-bye-techglider-forums-ta-ta-nitc-wiki/</guid><description>Today I bid adieu to The TechGlider Forums which used to reside at https://techglider.in/forums Started in August of 2008, it was my attempt to build a tech support community around my friends and visitors of my website - TechGlider.in. This decision comes at a time when I have realized it&amp;rsquo;s no longer a good idea to build a community like this on phpBB, with the advent of platforms like facebook and twitter (and Google+ more recently) and their penetrations in our lives.</description></item><item><title>The Story of the TechGlider</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2011/03/26/the-story-of-the-techglider/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2011 05:41:22 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2011/03/26/the-story-of-the-techglider/</guid><description>Hi all, In this post I will be sharing some interesting points that fell along during realization of my idea of the TechGlider.First of all I am sharing some initial hand-drawn logos for the site. These were shared with my friend Arvis on June 28, 2009 for his comments.
The following was the outcome of earlier designs on July 5, 2009:
The following is a screenshot of StudenTech.</description></item><item><title>...and, we're back!</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2011/03/13/and-we-are-back/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2011 07:43:51 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2011/03/13/and-we-are-back/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been so long - missing the TechGlider - my dream, my hard work of over 2 years was gone. Started in July 2008, gone in July 2010. :(
The reason of this long absence: I lost the ownership of the domain techglider.com - partly because of my own carelessness, and partly because of my webhost Four &amp;lsquo;S&amp;rsquo; Tech&amp;rsquo;s troubles. In the process, I did learn a few interesting things like the concept of drop catching, how the companies like GoDaddy make so much money; and more importantly how not to lose my domain again.</description></item><item><title>Missing writing on the blog</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2010/03/27/missing-writing-on-the-blog/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2010 08:50:12 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2010/03/27/missing-writing-on-the-blog/</guid><description>You may have noticed I have written almost nothing after November last year.
The main reason has been some or other problem with my website&amp;rsquo;s hosting server until it was shifted to another one in early Feb. But after this happened it&amp;rsquo;s some strange problem in the campus network that my website is only accessible at certain unexpected times as now. While writing this I am not sure, I will be able to publish this post or not, as the site seems accessible at completely random times and duration.</description></item><item><title>Status Update: Feb 26, 2010</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2010/02/26/status-update-feb-26-2010/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2010 08:15:14 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2010/02/26/status-update-feb-26-2010/</guid><description>BUSY: Setting up LAN at A Hostel (yay!)
BUSY: Exams start on Wednesday March 3; worrying when to start study ;)
BUSY: Trying to design a database to be used in CSED&amp;rsquo;s website
BUSY: Thinking when to read the book The Hitchhiker&amp;rsquo;s Guide to the Galaxy by Douglas Adams which has been chosen by me for a review
BUSY: Thinking what date to reserve train tickets to home after end sems</description></item><item><title>My Old Projects</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2009/11/08/my-old-projects/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2009 11:00:33 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2009/11/08/my-old-projects/</guid><description>DAV Public School Website - Done in class 9 (2004) This website was done by me when I was studying in standard 9. As a product of an inter house web design competition (which yours truly won while facing other participants who were all seniors ranging from classes 10 to 12), this website inspired me to step further into web design. Download zip (598.81 KB) | Browse here
DAV Public School Website - Done in class 10 (2005) This was just a renovated version of the older site but with a lot of loaded content, included some videos of the school.</description></item><item><title>Testing websites with IE on linux</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2008/09/21/testing-websites-with-ie-on-linux/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2008 16:14:22 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2008/09/21/testing-websites-with-ie-on-linux/</guid><description>Just found this great tool IEs4Linux for testing websites under Internet Explorer 6, 5.5 and 5 on linux. It currently doesn&amp;rsquo;t support IE7 but that feature is in development beta. Find more info here: http://www.tatanka.com.br/ies4linux/page/Main_Page
Update (Jun 23, 2011):
IEs4Linux now also supports IE7, IE8 and IE9 in beta.
&amp;ndash;
Kartik - The TechGlider Guy
http://www.techglider.in</description></item></channel></rss>