<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>domain on The TechGlider</title><link>techglider.in/tags/domain/</link><description>Recent content in domain on The TechGlider</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2011 07:43:51 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="techglider.in/tags/domain/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>...and, we're back!</title><link>techglider.in/post/2011/03/13/and-we-are-back/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2011 07:43:51 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2011/03/13/and-we-are-back/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been so long - missing the TechGlider - my dream, my hard work of over 2 years was gone. Started in July 2008, gone in July 2010. :(
The reason of this long absence: I lost the ownership of the domain techglider.com - partly because of my own carelessness, and partly because of my webhost Four &amp;lsquo;S&amp;rsquo; Tech&amp;rsquo;s troubles. In the process, I did learn a few interesting things like the concept of drop catching, how the companies like GoDaddy make so much money; and more importantly how not to lose my domain again.</description></item><item><title>Broadband runs slow?</title><link>techglider.in/post/2008/08/23/broadband-runs-slow/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2008 16:29:19 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2008/08/23/broadband-runs-slow/</guid><description>If you have a broadband connection and find it taking too much time to load websites, you can try this method to make it a lot faster.
As you might be knowing, the web address you type in your browser to visit a particular site first gets resolved into a unique IP address by a DNS server. The default DNS servers your OS uses tend to be very slow. And here&amp;rsquo;s an alternative - OpenDNS.</description></item><item><title>Finally a website of my own!</title><link>techglider.in/post/2008/07/31/finally-a-website-of-my-own/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2008 00:44:02 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2008/07/31/finally-a-website-of-my-own/</guid><description>Hello there, :-) This is Kartik Singhal.
Well, finally done selecting a domain name (this was the most interesting part of the whole process), buying webspace and setting up this blog (quite complex a process, though) and I have my own website now!
I will introduce you to my ideas and future plans for this website here.
Please wait for my second post as it happens tonight with all the info I have to offer about this website.</description></item></channel></rss>