<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>TGF on The TechGlider</title><link>techglider.in/categories/tgf/</link><description>Recent content in TGF on The TechGlider</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2011 08:28:01 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="techglider.in/categories/tgf/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Bash Script to Download MIT OCW Videos</title><link>techglider.in/post/2011/03/27/bash-script-to-download-mit-ocw-videos/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2011 08:28:01 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2011/03/27/bash-script-to-download-mit-ocw-videos/</guid><description>Some months back in November, I had used many variants of the following script to automate the download of MIT OCW videos:
#!/bin/bash baseurl=&amp;#34;http://www.archive.org/download/MIT_Structure_of_Computer_Programs_1986/lec&amp;#34; urlend=&amp;#34;b_512kb.mp4&amp;#34; log=&amp;#34;log_b&amp;#34; for i in {1..7} do nohup wget -c &amp;#34;${baseurl}$i${urlend}&amp;#34; &amp;gt; &amp;#34;${log}$i&amp;#34; &amp;amp; done It doesn&amp;rsquo;t really do much, just put the baseurl and urlend properly which should be common for similar links and run a for loop.
Sharing so that it may come handy to some others in similar needs.</description></item><item><title>The Story of the TechGlider</title><link>techglider.in/post/2011/03/26/the-story-of-the-techglider/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2011 05:41:22 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2011/03/26/the-story-of-the-techglider/</guid><description>Hi all, In this post I will be sharing some interesting points that fell along during realization of my idea of the TechGlider.First of all I am sharing some initial hand-drawn logos for the site. These were shared with my friend Arvis on June 28, 2009 for his comments.
The following was the outcome of earlier designs on July 5, 2009:
The following is a screenshot of StudenTech.</description></item><item><title>Delaying Product Activation in Windows 7</title><link>techglider.in/post/2010/05/28/delaying-product-activation-in-windows-7/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2010 02:16:52 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2010/05/28/delaying-product-activation-in-windows-7/</guid><description>We all know that we can use Windows 7 without entering a product key for 30 days. But do you know that the grace period until activation can be extended to a maximum of 150 days?
There is a way to do this and note that you should use this method when you have 2-3 days remaining for product activation as this method can work for a maximum of 4 times (30 days + 4 X 30 days = 150 days).</description></item><item><title>Simple script to install essential packages in Ubuntu 10.04 Lucid 64-bit</title><link>techglider.in/post/2010/05/05/simple-script-to-install-essential-packages-in-ubuntu-10-04-lucid-64-bit/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2010 07:16:11 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2010/05/05/simple-script-to-install-essential-packages-in-ubuntu-10-04-lucid-64-bit/</guid><description>Please note that this script has been tested only with a lucid 64-bit installation. It requires an active internet connection to download packages (a broadband connection, otherwise it will seem to take forever to finish):
#!/bin/bash # Adding Medibuntu Repositories sudo wget http://www.medibuntu.org/sources.list.d/$(lsb_release -cs).list --output-document=/etc/apt/sources.list.d/medibuntu.list sudo aptitude update &amp;amp;&amp;amp; sudo aptitude install medibuntu-keyring &amp;amp;&amp;amp; sudo aptitude update sudo update-apt-xapian-index # Install multimedia codecs sudo apt-get remove gnash gnash-common libflashsupport mozilla-plugin-gnash swfdec-mozilla sudo apt-get install gstreamer0.</description></item><item><title>Recommended software for a new Ubuntu install</title><link>techglider.in/post/2010/04/30/recommended-software-for-a-new-ubuntu-install/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2010 15:35:38 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2010/04/30/recommended-software-for-a-new-ubuntu-install/</guid><description>Here&amp;rsquo;s my list of recommended software to install after doing a fresh Ubuntu installation:
netspeed ntfs-config gparted gnome-do wine vlc gimp filezilla stardict bluefish ccsm opera google chrome chm viewer or chmsee inkscape sunjava acroread python3 screem virtualbox &amp;ndash;
Kartik - The TechGlider Guy
http://www.techglider.in</description></item><item><title>A Simple Tic Tac Toe Game in C</title><link>techglider.in/post/2009/11/12/a-simple-tic-tac-toe-game-in-c/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2009 13:24:53 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2009/11/12/a-simple-tic-tac-toe-game-in-c/</guid><description>Tic Tac Toe (T3), a two-player game developed in C/C++ in 2006-2007
For the school project in C++ in standard 11, I chose to make a game. Although the game doesn&amp;rsquo;t feature AI, it demonstrates the graphics and sound capabilities of C/C++ with Turbo C++ compiler.
Here is the link to the code (I can&amp;rsquo;t support it any more, so please don&amp;rsquo;t ask if you are unable to run it.):</description></item><item><title>Essential software for a working Ubuntu 9.04 Desktop</title><link>techglider.in/post/2009/09/19/essential-software-for-a-working-ubuntu-9-04-desktop/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2009 15:08:30 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2009/09/19/essential-software-for-a-working-ubuntu-9-04-desktop/</guid><description>These are the steps to follow if you want your latest Ubuntu install to have all the essential software and codecs installed so that you can use your Ubuntu linux system as a/an replacement/addition of windows operating system.
You should be connected to internet to follow these steps. You can use Ctrl+Shift+V to paste the copied code in Terminal, which can be accessed as Applications-&amp;gt;Accessories-&amp;gt;Terminal.
First of all, choose the best server in System-&amp;gt;Administration-&amp;gt;Software Sources.</description></item><item><title>Checking BSNL broadband usage</title><link>techglider.in/post/2008/12/07/checking-bsnl-broadband-usage/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2008 13:34:03 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2008/12/07/checking-bsnl-broadband-usage/</guid><description>On older connections (before december 2007) broadband usage check can be done on one of the following IP addresses:
http://10.240.64.195
http://10.240.89.199
http://10.240.128.195
http://10.240.16.195
http://10.240.144.195
If one address doesn&amp;rsquo;t work, you can try another one. I happened to use the 4th IP address for a lot of months and one day it stopped working; now I am using the 2nd IP address from the above list.</description></item><item><title>How to become a Hacker?</title><link>techglider.in/post/2008/10/05/how-to-become-a-hacker/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2008 08:21:49 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2008/10/05/how-to-become-a-hacker/</guid><description>A lot of people ask me &amp;ldquo;how can I become a hacker&amp;rdquo;?
I ask them to differentiate between a hacker and a cracker first and specify what do they actually want to become. If the answer is a hacker, I need to direct them to this page (perhaps the best page on the net for a guide to becoming a hacker): http://www.catb.org/~esr/faqs/hacker-howto.html
For crackers-to-be I don&amp;rsquo;t have very-healthy feelings and ask them to correct their mindsets.</description></item><item><title>Testing websites with IE on linux</title><link>techglider.in/post/2008/09/21/testing-websites-with-ie-on-linux/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2008 16:14:22 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2008/09/21/testing-websites-with-ie-on-linux/</guid><description>Just found this great tool IEs4Linux for testing websites under Internet Explorer 6, 5.5 and 5 on linux. It currently doesn&amp;rsquo;t support IE7 but that feature is in development beta. Find more info here: http://www.tatanka.com.br/ies4linux/page/Main_Page
Update (Jun 23, 2011):
IEs4Linux now also supports IE7, IE8 and IE9 in beta.
&amp;ndash;
Kartik - The TechGlider Guy
http://www.techglider.in</description></item><item><title>What to do after a new Ubuntu 8.04 Hardy Heron installation?</title><link>techglider.in/post/2008/09/08/what-to-do-after-a-new-ubuntu-8-04-hardy-heron-installation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2008 10:52:09 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2008/09/08/what-to-do-after-a-new-ubuntu-8-04-hardy-heron-installation/</guid><description>After Install Tasks Have your internet connection ready. If you have ADSL (BSNL, Airtel broadband) connection, and you are used connecting using a username and password in windows, then, open up a Terminal (Applications-&amp;gt;Accessories) and give the following command: ``` sudo pppoeconf ``` You will prompted for your password. Then a wizard runs and detects your connection (usually eth0). Accept all the default settings and when prompted type your connection username and password.</description></item><item><title>A Guide to Installing Fedora 9: Part 2</title><link>techglider.in/post/2008/09/07/a-guide-to-installing-fedora-9-part-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2008 14:52:21 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2008/09/07/a-guide-to-installing-fedora-9-part-2/</guid><description>So, you have already booted up with the live DVD. Follow this part to actually install Fedora on your system&amp;hellip;
The Main Installation of Fedora: After reaching to the Fedora Desktop (if you don&amp;rsquo;t know how, follow the first part of this guide), use the &amp;ldquo;Install to Hard Drive&amp;rdquo; icon to start the Fedora installer. You will be greeted with the following window: Click &amp;lsquo;Next&amp;rsquo;. Select the layout of your keyboard from the list that appears (usually US English).</description></item><item><title>A Guide to Installing Fedora 9: Part 1</title><link>techglider.in/post/2008/09/06/a-guide-to-installing-fedora-9-part-1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2008 01:50:41 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2008/09/06/a-guide-to-installing-fedora-9-part-1/</guid><description>This is a beginner&amp;rsquo;s tutorial to installing Fedora 9 on your PC. In a recent survey I found that Fedora is more popular in India than Ubuntu (my personal favorite) so I decided to give a installation guide for Fedora instead of Ubuntu (read: https://techglider.in/blog/blog1.php/20 &amp;hellip; thiversary).
Prerequisites: You will need
Fedora 9 installation DVD (to know how to get one, visit: https://techglider.in/blog/blog1.php/20 &amp;hellip; ting-linux)
A PC system with atleast 9 GB of free space and minimum of 256 MB of RAM</description></item><item><title>Broadband runs slow?</title><link>techglider.in/post/2008/08/23/broadband-runs-slow/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2008 16:29:19 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2008/08/23/broadband-runs-slow/</guid><description>If you have a broadband connection and find it taking too much time to load websites, you can try this method to make it a lot faster.
As you might be knowing, the web address you type in your browser to visit a particular site first gets resolved into a unique IP address by a DNS server. The default DNS servers your OS uses tend to be very slow. And here&amp;rsquo;s an alternative - OpenDNS.</description></item><item><title>iPhone 3G</title><link>techglider.in/post/2008/08/23/iphone-3g/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2008 15:23:35 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2008/08/23/iphone-3g/</guid><description>As you may be knowing, Apple&amp;rsquo;s iPhone 3G has been launched just yesterday (Aug 22, 2008) at 00:00 hours by Airtel and Vodafone in India. They have kept its pricing as Rs. 31,000 for the 8 GB version and Rs. 36,100 for the 16 GB variant.
The iPhone is an example of convergence device which integrates an iPod, an internet device and of course a phone into a single piece of hardware.</description></item><item><title>Programming on your S60 phone!</title><link>techglider.in/post/2008/08/20/programming-on-your-s60-phone/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2008 00:44:11 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2008/08/20/programming-on-your-s60-phone/</guid><description>How many of you know that you can actually use your S60 phone (that includes all N-Series Nokia phones and certain others) to do programming? :?:
I just tried to this yesterday on my N72 and want to tell you that it&amp;rsquo;s a great fun to do and a finer way to cut time we waste in commuting (than listening to music or playing games on our mobile).
Of course you need to know programming in order to utilize your phone in this manner.</description></item><item><title>Recommended Addons for Mozilla Firefox</title><link>techglider.in/post/2008/08/17/recommended-addons-for-mozilla-firefox/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2008 07:28:58 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2008/08/17/recommended-addons-for-mozilla-firefox/</guid><description>Here&amp;rsquo;s a list of recommended addons for our favorite Mozilla Firefox web browser: (But first upgrade to latest version of Firefox if you haven&amp;rsquo;t done it yet:http://www.mozilla.com/en-US/firefox/ 8-)
For blocking ads, flash animations and scripts:
Adblock Plus (Don&amp;rsquo;t forget to subscribe to Easylist USA list in the window that pops-up after restarting Firefox) Flashblock NoScript For making your web experience easier:
Download Statusbar DownloadHelper Image Zoom Save Session Taboo For web development:</description></item><item><title>My PC's configuration</title><link>techglider.in/post/2008/08/16/my-pcs-configuration/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2008 11:09:09 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2008/08/16/my-pcs-configuration/</guid><description>My Platinium V2 (that&amp;rsquo;s the name of my PC) features:
Intel Core 2 Duo E6400 2.13 GHz processor
MSI P965 Neo MS-7235 mainboard
1.5 GB DDR2 SDRAM 667 MHz (512 MB Transcend, 1 GB Kingston)
Seagate Barracuda 7200.10 ST3320620AS 320 GB SATA hard disk
Palit ATi Radeon X800 GTO Graphics Card (256 MB) -&amp;gt; Sapphire ATi Radeon HD4670 Graphics Card (512 MB GDDR3, HDMI On-board)</description></item></channel></rss>