<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>college on The TechGlider</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/tags/college/</link><description>Recent content in college on The TechGlider</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 10:51:01 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/tags/college/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Things I wish I knew in College</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2016/10/01/things-i-wish-i-knew-in-college/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 10:51:01 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2016/10/01/things-i-wish-i-knew-in-college/</guid><description>Meta About a month ago, I asked the following question to the NIT Calicut CSE student body:
If you could ask only one question to an NITC CSE alumnus with diverse experience in industry, higher studies, and research, what would you?
The most raised concerns were:
How to decide between higher studies and industry as your next career move? What are the limitations of an NITC CSE education and how to succeed in the field despite them?</description></item><item><title>Sometimes, those casual group FB chats ...</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/status/2013/05/30/sometimes-those-casual-group-fb-chats-.../</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2013 18:57:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/status/2013/05/30/sometimes-those-casual-group-fb-chats-.../</guid><description>Note: This is an archived post from my unmaintained Tumblr blog https://k4rtik.tumblr.com</description></item><item><title>Bash Script to Download MIT OCW Videos</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2011/03/27/bash-script-to-download-mit-ocw-videos/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2011 08:28:01 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2011/03/27/bash-script-to-download-mit-ocw-videos/</guid><description>Some months back in November, I had used many variants of the following script to automate the download of MIT OCW videos:
#!/bin/bash baseurl=&amp;#34;http://www.archive.org/download/MIT_Structure_of_Computer_Programs_1986/lec&amp;#34; urlend=&amp;#34;b_512kb.mp4&amp;#34; log=&amp;#34;log_b&amp;#34; for i in {1..7} do nohup wget -c &amp;#34;${baseurl}$i${urlend}&amp;#34; &amp;gt; &amp;#34;${log}$i&amp;#34; &amp;amp; done It doesn&amp;rsquo;t really do much, just put the baseurl and urlend properly which should be common for similar links and run a for loop.
Sharing so that it may come handy to some others in similar needs.</description></item><item><title>The Story of the LAN at A</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2010/07/02/the-story-of-the-lan-at-a/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2010 04:46:38 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2010/07/02/the-story-of-the-lan-at-a/</guid><description>The following post was supposed to be published on Feb 28, 2010. But due to my procrastination and the importance of this I am finally publishing it now after so much time has passed.
So, finally, the much awaited (and the answer to the most asked question to me: Abe, kab aa raha hai&amp;hellip;?) - LAN is here at A Hostel, my hostel at NIT Calicut.
It all started with a challenge I accepted from Aakash to bring the LAN to A Hostel within month of starting of second sem.</description></item><item><title>Adventure on our first visit to an airport</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2010/03/09/adventure-on-our-first-visit-to-an-airport/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2010 13:09:34 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2010/03/09/adventure-on-our-first-visit-to-an-airport/</guid><description>On Friday, I along with my friend Amit (aka Pandey) went to the Kozhikode airport to receive the guest Mr. Aditya Sengupta of FOSSEE, IIT Bombay. This was our first chance to visit an airport. We went in a taxi provided by IEEE Students Branch of our college. The peculiar thing about the taxi was its name: Taxi Kinglikutty (pardon me if I am messing up the name).
We reached 15 minutes earlier than the scheduled time of arrival and found that the flight was delayed by 20 minutes.</description></item><item><title>Going home after 135 days</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2009/11/29/going-home-after-135-days/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2009 17:23:55 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2009/11/29/going-home-after-135-days/</guid><description>This post will be short.
After spending more than 4 months here at NIT Calicut, I am finally going back home.
This period starting from AIEEE 2009 counseling in July has been an amazing roller coaster ride for me. Many wonderful things happened with me. I got admission to a college whose image I had always seen in my dreams. That too in the same branch, i.e. Computer Science &amp;amp; Engineering, except for which I knew I could never excel in any other engineering branch.</description></item><item><title>Tathva and the Seniors - Part 1</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2009/11/20/tathva-and-the-seniors-part-1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2009 17:55:21 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2009/11/20/tathva-and-the-seniors-part-1/</guid><description>OK, I agree, it&amp;rsquo;s been too late to post about Tathva. But I had this post in mind since the end of Tathva on October 25, 2009. This is the time, when I am quitting my procrastination and I am free from the daily schedule and writing this post.
First of all, let me talk about the Lecture Series at Tathva &amp;lsquo;09. It started with Dr. APJ Abdul Kalam visiting the campus, and continued with talks by Dr.</description></item><item><title>This is How a Budding Engineer Searches for his Glasses</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2009/11/15/this-is-how-a-budding-engineer-searches-for-his-glasses/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2009 08:34:33 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2009/11/15/this-is-how-a-budding-engineer-searches-for-his-glasses/</guid><description>Just spotted this on the unofficial Notice Board of Hostel A (my hostel at NIT Calicut). Please click on the pics to enlarge:
Disclaimer: The names and other sensitive info has been smudged to preserve the person&amp;rsquo;s privacy.
This left me wondering of the creative minds of my hostel mates. And yeah, if you find his specs, please return them. You can post a comment here and ask me to help you return the glasses ;).</description></item><item><title>Dr. APJ Abdul Kalam's visit to NIT Calicut</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2009/10/15/dr-apj-abdul-kalams-visit-to-nit-calicut/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2009 16:29:33 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2009/10/15/dr-apj-abdul-kalams-visit-to-nit-calicut/</guid><description>It was this day, that I was waiting for almost a month now. Dr. APJ Abdul Kalam visiting the campus of National Institute of Technology Calicut, my college.
And, it was just yesternight and today&amp;rsquo;s morning, that I was so excited to get his one glimpse in front of my eyes. Everything in the campus seemed so good yesterday, with all the decorations, lightings and preparations in Open Air Theatre (OAT) and near Aryabhatta Hall.</description></item></channel></rss>