<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>techglider on The TechGlider</title><link>techglider.in/tags/techglider/</link><description>Recent content in techglider on The TechGlider</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2014 01:30:58 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="techglider.in/tags/techglider/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Posts from The TechGlider Blog Migrated</title><link>techglider.in/post/2014/10/27/posts-from-the-techglider-blog-migrated/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2014 01:30:58 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2014/10/27/posts-from-the-techglider-blog-migrated/</guid><description>Just a quick note that I have successfully migrated all posts from the original TechGlider Blog which used to reside at http://techglider.in/kartik/blog couple of years ago.
This completes migration of all my written content. Fixing broken links, images, etc. is the major work that remains.
Aside:
I ended up skimming through much of my old content, feels very childish now; my friends from that time might get a laugh or two reading about memories recorded in here.</description></item><item><title>reinit</title><link>techglider.in/post/2014/10/26/reinit/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2014 15:04:13 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2014/10/26/reinit/</guid><description>Today I am relaunching my website - http://techglider.in - in a new avatar. This, in the form of techglider.com, used to be my first website on the Internet until the .com domain was stolen by a domain shark. Sometime later, I switched to writing on wordpress.com and stopped maintaining this site.
A constant feeling of not having an official web home and a permanent place to put my thoughts out for the world has been nagging me for months, this reinit is the first step in solving this problem.</description></item><item><title>Good Bye TechGlider Forums, Ta-Ta NITC Wiki</title><link>techglider.in/post/2011/07/10/good-bye-techglider-forums-ta-ta-nitc-wiki/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2011 17:37:37 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2011/07/10/good-bye-techglider-forums-ta-ta-nitc-wiki/</guid><description>Today I bid adieu to The TechGlider Forums which used to reside at http://techglider.in/forums Started in August of 2008, it was my attempt to build a tech support community around my friends and visitors of my website - TechGlider.in. This decision comes at a time when I have realized it&amp;rsquo;s no longer a good idea to build a community like this on phpBB, with the advent of platforms like facebook and twitter (and Google+ more recently) and their penetrations in our lives.</description></item><item><title>The Story of the TechGlider</title><link>techglider.in/post/2011/03/26/the-story-of-the-techglider/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2011 05:41:22 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2011/03/26/the-story-of-the-techglider/</guid><description>Hi all, In this post I will be sharing some interesting points that fell along during realization of my idea of the TechGlider.First of all I am sharing some initial hand-drawn logos for the site. These were shared with my friend Arvis on June 28, 2009 for his comments.
The following was the outcome of earlier designs on July 5, 2009:
The following is a screenshot of StudenTech.</description></item><item><title>Done messing up enough with the looks of...</title><link>techglider.in/status/2011/03/13/done-messing-up-enough-with-the-looks-of/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2011 17:33:55 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/status/2011/03/13/done-messing-up-enough-with-the-looks-of/</guid><description>Done messing up enough with the looks of my old blog for the day. Have exams this week and haven&amp;rsquo;t studied a thing. Need to take a week&amp;rsquo;s break from the net. ;)
On another note: I have restored my website: TechGlider.in during this Ragam. Do take a look at &amp;hellip;and, we&amp;rsquo;re back!.</description></item><item><title>...and, we're back!</title><link>techglider.in/post/2011/03/13/and-we-are-back/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2011 07:43:51 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2011/03/13/and-we-are-back/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been so long - missing the TechGlider - my dream, my hard work of over 2 years was gone. Started in July 2008, gone in July 2010. :(
The reason of this long absence: I lost the ownership of the domain techglider.com - partly because of my own carelessness, and partly because of my webhost Four &amp;lsquo;S&amp;rsquo; Tech&amp;rsquo;s troubles. In the process, I did learn a few interesting things like the concept of drop catching, how the companies like GoDaddy make so much money; and more importantly how not to lose my domain again.</description></item><item><title>All about TechGlider</title><link>techglider.in/post/2008/08/01/all-about-techglider/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2008 02:12:02 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2008/08/01/all-about-techglider/</guid><description>So, I am back. (That was a hard and very tiring day, yesterday, so couldn&amp;rsquo;t keep up to my promise of writing this post yesternight, :-( apologies)
TechGlider.com as its name suggests would take you gliding into the world of tech. The main focus would be on free and open source software but that doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean I won&amp;rsquo;t focus on Windows or computer hardware or mobile phones for that matter. In short there would be stuff related to all things tech.</description></item></channel></rss>