<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>july 31 on The TechGlider</title><link>https://techglider.in/tags/july-31/</link><description>Recent content in july 31 on The TechGlider</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2011 07:43:51 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://techglider.in/tags/july-31/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>...and, we're back!</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2011/03/13/and-we-are-back/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2011 07:43:51 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2011/03/13/and-we-are-back/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been so long - missing the TechGlider - my dream, my hard work of over 2 years was gone. Started in July 2008, gone in July 2010. :(
The reason of this long absence: I lost the ownership of the domain techglider.com - partly because of my own carelessness, and partly because of my webhost Four &amp;lsquo;S&amp;rsquo; Tech&amp;rsquo;s troubles. In the process, I did learn a few interesting things like the concept of drop catching, how the companies like GoDaddy make so much money; and more importantly how not to lose my domain again.</description></item><item><title>That hard and tiring day of July 31</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2008/08/05/that-hard-and-tiring-day-of-july-31/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2008 14:22:47 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2008/08/05/that-hard-and-tiring-day-of-july-31/</guid><description>I mentioned about this day in my post of August 1.
I started the day at night by wishing a friend birthday, eventually making her wakeup at midnight. Then, came the inauguration of my website with my first post on The TechGlider Blog at 6 in the morning. This was the easy part of the day.
I reached the Ghaziabad Railway Station at 7:50 to board the train to Tilak Bridge at Delhi, for I use to go to South Delhi to attend FIITJEE classes for IIT-JEE preparation.</description></item></channel></rss>