<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Welcome on The TechGlider</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/categories/welcome/</link><description>Recent content in Welcome on The TechGlider</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2011 07:43:51 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/categories/welcome/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>...and, we're back!</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2011/03/13/and-we-are-back/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2011 07:43:51 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2011/03/13/and-we-are-back/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been so long - missing the TechGlider - my dream, my hard work of over 2 years was gone. Started in July 2008, gone in July 2010. :(
The reason of this long absence: I lost the ownership of the domain techglider.com - partly because of my own carelessness, and partly because of my webhost Four &amp;lsquo;S&amp;rsquo; Tech&amp;rsquo;s troubles. In the process, I did learn a few interesting things like the concept of drop catching, how the companies like GoDaddy make so much money; and more importantly how not to lose my domain again.</description></item><item><title>The TechGlider Blog is now Kartik Scribbles...</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2009/11/08/the-techglider-blog-is-now-kartik-scribbles/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2009 11:28:34 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2009/11/08/the-techglider-blog-is-now-kartik-scribbles/</guid><description>This change is something I wanted to incorporate since I restored this blog in the beginning of last month. Finally, the change is here.
The main reason why I changed the name of the blog is simple. &amp;lsquo;The TechGlider Blog&amp;rsquo; sounds like the official blog of my site - TechGlider.com which, in its actuality, is not that. This is my blog, Kartik&amp;rsquo;s. So, the name Kartik Scribbles&amp;hellip;
More personalized, more sensible, more fun, more readable.</description></item><item><title>The TechGlider Blog is back</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2009/10/03/the-techglider-blog-is-back/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2009 09:11:09 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2009/10/03/the-techglider-blog-is-back/</guid><description>I am really happy to announce that I have been able to restore the TGB successfully (after fiddling with the backups for almost a month). This period of two and a half months without my blog was really unbearable for me; the only thing that helped me bear this pain was what was happening in my real life. A lot of wonderful events have changed my life (e.g. I have taken admission in BTech CSE at NIT Calicut).</description></item><item><title>On Deepawali and the change of theme</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2008/10/28/on-deepawali-and-theme-change/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2008 17:09:34 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2008/10/28/on-deepawali-and-theme-change/</guid><description>This is today that somebody pointed out: &amp;ldquo;Your blog is not looking that fine&amp;rdquo;. And I realize why I lost interest in writing on this blog.
Following the suggestion I have changed the blog&amp;rsquo;s theme again. Tell me, if this one feels fine enough.
Today is Deepawali, the so-called biggest festival of India. Everybody out there is celebrating, burning crackers, or making merry; and here I am writing on my blog after a long break (my biggest break ever), amid the sounds of ladis, bombs, rockets, whistlers.</description></item><item><title>Welcome to the All New TechGlider Blog</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2008/10/06/welcome-to-the-all-new-techglider-blog/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2008 23:46:23 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2008/10/06/welcome-to-the-all-new-techglider-blog/</guid><description>This is my first post on WordPress and through this I welcome you to the all new TechGlider Blog.
I am finally finished with moving the TGB to WordPress. WordPress offers a plethora of plugins to customize one&amp;rsquo;s blog and I am trying to choose what are those that I need for the TGB. As pointed out in my last post, this change hasn&amp;rsquo;t been easy. I almost lost all of my previous posts for there was no efficient way to import the posts from my b2evolution installation to WordPress, so I had to do it manually and took a whole day for that (these type of repetitive works are really a pain in the neck for me).</description></item><item><title>TechGlider logo, finally designed</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2008/09/30/techglider-logo-finally-designed/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2008 04:48:54 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2008/09/30/techglider-logo-finally-designed/</guid><description>I am happy :-) to inform all of you that I have finally designed a logo for the TechGlider:
Although I am not that satisfied with the logo, but I think it will do for the time being. Any suggestions for improvement of the logo are welcome.
I couldn&amp;rsquo;t finish the development of TechGlider this week (designing a logo really takes too much of time ;-)</description></item><item><title>The TechGlider Forums are now active.</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2008/08/14/the-techglider-forums-are-now-active/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2008 00:31:56 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2008/08/14/the-techglider-forums-are-now-active/</guid><description>I am glad to inform you that finally the The TechGlider Forums have been activated on techglider.in. :-)
To visit the forums you can go to http://forums.techglider.in. Please read the first topic &amp;ldquo;General Rules&amp;rdquo; before posting anything on the forums.
You can register yourself on the forums by clicking on the &amp;ldquo;Register&amp;rdquo; link at the top-right of the page. After you become a member, you can ask questions, get answers, start new topics for discussions under the given categories and post about anything you like.</description></item><item><title>All about TechGlider</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2008/08/01/all-about-techglider/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2008 02:12:02 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2008/08/01/all-about-techglider/</guid><description>So, I am back. (That was a hard and very tiring day, yesterday, so couldn&amp;rsquo;t keep up to my promise of writing this post yesternight, :-( apologies)
TechGlider.com as its name suggests would take you gliding into the world of tech. The main focus would be on free and open source software but that doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean I won&amp;rsquo;t focus on Windows or computer hardware or mobile phones for that matter. In short there would be stuff related to all things tech.</description></item><item><title>Finally a website of my own!</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2008/07/31/finally-a-website-of-my-own/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2008 00:44:02 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2008/07/31/finally-a-website-of-my-own/</guid><description>Hello there, :-) This is Kartik Singhal.
Well, finally done selecting a domain name (this was the most interesting part of the whole process), buying webspace and setting up this blog (quite complex a process, though) and I have my own website now!
I will introduce you to my ideas and future plans for this website here.
Please wait for my second post as it happens tonight with all the info I have to offer about this website.</description></item></channel></rss>