<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>programming on The TechGlider</title><link>https://techglider.in/tags/programming/</link><description>Recent content in programming on The TechGlider</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2015 21:19:16 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://techglider.in/tags/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Gap</title><link>https://techglider.in/quote/2015/12/06/the-gap/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2015 21:19:16 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/quote/2015/12/06/the-gap/</guid><description>Nobody tells this to people who are beginners, I wish someone told me. All of us who do creative work, we get into it because we have good taste. But there is this gap. For the first couple years you make stuff, it&amp;rsquo;s just not that good. It&amp;rsquo;s trying to be good, it has potential, but it&amp;rsquo;s not. But your taste, the thing that got you into the game, is still killer.</description></item><item><title>Reading A Tour of C++</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2015/07/18/tour-of-cplusplus/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2015 20:18:19 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2015/07/18/tour-of-cplusplus/</guid><description>I have been reading Bjarne Stroustrup’s A Tour of C++ and the language feels like a totally new language since my last project in C++ which was years ago. Since, (re-)learning a language requires both reading and writing code, I decided to work through some exercises on Exercism.
For C++, Exercism encourages a test-driven approach to solving problems and requires some tooling support (CMake) to focus on solving the problem instead of wasting time on setting up a build system for each exercise.</description></item><item><title>Controlling iTunes using Android Wear</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2015/07/14/controlling-itunes-using-android-wear/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2015 16:58:36 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2015/07/14/controlling-itunes-using-android-wear/</guid><description>I happen to be surrounded by a lot of gadgets lately. One of them is a pretty Moto 360, one of the early Android Wear watches:
and another a MacBook Air (PlatiniumAir) which is about to celebrate its first anniversary:
This morning while walking-reading in my room, I had iTunes on the MacBook playing some tracks from one of the auto-generated Apple Music playlists. Now, it’s fairly easy to flick away mobile (lying away on my desk) notifications using my watch and not interrupt my reading for more than a couple seconds.</description></item><item><title>Worry Dream</title><link>https://techglider.in/status/2013/06/11/worry-dream/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2013 04:17:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/status/2013/06/11/worry-dream/</guid><description>visual-punctuation:
One of the most impressive gaming building platforms I’ve ever seen.
Creating a better canvas, to create a better artist.
Brilliant! Really. I want to try this out.
Note: This is an archived post from my unmaintained Tumblr blog https://k4rtik.tumblr.com</description></item><item><title>The programmers of tomorrow are the wizards of...</title><link>https://techglider.in/quote/2013/02/26/the-programmers-of-tomorrow-are-the-wizards-of/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2013 18:59:54 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/quote/2013/02/26/the-programmers-of-tomorrow-are-the-wizards-of/</guid><description>The programmers of tomorrow are the wizards of the future. You&amp;rsquo;re going to look like you have magic powers compared to everybody else.
&amp;mdash;Gabe Newell, Founder and President, Valve (Source: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dU1xS07N-FA courtesy of code.org)</description></item><item><title>Always code as if the guy who ends...</title><link>https://techglider.in/quote/2012/12/28/always-code-as-if-the-guy-who-ends/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2012 10:39:01 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/quote/2012/12/28/always-code-as-if-the-guy-who-ends/</guid><description>Always code as if the guy who ends up maintaining your code will be a violent psychopath who knows where you live. Code for readability.
&amp;mdash;John F Woods. Source: https://groups.google.com/d/msg/comp.lang.c++/rYCO5yn4lXw/oITtSkZOtoUJ (With special attribution to two juniors who posted this on homepage of CSEA&amp;rsquo;s upcoming website.)</description></item><item><title>A Fun Security Weekend with null and sCTF</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2012/06/22/a-fun-security-weekend-with-null-and-sctf/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2012 19:39:05 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2012/06/22/a-fun-security-weekend-with-null-and-sctf/</guid><description>I know it&amp;rsquo;s quite late to post about the last weekend when another weekend is around the corner, but couldn&amp;rsquo;t control myself as the last one was so eventful. :)
It was almost 2 weeks back that I got to know about sCTF 2012. I have always wanted to learn about computer security (and the darker side of hacking), but haven&amp;rsquo;t been able to give time it to it. What followed was a quick search for team members from among my batch via FB - Nithin immediately showed interest, we pulled Jerrin in too.</description></item><item><title>(Bangalore) Summer of '12... with BeagleBone</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2012/06/13/bangalore-summer-of-12-with-beaglebone/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2012 16:42:13 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2012/06/13/bangalore-summer-of-12-with-beaglebone/</guid><description>This post will be slightly long. Lots of exciting things happening over a Bangalore summer this year for me. :D
Somehow I always wanted to learn more about hardware and with a mentor like Khasim the road seems a lot more exciting. I first met him when he came to conduct a workshop on BeagleBoard during Tathva 2009 at my college - NIT Calicut. I was just a fresher then and have since regretted that I could not attend that workshop completely (due to my participation in various CS related competitions).</description></item><item><title>Control All Computers in a Lab from a Single System</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2012/02/12/control-all-computers-in-a-lab-from-a-single-system/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2012 03:10:21 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2012/02/12/control-all-computers-in-a-lab-from-a-single-system/</guid><description>Quoting Dhandeep, our super-cool lab-admin:
now , all 70 systems in the lab can be switched on and switched off by single commands from the hostel&amp;hellip;
Yes, that and a lot more is possible in our Software Systems Lab now. How? Read on&amp;hellip;
The Setup We have over 70 systems with Ubuntu 10.04 LTS installed on them. There is an administrative account (let&amp;rsquo;s call it admin for this post) and a guest (limited privilege) account on each.</description></item><item><title>Building a Modern Computer in 12 Steps - A Perfect Elective Course for Sem 3 of CSE</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2011/02/28/building-a-modern-computer-in-12-steps-a-perfect-elective-course-for-sem-3-of-cse/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2011 17:01:40 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2011/02/28/building-a-modern-computer-in-12-steps-a-perfect-elective-course-for-sem-3-of-cse/</guid><description>Just watched this Google Tech Talk on From Nand to Tetris in 12 steps by Shimon Schocken introducing a course he developed along with Noam Nisan:
A must watch for all CS faculty of hardware, algorithms and systems.
The course covers 12 projects to be done over a single semester covering building everything from basic logic gates to computer architecture, and from machine language to an operating system starting from a False and a NAND using a custom HDL.</description></item><item><title>Input/Output using Text Files Without Diving into File Handling</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2011/02/10/inputoutput-using-text-files-without-diving-into-file-handling/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2011 10:18:08 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2011/02/10/inputoutput-using-text-files-without-diving-into-file-handling/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s quite easy to use text files as input source or to redirect the output of programs to files if you happen to do programming on a unix/linux terminal.
Let&amp;rsquo;s take an example of a usual random number generator:
// random.c #include &amp;lt;stdio.h&amp;gt;#include &amp;lt;stdlib.h&amp;gt;int main () { int i, count=99999999; for (i = 0; i &amp;lt; count; i += 1) printf(&amp;#34;%d\n&amp;#34;, (int)random()); return 0; } Let&amp;rsquo;s generate an executable by the name random.</description></item><item><title>Discovered today the only two subjects I...</title><link>https://techglider.in/status/2011/01/20/discovered-today-the-only-two-subjects-i/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2011 15:07:21 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/status/2011/01/20/discovered-today-the-only-two-subjects-i/</guid><description>Discovered today the only two subjects I am really liking in my 4th sem of BTech:
Data Structures and Algorithms - no attendance, low strength, more discussion possible in Sudeep Sir&amp;rsquo;s class Computer Organization - I think I was always more inclined towards hardware and internals of computer system, assembly language programming comes as a bonus part with this course</description></item><item><title>Just installed QtSpim - the latest versi...</title><link>https://techglider.in/status/2011/01/14/just-installed-qtspim-the-latest-versi/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Jan 2011 04:34:22 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/status/2011/01/14/just-installed-qtspim-the-latest-versi/</guid><description>Just installed QtSpim - the latest version of SPIM MIPS Simulator, hope to do start with some assembly coding soon.</description></item><item><title>First Hands-on with Assembly Language Programming</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2010/10/25/first-hands-on-with-assembly-language-programming/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2010 09:46:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2010/10/25/first-hands-on-with-assembly-language-programming/</guid><description>I always wanted to learn assembly language programming. I had never tried do it myself and was disappointed to know that it was not there in our Logic Design course this semester (this because it was mentioned in the syllabus and I had taken pains to find good books on assembly from the library and get them issued, just to return them after learning that the syllabus for the course was too less compared to what was given on the department&amp;rsquo;s website).</description></item><item><title>Using gdb to see through your program flow!</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2010/10/05/using-gdb-to-see-through-your-program-flow/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2010 11:37:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2010/10/05/using-gdb-to-see-through-your-program-flow/</guid><description>Using GDB was something I wanted to learn since I started programming in GNU/Linux environment. I read through man pages, info pages, and some vague guides on the net over the weeks but couldn&amp;rsquo;t figure out why wasn&amp;rsquo;t I able to use it properly.
Then somehow I found this: RMS&amp;rsquo;s gdb Debugger Tutorial and learned that the I was making a very small mistake every time while compiling the code.</description></item></channel></rss>