<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>change on The TechGlider</title><link>techglider.in/tags/change/</link><description>Recent content in change on The TechGlider</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 10:51:01 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="techglider.in/tags/change/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Things I wish I knew in College</title><link>techglider.in/post/2016/10/01/things-i-wish-i-knew-in-college/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 10:51:01 -0400</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2016/10/01/things-i-wish-i-knew-in-college/</guid><description>Meta About a month ago, I asked the following question to the NIT Calicut CSE student body:
If you could ask only one question to an NITC CSE alumnus with diverse experience in industry, higher studies, and research, what would you?
The most raised concerns were:
How to decide between higher studies and industry as your next career move? What are the limitations of an NITC CSE education and how to succeed in the field despite them?</description></item><item><title>Reflections on the Facebook Sannyasa</title><link>techglider.in/post/2016/04/24/reflections-on-the-facebook-sannyasa/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2016 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2016/04/24/reflections-on-the-facebook-sannyasa/</guid><description>As some of you reading this might be aware I have been away for a while.
I deactivated my Facebook account sometime in the first week of Feb; it has been over 75 days. I did try activating it once after 30 days were over and realized within a couple of hours, how ugly and consumeristic this part of the Internet is and since then had not tried logging in again until last night.</description></item><item><title>Java</title><link>techglider.in/post/2016/01/02/java/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2016 22:51:18 -0500</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2016/01/02/java/</guid><description>I don&amp;rsquo;t really recall why I avoided Java all this while.
Few weeks after arriving here at Brown, I learnt Brown is, what they call, a Java school. That&amp;rsquo;s probably not completely true, but for a vast majority of students that take Andy&amp;rsquo;s intro class, CS15, it is. I have come to realize it is not such a bad thing (quite the opposite).
I remember my first few weeks at college when I was trying to teach myself Java in the CC (whoa, they have a website now!</description></item><item><title>Relearning Computer Science</title><link>techglider.in/post/2015/10/28/relearning-computer-science/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2015 11:35:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2015/10/28/relearning-computer-science/</guid><description>Awakening I was awaken from a long sleep of ignorance with some events that occurred in the last couple of weeks. A sudden surge of conscientiousness about taking my education in my hands was one of the immediate results.
The inflection point was getting to hear Bryan Cantrill in person and interviewing with him the next day. I didn’t do my best, but was humbled by Cantrill into realizing how much I had to learn.</description></item><item><title>Exploring Medium</title><link>techglider.in/post/2015/06/29/exploring-medium/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2015 15:41:42 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2015/06/29/exploring-medium/</guid><description>I am considering writing more often, more personal posts on Medium at https://medium.com/@k4rtik. Here&amp;rsquo;s first one among them:</description></item><item><title>15 Commitments of Conscious Leadership</title><link>techglider.in/quote/2014/11/30/15-commitments-of-conscious-leadership/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2014 12:37:31 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/quote/2014/11/30/15-commitments-of-conscious-leadership/</guid><description>Read as &amp;lsquo;commitment&amp;rsquo; and then a &amp;lsquo;counter-commitment&amp;rsquo; for each point.
I commit to taking full responsibility for the circumstances of my life, and my physical, emotional, mental and spiritual wellbeing. I commit to support others to take full responsibility for their lives.
I commit to blaming others and myself for what is wrong in the world. I commit to being a victim, villain, or a hero and taking more or less than 100% responsibility.</description></item><item><title>Swaraj by Arvind Kejriwal - A Review</title><link>techglider.in/post/2014/03/20/swaraj-by-arvind-kejriwal-a-review/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2014 17:53:41 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2014/03/20/swaraj-by-arvind-kejriwal-a-review/</guid><description>Swaraj by Arvind Kejriwal
My rating: 4 of 5 stars
Ended up reading a Hindi book after many years, &amp;lsquo;कथेतर&amp;rsquo; (non-fiction, new word learnt!) on that.
Little Background I haven&amp;rsquo;t followed Kejriwal&amp;rsquo;s or Anna&amp;rsquo;s movement from the beginning. I first gave serious attention when AAP managed to win a substantial number of seats in Delhi last December. Since then, I have come to admire Kejriwal&amp;rsquo;s clarity of thought, his ideas and his mission, all of which can be ascertained in any of his recent interviews or QA&amp;rsquo;s with audience where neither the interviewer nor the public leave any stone unturned to grill him.</description></item><item><title>Week 1 at Bangalore and Work</title><link>techglider.in/post/2013/07/21/week-1-at-bangalore-and-work/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2013 14:53:31 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2013/07/21/week-1-at-bangalore-and-work/</guid><description>I landed at Bangalore airport last week flying on an indiGo for the first time; found the experience better than JetKonnect from my first flight.
Next day (Sunday) started early with a walk to Oracle Tech Park and back to get myself familiarized with the area before first day at work. A much-needed haircut followed.
Having caught cold with the change in weather, I had to miss the Goodreads meetup planned at Brigade Road during the day, which I was eagerly awaiting to attend with a friend.</description></item><item><title>Nothing in the world can take the place...</title><link>techglider.in/quote/2013/05/14/nothing-in-the-world-can-take-the-place/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2013 00:32:04 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/quote/2013/05/14/nothing-in-the-world-can-take-the-place/</guid><description>Nothing in the world can take the place of persistence. Talent will not; nothing is more common than unsuccessful men with talent. Genius will not; unrewarded genius is almost a proverb. Education will not; the world is full of educated derelicts. Persistence and determination alone are omnipotent. The slogan Press On! has solved and always will solve the problems of the human race.
&amp;mdash;Calvin Coolidge (Discovered this as my MITian friend Ankur&amp;rsquo;s gmail chat status)</description></item><item><title>Found the culprit for a long standing problem...</title><link>techglider.in/status/2013/04/19/found-the-culprit-for-a-long-standing-problem/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2013 14:39:46 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/status/2013/04/19/found-the-culprit-for-a-long-standing-problem/</guid><description>Found the culprit for a long standing problem with Linux install disk booting on my Dell Studio XPS 1645 today at http://forums.linuxmint.com/viewtopic.php?f=46&amp;amp;t=126993#p692786 - it was my wireless card. Was facing this problem at least since last October when I tried to install latest editions of Fedora and ArchLinux but couldn&amp;rsquo;t. On Linux Mint 14 Cinnamon now.</description></item><item><title>Of FOSSMeets at NIT Calicut</title><link>techglider.in/post/2013/04/14/of-fossmeets-at-nit-calicut/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 08:33:41 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2013/04/14/of-fossmeets-at-nit-calicut/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been over a month and a half since the last edition of FOSSMeet at NIT Calicut. As an active member of organizing team for FOSSMeets &amp;lsquo;10 and &amp;lsquo;11 and a keen but silent observer for the 2013 edition, I want to share some history, some ideas &amp;amp; few observations with this post. The intent is to generate discussion among people who have been part of earlier FOSSMeets and to leave some things to ponder about (and act on) for juniors.</description></item><item><title>Musing over The Challenge</title><link>techglider.in/post/2013/02/11/musing-over-the-challenge/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2013 07:28:32 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2013/02/11/musing-over-the-challenge/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been 10 days since I started this challenge. Up to now, I seem to be failing in living up to the daily requirement in the Fibonacci order (0, 1, 1, 2 - the day gaps); of course, I don&amp;rsquo;t want the sequence to continue.
In retrospect, I can see what stopped me in the days I missed - once it was just a tiring day, someday it was work/extended meeting, some day just plain lack of creativity.</description></item><item><title>Even after giving enough time to that someone...</title><link>techglider.in/status/2013/02/08/even-after-giving-enough-time-to-that-someone/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2013 17:50:21 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/status/2013/02/08/even-after-giving-enough-time-to-that-someone/</guid><description>Even after giving enough time to that someone you are pissed off with, you can&amp;rsquo;t always expect to be impressed. Perhaps Randy was wrong. I held this view for a very long time; but time has taken such a turn in last few months that I am only left wondering what Randy exactly meant by enough time.</description></item><item><title>28 Days Challenge</title><link>techglider.in/post/2013/02/01/28-days-challenge/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 16:30:02 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2013/02/01/28-days-challenge/</guid><description>Inspired long back by Oliver Emberton&amp;rsquo;s herculian 30 Day Challenger, I have decided to try it out for myself this month. Feb being the smallest month should serve as the easiest possible start. ;-)
The motivation for doing this are similar - stretching myself to give up on a bad habit, get the most out of my day, or being more productive in general.
Given that I have a lot to say, things that keep on forming virtual blog posts in my mind - some of which are technical, some about my dream college, some advice for juniors, some worldly pondering, some internal struggles - I have decided on my first challenge:</description></item><item><title>Ponderings of the Year Past: Part 2</title><link>techglider.in/post/2012/03/26/ponderings-of-the-year-past-part-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2012 21:03:03 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2012/03/26/ponderings-of-the-year-past-part-2/</guid><description>The following are few important lessons I learnt over the gone year – 2011 (see Part 1 here):
Friends To be very frank (and you can call me weird), I didn&amp;rsquo;t know the meaning of a close friend until about early 2011. As far as I remember, until first semester, definition of a friend for me was somebody who shared similar interests, mutual respect, and trust. I remember objecting to Rama to call him names (in return of his such various favors) by saying &amp;ldquo;dude, I respect you!</description></item><item><title>Ponderings of the Year Past: Part 1</title><link>techglider.in/post/2012/03/26/ponderings-of-the-year-past-part-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2012 19:59:28 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2012/03/26/ponderings-of-the-year-past-part-1/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been long since I wrote something. To be frank, it was last July in which I actually spoke out my mind. Of course, I wished to write a lot more (who doesn&amp;rsquo;t). This one is going to be long, so I decided to partition it.
The following are few important lessons I learnt over the gone year - 2011:
Computer Science != Computer Engineering Vineeth Sir always calls it Computing Science, we even had a discussion over it, perhaps over a year back( and once again recently); the doubt got cleared up only after I looked up ACM&amp;rsquo;s Computing Curricula Recommendations which defines five sub-disciplines of computing: Computer Science, Computer Engineering, Information Systems, Information Technology, and Software Engineering (they have pretty decent comparisons among these disciplines using pictures and charts).</description></item><item><title>Of Corruption, India, and My First Bribe</title><link>techglider.in/post/2011/07/15/of-corruption-india-and-my-first-bribe/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2011 12:50:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2011/07/15/of-corruption-india-and-my-first-bribe/</guid><description>It was this Monday when I visited Rath mam with my friend Arvis. Rath mam had just returned from US after visiting both her children who are well settled in US working in IT companies. Somehow that day our discussion went on to what me and Arvis plan to do in the future after college. Mam was telling us why we should think about moving outside India for higher studies. She stated three important reasons why India is not yet the best place to lead life for those with some moral support system:</description></item><item><title>Disconnect - An Experiment</title><link>techglider.in/post/2011/07/10/disconnect-an-experiment/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2011 18:37:01 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2011/07/10/disconnect-an-experiment/</guid><description>This will be short.
A small announcement: I will be out of touch for about a week on the Internet. Disconnected on all social networks (including twitter) and off-line on chats (including GMail chat) and unavailable on SMS. I have already disabled all email and SMS notifications from the social networks. This is just for the sake of experimenting to see if I can still live without social media, so don&amp;rsquo;t get weird ideas about this.</description></item><item><title>Good Bye TechGlider Forums, Ta-Ta NITC Wiki</title><link>techglider.in/post/2011/07/10/good-bye-techglider-forums-ta-ta-nitc-wiki/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2011 17:37:37 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2011/07/10/good-bye-techglider-forums-ta-ta-nitc-wiki/</guid><description>Today I bid adieu to The TechGlider Forums which used to reside at http://techglider.in/forums Started in August of 2008, it was my attempt to build a tech support community around my friends and visitors of my website - TechGlider.in. This decision comes at a time when I have realized it&amp;rsquo;s no longer a good idea to build a community like this on phpBB, with the advent of platforms like facebook and twitter (and Google+ more recently) and their penetrations in our lives.</description></item><item><title>7 Commandments of the Personal Computer Revolution</title><link>techglider.in/quote/2011/04/22/7-commandments-of-the-personal-computer-revolution/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2011 13:11:08 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/quote/2011/04/22/7-commandments-of-the-personal-computer-revolution/</guid><description>7 Commandments of the Personal Computer Revolution:
Access to Computers - and anything that might teach you something about the way the world works - should be unlimited and total. Always yield to the Hands-on Imperative. All information should be free. Mistrust authority - promote decentralization. Hackers should be judged by their hacking, not bogus criteria such as degrees, age, race,or position. You can create art and beauty on a computer.</description></item><item><title>The Story of the TechGlider</title><link>techglider.in/post/2011/03/26/the-story-of-the-techglider/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2011 05:41:22 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2011/03/26/the-story-of-the-techglider/</guid><description>Hi all, In this post I will be sharing some interesting points that fell along during realization of my idea of the TechGlider.First of all I am sharing some initial hand-drawn logos for the site. These were shared with my friend Arvis on June 28, 2009 for his comments.
The following was the outcome of earlier designs on July 5, 2009:
The following is a screenshot of StudenTech.</description></item><item><title>Done messing up enough with the looks of...</title><link>techglider.in/status/2011/03/13/done-messing-up-enough-with-the-looks-of/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2011 17:33:55 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/status/2011/03/13/done-messing-up-enough-with-the-looks-of/</guid><description>Done messing up enough with the looks of my old blog for the day. Have exams this week and haven&amp;rsquo;t studied a thing. Need to take a week&amp;rsquo;s break from the net. ;)
On another note: I have restored my website: TechGlider.in during this Ragam. Do take a look at &amp;hellip;and, we&amp;rsquo;re back!.</description></item><item><title>...and, we're back!</title><link>techglider.in/post/2011/03/13/and-we-are-back/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2011 07:43:51 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2011/03/13/and-we-are-back/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been so long - missing the TechGlider - my dream, my hard work of over 2 years was gone. Started in July 2008, gone in July 2010. :(
The reason of this long absence: I lost the ownership of the domain techglider.com - partly because of my own carelessness, and partly because of my webhost Four &amp;lsquo;S&amp;rsquo; Tech&amp;rsquo;s troubles. In the process, I did learn a few interesting things like the concept of drop catching, how the companies like GoDaddy make so much money; and more importantly how not to lose my domain again.</description></item><item><title>Really Achieving Your Childhood Dreams - The Last Lecture</title><link>techglider.in/post/2011/03/09/really-achieving-your-childhood-dreams-the-last-lecture/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2011 19:01:21 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2011/03/09/really-achieving-your-childhood-dreams-the-last-lecture/</guid><description>I finally got a chance to watch this wonderful talk (by Randy Pausch) popularly known as The Last Lecture. I wanted to watch this for a long time - since Anjhan mentioned about it in his keynote at foss.in and since Prateek Kalyankar had recommended this to me in Jan.
A really nice watch for anyone who has ever dreamed and thought of fulfilling them. I was particularly amazed to see a youthful, energetic, handsome Randy deliver that talk in such a cheerful, darkly funny way, while being just a few months away from his death (and knowing it!</description></item><item><title>And I successfully pulled out two consecutive all...</title><link>techglider.in/status/2011/03/06/and-i-successfully-pulled-out-two-consecutive-all/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2011 00:22:25 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/status/2011/03/06/and-i-successfully-pulled-out-two-consecutive-all/</guid><description>And I successfully pulled out two consecutive all-nighters - a first time in my life! For the record: my first all nighter in college was just in last sem (during which Jaseem had to kick me 2-3 times to keep me awake).
And these two were spent properly working on something I love and without facing any loss in productivity during the day. Congrats to myself!</description></item><item><title>The Branch Tour 2011 and me (Part 2)</title><link>techglider.in/post/2011/03/01/the-branch-tour-2011-and-me-part-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 02:30:42 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2011/03/01/the-branch-tour-2011-and-me-part-2/</guid><description>This is second and the last part of my earlier post - The Branch Tour 2011 and me. Please read my last post before reading this.
Disclaimer: The following post is dedicated to all my branch mates and is a little more on the personal side. Additionally, the post is too long and may not be of any relevance for those who seek to attain any bit of technical nirvana from this blog.</description></item><item><title>Building a Modern Computer in 12 Steps - A Perfect Elective Course for Sem 3 of CSE</title><link>techglider.in/post/2011/02/28/building-a-modern-computer-in-12-steps-a-perfect-elective-course-for-sem-3-of-cse/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2011 17:01:40 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2011/02/28/building-a-modern-computer-in-12-steps-a-perfect-elective-course-for-sem-3-of-cse/</guid><description>Just watched this Google Tech Talk on From Nand to Tetris in 12 steps by Shimon Schocken introducing a course he developed along with Noam Nisan:
A must watch for all CS faculty of hardware, algorithms and systems.
The course covers 12 projects to be done over a single semester covering building everything from basic logic gates to computer architecture, and from machine language to an operating system starting from a False and a NAND using a custom HDL.</description></item><item><title>The Branch Tour 2011 and me (Part 1)</title><link>techglider.in/post/2011/02/28/the-branch-tour-2011-and-me-part-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2011 02:30:13 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2011/02/28/the-branch-tour-2011-and-me-part-1/</guid><description>Disclaimer: The following post is dedicated to all my branch mates and is a little more on the personal side. Additionally, the post is too long and may not be of any relevance for those who seek to attain any bit of technical nirvana from this blog. So, you may happily TLDR this post.
Many have asked me why I decided to go for branch tour when almost none of the northies were ready to go.</description></item><item><title>The reason why I recently shifted to thi...</title><link>techglider.in/status/2010/12/25/the-reason-why-i-recently-shifted-to-thi/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Dec 2010 02:47:21 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/status/2010/12/25/the-reason-why-i-recently-shifted-to-thi/</guid><description>The reason why I recently shifted to this blog is detailed at http://kartikscribbles.posterous.com/one-last-post-on-my-posterous</description></item><item><title>FOSS.IN just got over. And it was the la...</title><link>techglider.in/status/2010/12/18/foss-in-just-got-over-and-it-was-the-la/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2010 11:23:23 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/status/2010/12/18/foss-in-just-got-over-and-it-was-the-la/</guid><description>FOSS.IN just got over. And it was the last one ever. I am so grateful to Praveen because of whom I made up my mind to attend it. I badly needed a change in my thinking process which this foss.in has succeeded in bringing. This new blog is one step of the impact of the change.</description></item><item><title>The TechGlider Blog is back</title><link>techglider.in/post/2009/10/03/the-techglider-blog-is-back/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2009 09:11:09 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2009/10/03/the-techglider-blog-is-back/</guid><description>I am really happy to announce that I have been able to restore the TGB successfully (after fiddling with the backups for almost a month). This period of two and a half months without my blog was really unbearable for me; the only thing that helped me bear this pain was what was happening in my real life. A lot of wonderful events have changed my life (e.g. I have taken admission in BTech CSE at NIT Calicut).</description></item><item><title>Welcome to the All New TechGlider Blog</title><link>techglider.in/post/2008/10/06/welcome-to-the-all-new-techglider-blog/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2008 23:46:23 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2008/10/06/welcome-to-the-all-new-techglider-blog/</guid><description>This is my first post on WordPress and through this I welcome you to the all new TechGlider Blog.
I am finally finished with moving the TGB to WordPress. WordPress offers a plethora of plugins to customize one&amp;rsquo;s blog and I am trying to choose what are those that I need for the TGB. As pointed out in my last post, this change hasn&amp;rsquo;t been easy. I almost lost all of my previous posts for there was no efficient way to import the posts from my b2evolution installation to WordPress, so I had to do it manually and took a whole day for that (these type of repetitive works are really a pain in the neck for me).</description></item><item><title>How to become a Hacker?</title><link>techglider.in/post/2008/10/05/how-to-become-a-hacker/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2008 08:21:49 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2008/10/05/how-to-become-a-hacker/</guid><description>A lot of people ask me &amp;ldquo;how can I become a hacker&amp;rdquo;?
I ask them to differentiate between a hacker and a cracker first and specify what do they actually want to become. If the answer is a hacker, I need to direct them to this page (perhaps the best page on the net for a guide to becoming a hacker): http://www.catb.org/~esr/faqs/hacker-howto.html
For crackers-to-be I don&amp;rsquo;t have very-healthy feelings and ask them to correct their mindsets.</description></item></channel></rss>