<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Home on The TechGlider</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/tags/home/</link><description>Recent content in Home on The TechGlider</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2013 18:25:07 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/tags/home/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>My First and Last 3D SketchUp</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2013/02/02/my-first-and-last-3d-sketchup/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2013 18:25:07 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2013/02/02/my-first-and-last-3d-sketchup/</guid><description>So, here is the first one.
[gallery type=&amp;ldquo;slideshow&amp;rdquo; ids=&amp;ldquo;512,513,514,515,516&amp;rdquo;]
I had created this long back in Decemeber of 2006. The file cab.skp (Google SketchUp file) was lying in my system since ages. Tried opening it today, discovered there is no Linux support for its viewer/editor (you listening Google?). After some fiddling with Wine and finally resorting to spend some time on a friend&amp;rsquo;s Windows Laptop, here we are. Quite a piece of art, ain&amp;rsquo;t it?</description></item><item><title>Of Corruption, India, and My First Bribe</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2011/07/15/of-corruption-india-and-my-first-bribe/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2011 12:50:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2011/07/15/of-corruption-india-and-my-first-bribe/</guid><description>It was this Monday when I visited Rath mam with my friend Arvis. Rath mam had just returned from US after visiting both her children who are well settled in US working in IT companies. Somehow that day our discussion went on to what me and Arvis plan to do in the future after college. Mam was telling us why we should think about moving outside India for higher studies. She stated three important reasons why India is not yet the best place to lead life for those with some moral support system:</description></item><item><title>The Great Indian Jugaad</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2011/05/30/the-great-indian-jugaad/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2011 15:08:26 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2011/05/30/the-great-indian-jugaad/</guid><description>Just spotted this unique and innovative use of cheap UPS batteries in the local vegetable market (sabzi mandi) near my home at Ghaziabad. I could see dozens of these lamps in a row in the market. At a place like ours with such severe power cuts, this seems like a good alternative for the vegetable vendors.</description></item></channel></rss>