<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>science on The TechGlider</title><link>https://techglider.in/tags/science/</link><description>Recent content in science on The TechGlider</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2013 18:52:40 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://techglider.in/tags/science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Logicomix: An Epic Search for Truth</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2013/02/03/logicomix-an-epic-search-for-truth/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2013 18:52:40 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2013/02/03/logicomix-an-epic-search-for-truth/</guid><description>This one needs to be quick, 14 minutes until midnight.
Logicomix (Photo credit: Wikipedia)
In this post I want to introduce a graphic novel which I read about a year back - Logicomix: An Epic Search for Truth.
How I ended up reading this is an interesting story in itself. Let me try to recite in minimum possible words. During that time (Sem 6) I had enrolled for a course called Computational Complexity by Murali sir.</description></item><item><title>Ponderings of the Year Past: Part 1</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2012/03/26/ponderings-of-the-year-past-part-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2012 19:59:28 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2012/03/26/ponderings-of-the-year-past-part-1/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been long since I wrote something. To be frank, it was last July in which I actually spoke out my mind. Of course, I wished to write a lot more (who doesn&amp;rsquo;t). This one is going to be long, so I decided to partition it.
The following are few important lessons I learnt over the gone year - 2011:
Computer Science != Computer Engineering Vineeth Sir always calls it Computing Science, we even had a discussion over it, perhaps over a year back( and once again recently); the doubt got cleared up only after I looked up ACM&amp;rsquo;s Computing Curricula Recommendations which defines five sub-disciplines of computing: Computer Science, Computer Engineering, Information Systems, Information Technology, and Software Engineering (they have pretty decent comparisons among these disciplines using pictures and charts).</description></item><item><title>The Next Generation of Makers</title><link>https://techglider.in/quote/2011/04/08/the-next-generation-of-makers-2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2011 09:49:41 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/quote/2011/04/08/the-next-generation-of-makers-2/</guid><description>I know the future is what I make it.
I believe I can make the world better.
I understand I need knowledge and passion.
I choose to participate, not observe.
I work with my hands and my mind.
I pursue beauty in what I produce.
I see art in science and science in art.
I value skills.
I am the next generation of Maker!
&amp;mdash;Source: http://www.</description></item><item><title>Really Achieving Your Childhood Dreams - The Last Lecture</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2011/03/09/really-achieving-your-childhood-dreams-the-last-lecture/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2011 19:01:21 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2011/03/09/really-achieving-your-childhood-dreams-the-last-lecture/</guid><description>I finally got a chance to watch this wonderful talk (by Randy Pausch) popularly known as The Last Lecture. I wanted to watch this for a long time - since Anjhan mentioned about it in his keynote at foss.in and since Prateek Kalyankar had recommended this to me in Jan.
A really nice watch for anyone who has ever dreamed and thought of fulfilling them. I was particularly amazed to see a youthful, energetic, handsome Randy deliver that talk in such a cheerful, darkly funny way, while being just a few months away from his death (and knowing it!</description></item><item><title>Building a Modern Computer in 12 Steps - A Perfect Elective Course for Sem 3 of CSE</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2011/02/28/building-a-modern-computer-in-12-steps-a-perfect-elective-course-for-sem-3-of-cse/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2011 17:01:40 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2011/02/28/building-a-modern-computer-in-12-steps-a-perfect-elective-course-for-sem-3-of-cse/</guid><description>Just watched this Google Tech Talk on From Nand to Tetris in 12 steps by Shimon Schocken introducing a course he developed along with Noam Nisan:
A must watch for all CS faculty of hardware, algorithms and systems.
The course covers 12 projects to be done over a single semester covering building everything from basic logic gates to computer architecture, and from machine language to an operating system starting from a False and a NAND using a custom HDL.</description></item><item><title>Just finished reading Oral history inter...</title><link>https://techglider.in/status/2011/01/22/just-finished-reading-oral-history-inter/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2011 13:15:50 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/status/2011/01/22/just-finished-reading-oral-history-inter/</guid><description>Just finished reading Oral history interview with Edsger W. Dijkstra (transcript availabe on that link). This was suggested by Subhashree mam in our first lecture of Discrete Computational Structures course with her. An interesting read about Dijkstra&amp;rsquo;s life and history of the establishment of computing science as a discipline.</description></item><item><title>The Pleasure of Finding Things Out</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2011/01/05/the-pleasure-of-finding-things-out/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2011 20:25:41 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2011/01/05/the-pleasure-of-finding-things-out/</guid><description>Just watched this video whose link I got from Anjhan&amp;rsquo;s blog, an interview of Richard Feynman. I started out to watch only the first 10 minutes but really couldn&amp;rsquo;t stop myself to watch the whole thing (although I have to attend class at 8 AM). Must watch for the curious thinker, the scientist, the hacker.</description></item><item><title>List of Books Read So Far</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2008/09/08/list-of-books-read-so-far/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2008 01:50:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2008/09/08/list-of-books-read-so-far/</guid><description>This is a list of books I used to maintain at The TechGlider Forums, imported here for keeping it updated.
Here I list the books I have read (only those whose names I remember) so far (in finishing order):
Harry Potter and the Philosopher&amp;rsquo;s Stone, by J K Rowling
Harry Potter and the Chamber of Secrets, by J K Rowling
Harry Potter and the Prisoner of Azkaban, by J K Rowling</description></item></channel></rss>