<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>techglider.in on The TechGlider</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/tags/techglider.in/</link><description>Recent content in techglider.in on The TechGlider</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2011 17:37:37 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/tags/techglider.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Good Bye TechGlider Forums, Ta-Ta NITC Wiki</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2011/07/10/good-bye-techglider-forums-ta-ta-nitc-wiki/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2011 17:37:37 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2011/07/10/good-bye-techglider-forums-ta-ta-nitc-wiki/</guid><description>Today I bid adieu to The TechGlider Forums which used to reside at http://techglider.in/forums Started in August of 2008, it was my attempt to build a tech support community around my friends and visitors of my website - TechGlider.in. This decision comes at a time when I have realized it&amp;rsquo;s no longer a good idea to build a community like this on phpBB, with the advent of platforms like facebook and twitter (and Google+ more recently) and their penetrations in our lives.</description></item><item><title>The Story of the TechGlider</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2011/03/26/the-story-of-the-techglider/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2011 05:41:22 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2011/03/26/the-story-of-the-techglider/</guid><description>Hi all, In this post I will be sharing some interesting points that fell along during realization of my idea of the TechGlider.First of all I am sharing some initial hand-drawn logos for the site. These were shared with my friend Arvis on June 28, 2009 for his comments.
The following was the outcome of earlier designs on July 5, 2009:
The following is a screenshot of StudenTech.</description></item><item><title>...and, we're back!</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2011/03/13/and-we-are-back/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2011 07:43:51 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2011/03/13/and-we-are-back/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been so long - missing the TechGlider - my dream, my hard work of over 2 years was gone. Started in July 2008, gone in July 2010. :(
The reason of this long absence: I lost the ownership of the domain techglider.com - partly because of my own carelessness, and partly because of my webhost Four &amp;lsquo;S&amp;rsquo; Tech&amp;rsquo;s troubles. In the process, I did learn a few interesting things like the concept of drop catching, how the companies like GoDaddy make so much money; and more importantly how not to lose my domain again.</description></item><item><title>Test version of main TechGlider.com site is out!</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2008/08/06/test-version-of-main-techglidercom-site-is-out/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2008 16:35:47 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2008/08/06/test-version-of-main-techglidercom-site-is-out/</guid><description>I am pleased to inform you all that I have finally uploaded a test version of the main TechGlider.com site. :-)
As I have mentioned that it&amp;rsquo;s a test version, a lot of download links and the forums link are not working and I am very sorry for that. The main purpose of the test site is to showcase the main design and structure of the future TechGlider site.
You can view the site by clicking on the &amp;ldquo;Visit the main TechGlider site&amp;rdquo; link at the above navigation bar.</description></item></channel></rss>