<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>curiosity on The TechGlider</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/tags/curiosity/</link><description>Recent content in curiosity on The TechGlider</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2015 07:13:09 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/tags/curiosity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Learn</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/quote/2015/03/05/live-as-if-you-were-to-die-tomorrow-learn/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2015 07:13:09 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/quote/2015/03/05/live-as-if-you-were-to-die-tomorrow-learn/</guid><description>Live as if you were to die tomorrow. Learn as if you were to live forever.
&amp;mdash;Mahatma Gandhi, Goodreads citation (did not find any authoritative source of this quote)
This used to be my motto for a long time before college, cannot recall when this disappeared from my active conscience. Caught my eye when Prof. Adam Porter quoted this in the announcement email for week 7 of his Coursera class on Programming Mobile Applications for Android Handheld Systems.</description></item><item><title>15 Commitments of Conscious Leadership</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/quote/2014/11/30/15-commitments-of-conscious-leadership/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2014 12:37:31 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/quote/2014/11/30/15-commitments-of-conscious-leadership/</guid><description>Read as &amp;lsquo;commitment&amp;rsquo; and then a &amp;lsquo;counter-commitment&amp;rsquo; for each point.
I commit to taking full responsibility for the circumstances of my life, and my physical, emotional, mental and spiritual wellbeing. I commit to support others to take full responsibility for their lives.
I commit to blaming others and myself for what is wrong in the world. I commit to being a victim, villain, or a hero and taking more or less than 100% responsibility.</description></item><item><title>It feels so relieving to get your lost...</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/status/2013/04/20/it-feels-so-relieving-to-get-your-lost/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2013 12:16:13 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/status/2013/04/20/it-feels-so-relieving-to-get-your-lost/</guid><description>It feels so relieving to get your lost data back!
After trying multiple file recovery tools like TestDisk/PhotoRec, Recuva, etc. I had ran chkdsk (of course, from Windows) as a last resort on that particular partition last night. Since, Windows doesn&amp;rsquo;t show protected system files easily I couldn&amp;rsquo;t see the content of found.000 directory that got created in the said partition. I made a mental note of checking this directory out later from Linux.</description></item><item><title>Another strange thing and a big lesson learned...</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/status/2013/04/19/another-strange-thing-and-a-big-lesson-learned/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2013 14:55:02 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/status/2013/04/19/another-strange-thing-and-a-big-lesson-learned/</guid><description>Another strange thing and a big lesson learned today was regarding disk handling by Windows and Linux. I had been observing missing files from my hard disk for a few weeks now, always suspected it was due to bad sectors but tests didn&amp;rsquo;t turn up anything positive. When I took the backup of my old Ubuntu home directory to an NTFS partition, installed Linux Mint and then tried to access the backup I was left with a shock - the whole backup was gone!</description></item><item><title>Logicomix: An Epic Search for Truth</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2013/02/03/logicomix-an-epic-search-for-truth/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2013 18:52:40 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2013/02/03/logicomix-an-epic-search-for-truth/</guid><description>This one needs to be quick, 14 minutes until midnight.
Logicomix (Photo credit: Wikipedia)
In this post I want to introduce a graphic novel which I read about a year back - Logicomix: An Epic Search for Truth.
How I ended up reading this is an interesting story in itself. Let me try to recite in minimum possible words. During that time (Sem 6) I had enrolled for a course called Computational Complexity by Murali sir.</description></item><item><title>A Fun Security Weekend with null and sCTF</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2012/06/22/a-fun-security-weekend-with-null-and-sctf/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2012 19:39:05 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2012/06/22/a-fun-security-weekend-with-null-and-sctf/</guid><description>I know it&amp;rsquo;s quite late to post about the last weekend when another weekend is around the corner, but couldn&amp;rsquo;t control myself as the last one was so eventful. :)
It was almost 2 weeks back that I got to know about sCTF 2012. I have always wanted to learn about computer security (and the darker side of hacking), but haven&amp;rsquo;t been able to give time it to it. What followed was a quick search for team members from among my batch via FB - Nithin immediately showed interest, we pulled Jerrin in too.</description></item><item><title>(Bangalore) Summer of '12... with BeagleBone</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2012/06/13/bangalore-summer-of-12-with-beaglebone/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2012 16:42:13 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2012/06/13/bangalore-summer-of-12-with-beaglebone/</guid><description>This post will be slightly long. Lots of exciting things happening over a Bangalore summer this year for me. :D
Somehow I always wanted to learn more about hardware and with a mentor like Khasim the road seems a lot more exciting. I first met him when he came to conduct a workshop on BeagleBoard during Tathva 2009 at my college - NIT Calicut. I was just a fresher then and have since regretted that I could not attend that workshop completely (due to my participation in various CS related competitions).</description></item><item><title>Ponderings of the Year Past: Part 2</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2012/03/26/ponderings-of-the-year-past-part-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2012 21:03:03 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2012/03/26/ponderings-of-the-year-past-part-2/</guid><description>The following are few important lessons I learnt over the gone year – 2011 (see Part 1 here):
Friends To be very frank (and you can call me weird), I didn&amp;rsquo;t know the meaning of a close friend until about early 2011. As far as I remember, until first semester, definition of a friend for me was somebody who shared similar interests, mutual respect, and trust. I remember objecting to Rama to call him names (in return of his such various favors) by saying &amp;ldquo;dude, I respect you!</description></item><item><title>Ponderings of the Year Past: Part 1</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2012/03/26/ponderings-of-the-year-past-part-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2012 19:59:28 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2012/03/26/ponderings-of-the-year-past-part-1/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been long since I wrote something. To be frank, it was last July in which I actually spoke out my mind. Of course, I wished to write a lot more (who doesn&amp;rsquo;t). This one is going to be long, so I decided to partition it.
The following are few important lessons I learnt over the gone year - 2011:
Computer Science != Computer Engineering Vineeth Sir always calls it Computing Science, we even had a discussion over it, perhaps over a year back( and once again recently); the doubt got cleared up only after I looked up ACM&amp;rsquo;s Computing Curricula Recommendations which defines five sub-disciplines of computing: Computer Science, Computer Engineering, Information Systems, Information Technology, and Software Engineering (they have pretty decent comparisons among these disciplines using pictures and charts).</description></item><item><title>Intension and Extension</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/quote/2012/01/26/intension-and-extension/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2012 06:33:47 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/quote/2012/01/26/intension-and-extension/</guid><description>To give an &amp;ldquo;intensional definition&amp;rdquo; is to define a word or phrase in terms of other words, as a dictionary does. To give an &amp;ldquo;extensional definition&amp;rdquo; is to point to examples, as adults do when teaching children. The preceding sentence gives an intensional definition of &amp;ldquo;extensional definition&amp;rdquo;, which makes it an extensional example of &amp;ldquo;intensional definition&amp;rdquo;.
&amp;mdash;Source: http://lesswrong.com/lw/nh/extensions_and_intensions/</description></item><item><title>The Hacker Attitude</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/quote/2011/03/10/the-hacker-attitude/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2011 09:03:29 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/quote/2011/03/10/the-hacker-attitude/</guid><description>The Hacker Attitude:
The world is full of fascinating problems waiting to be solved. No problem should ever have to be solved twice. Boredom and drudgery are evil. Freedom is good. Attitude is no substitute for competence. &amp;mdash;Eric Steven Raymond at How To Become A Hacker</description></item><item><title>Really Achieving Your Childhood Dreams - The Last Lecture</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2011/03/09/really-achieving-your-childhood-dreams-the-last-lecture/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2011 19:01:21 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2011/03/09/really-achieving-your-childhood-dreams-the-last-lecture/</guid><description>I finally got a chance to watch this wonderful talk (by Randy Pausch) popularly known as The Last Lecture. I wanted to watch this for a long time - since Anjhan mentioned about it in his keynote at foss.in and since Prateek Kalyankar had recommended this to me in Jan.
A really nice watch for anyone who has ever dreamed and thought of fulfilling them. I was particularly amazed to see a youthful, energetic, handsome Randy deliver that talk in such a cheerful, darkly funny way, while being just a few months away from his death (and knowing it!</description></item><item><title>Building a Modern Computer in 12 Steps - A Perfect Elective Course for Sem 3 of CSE</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2011/02/28/building-a-modern-computer-in-12-steps-a-perfect-elective-course-for-sem-3-of-cse/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2011 17:01:40 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2011/02/28/building-a-modern-computer-in-12-steps-a-perfect-elective-course-for-sem-3-of-cse/</guid><description>Just watched this Google Tech Talk on From Nand to Tetris in 12 steps by Shimon Schocken introducing a course he developed along with Noam Nisan:
A must watch for all CS faculty of hardware, algorithms and systems.
The course covers 12 projects to be done over a single semester covering building everything from basic logic gates to computer architecture, and from machine language to an operating system starting from a False and a NAND using a custom HDL.</description></item><item><title>The Pleasure of Finding Things Out</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2011/01/05/the-pleasure-of-finding-things-out/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2011 20:25:41 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2011/01/05/the-pleasure-of-finding-things-out/</guid><description>Just watched this video whose link I got from Anjhan&amp;rsquo;s blog, an interview of Richard Feynman. I started out to watch only the first 10 minutes but really couldn&amp;rsquo;t stop myself to watch the whole thing (although I have to attend class at 8 AM). Must watch for the curious thinker, the scientist, the hacker.</description></item><item><title>List of Books Read So Far</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2008/09/08/list-of-books-read-so-far/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2008 01:50:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2008/09/08/list-of-books-read-so-far/</guid><description>This is a list of books I used to maintain at The TechGlider Forums, imported here for keeping it updated.
Here I list the books I have read (only those whose names I remember) so far (in finishing order):
Harry Potter and the Philosopher&amp;rsquo;s Stone, by J K Rowling
Harry Potter and the Chamber of Secrets, by J K Rowling
Harry Potter and the Prisoner of Azkaban, by J K Rowling</description></item></channel></rss>