<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>blog on The TechGlider</title><link>https://techglider.in/tags/blog/</link><description>Recent content in blog on The TechGlider</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 10:51:01 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://techglider.in/tags/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Things I wish I knew in College</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2016/10/01/things-i-wish-i-knew-in-college/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 10:51:01 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2016/10/01/things-i-wish-i-knew-in-college/</guid><description>Meta About a month ago, I asked the following question to the NIT Calicut CSE student body:
If you could ask only one question to an NITC CSE alumnus with diverse experience in industry, higher studies, and research, what would you?
The most raised concerns were:
How to decide between higher studies and industry as your next career move? What are the limitations of an NITC CSE education and how to succeed in the field despite them?</description></item><item><title>Exploring Medium</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2015/06/29/exploring-medium/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2015 15:41:42 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2015/06/29/exploring-medium/</guid><description>I am considering writing more often, more personal posts on Medium at https://medium.com/@k4rtik. Here&amp;rsquo;s first one among them:</description></item><item><title>On Blogging</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2015/06/28/on-blogging/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2015 23:40:17 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2015/06/28/on-blogging/</guid><description>Something interesting happened this morning which leads to existence of this post.
I had gone to visit a long time friend and mentor Amarjit at his home. It was unusual of him to not welcome me at the door himself. I soon learnt why — Deepak Malani was there!
I know Deepak for about 4–5 years now, mostly from stories told by seniors (of IEEE Glory Days) and from Amarjit himself.</description></item><item><title>Posts from The TechGlider Blog Migrated</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2014/10/27/posts-from-the-techglider-blog-migrated/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2014 01:30:58 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2014/10/27/posts-from-the-techglider-blog-migrated/</guid><description>Just a quick note that I have successfully migrated all posts from the original TechGlider Blog which used to reside at https://techglider.in/kartik/blog couple of years ago.
This completes migration of all my written content. Fixing broken links, images, etc. is the major work that remains.
Aside:
I ended up skimming through much of my old content, feels very childish now; my friends from that time might get a laugh or two reading about memories recorded in here.</description></item><item><title>Musing over The Challenge</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2013/02/11/musing-over-the-challenge/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2013 07:28:32 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2013/02/11/musing-over-the-challenge/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been 10 days since I started this challenge. Up to now, I seem to be failing in living up to the daily requirement in the Fibonacci order (0, 1, 1, 2 - the day gaps); of course, I don&amp;rsquo;t want the sequence to continue.
In retrospect, I can see what stopped me in the days I missed - once it was just a tiring day, someday it was work/extended meeting, some day just plain lack of creativity.</description></item><item><title>Good Bye TechGlider Forums, Ta-Ta NITC Wiki</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2011/07/10/good-bye-techglider-forums-ta-ta-nitc-wiki/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2011 17:37:37 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2011/07/10/good-bye-techglider-forums-ta-ta-nitc-wiki/</guid><description>Today I bid adieu to The TechGlider Forums which used to reside at https://techglider.in/forums Started in August of 2008, it was my attempt to build a tech support community around my friends and visitors of my website - TechGlider.in. This decision comes at a time when I have realized it&amp;rsquo;s no longer a good idea to build a community like this on phpBB, with the advent of platforms like facebook and twitter (and Google+ more recently) and their penetrations in our lives.</description></item><item><title>Done messing up enough with the looks of...</title><link>https://techglider.in/status/2011/03/13/done-messing-up-enough-with-the-looks-of/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2011 17:33:55 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/status/2011/03/13/done-messing-up-enough-with-the-looks-of/</guid><description>Done messing up enough with the looks of my old blog for the day. Have exams this week and haven&amp;rsquo;t studied a thing. Need to take a week&amp;rsquo;s break from the net. ;)
On another note: I have restored my website: TechGlider.in during this Ragam. Do take a look at &amp;hellip;and, we&amp;rsquo;re back!.</description></item><item><title>...and, we're back!</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2011/03/13/and-we-are-back/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2011 07:43:51 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2011/03/13/and-we-are-back/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been so long - missing the TechGlider - my dream, my hard work of over 2 years was gone. Started in July 2008, gone in July 2010. :(
The reason of this long absence: I lost the ownership of the domain techglider.com - partly because of my own carelessness, and partly because of my webhost Four &amp;lsquo;S&amp;rsquo; Tech&amp;rsquo;s troubles. In the process, I did learn a few interesting things like the concept of drop catching, how the companies like GoDaddy make so much money; and more importantly how not to lose my domain again.</description></item><item><title>Wow Just noticed my blog reached over a...</title><link>https://techglider.in/status/2011/02/25/wow-just-noticed-my-blog-reached-over-a/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2011 10:30:32 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/status/2011/02/25/wow-just-noticed-my-blog-reached-over-a/</guid><description>Wow! Just noticed - my blog reached over a 1000 hits. Hope to be a more regular blogger this time.</description></item><item><title>The reason why I recently shifted to thi...</title><link>https://techglider.in/status/2010/12/25/the-reason-why-i-recently-shifted-to-thi/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Dec 2010 02:47:21 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/status/2010/12/25/the-reason-why-i-recently-shifted-to-thi/</guid><description>The reason why I recently shifted to this blog is detailed at http://kartikscribbles.posterous.com/one-last-post-on-my-posterous</description></item><item><title>Missing writing on the blog</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2010/03/27/missing-writing-on-the-blog/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2010 08:50:12 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2010/03/27/missing-writing-on-the-blog/</guid><description>You may have noticed I have written almost nothing after November last year.
The main reason has been some or other problem with my website&amp;rsquo;s hosting server until it was shifted to another one in early Feb. But after this happened it&amp;rsquo;s some strange problem in the campus network that my website is only accessible at certain unexpected times as now. While writing this I am not sure, I will be able to publish this post or not, as the site seems accessible at completely random times and duration.</description></item><item><title>All about TechGlider</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2008/08/01/all-about-techglider/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2008 02:12:02 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2008/08/01/all-about-techglider/</guid><description>So, I am back. (That was a hard and very tiring day, yesterday, so couldn&amp;rsquo;t keep up to my promise of writing this post yesternight, :-( apologies)
TechGlider.com as its name suggests would take you gliding into the world of tech. The main focus would be on free and open source software but that doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean I won&amp;rsquo;t focus on Windows or computer hardware or mobile phones for that matter. In short there would be stuff related to all things tech.</description></item></channel></rss>