<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>fiitjee on The TechGlider</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/tags/fiitjee/</link><description>Recent content in fiitjee on The TechGlider</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2008 17:24:44 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/tags/fiitjee/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Going away from home....</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2008/09/08/going-away-from-home/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2008 17:24:44 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2008/09/08/going-away-from-home/</guid><description>Though not that far away, but it&amp;rsquo;s finally here. I will be living in some other place for the first time ever in my life. I want to admit, if I had not dropped the year, this may have happened more than a month ago (moving into hostel of some great college, I would have taken admission into).
So, what has happened is that due to LARGE commuting time for attending classes at FIITJEE (5 hours commute time for a 4 hour session), I have been forced to take up a room at Delhi and reside there.</description></item><item><title>That hard and tiring day of July 31</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2008/08/05/that-hard-and-tiring-day-of-july-31/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2008 14:22:47 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2008/08/05/that-hard-and-tiring-day-of-july-31/</guid><description>I mentioned about this day in my post of August 1.
I started the day at night by wishing a friend birthday, eventually making her wakeup at midnight. Then, came the inauguration of my website with my first post on The TechGlider Blog at 6 in the morning. This was the easy part of the day.
I reached the Ghaziabad Railway Station at 7:50 to board the train to Tilak Bridge at Delhi, for I use to go to South Delhi to attend FIITJEE classes for IIT-JEE preparation.</description></item></channel></rss>