<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>friends on The TechGlider</title><link>https://techglider.in/tags/friends/</link><description>Recent content in friends on The TechGlider</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2016 21:15:39 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://techglider.in/tags/friends/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>2016: Year (and a half) in Review</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2016/12/31/2016-year-and-a-half-in-review/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2016 21:15:39 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2016/12/31/2016-year-and-a-half-in-review/</guid><description>I wanted to write an EoY Review post last year like I did two years ago but I didn&amp;rsquo;t as I was too busy making sure 2016 was beginning with my most important goal for that year&amp;mdash;overcoming my fear of coding and becoming a better programmer. 2016 has been a great year of personal learning and I want to celebrate its passing by documenting some of that learning and experiences.</description></item><item><title>Friendships</title><link>https://techglider.in/status/2016/05/19/friendships/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2016 17:24:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/status/2016/05/19/friendships/</guid><description>http://waitbutwhy.com/2014/12/10-types-odd-friendships-youre-probably-part.html
So, I needed to get educated about my friendships. This relaxed me a bit.
Note: This is an archived post from my unmaintained Tumblr blog https://k4rtik.tumblr.com</description></item><item><title>Reflections on the Facebook Sannyasa</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2016/04/24/reflections-on-the-facebook-sannyasa/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2016 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2016/04/24/reflections-on-the-facebook-sannyasa/</guid><description>As some of you reading this might be aware I have been away for a while.
I deactivated my Facebook account sometime in the first week of Feb; it has been over 75 days. I did try activating it once after 30 days were over and realized within a couple of hours, how ugly and consumeristic this part of the Internet is and since then had not tried logging in again until last night.</description></item><item><title>Couple of weird things happened today</title><link>https://techglider.in/status/2016/04/22/couple-of-weird-things-happened-today/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2016 05:36:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/status/2016/04/22/couple-of-weird-things-happened-today/</guid><description>Note: This is an archived post from my unmaintained Tumblr blog https://k4rtik.tumblr.com</description></item><item><title>Friends</title><link>https://techglider.in/status/2016/03/28/friends/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2016 00:31:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/status/2016/03/28/friends/</guid><description>Note: This is an archived post from my unmaintained Tumblr blog https://k4rtik.tumblr.com</description></item><item><title>On Blogging</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2015/06/28/on-blogging/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2015 23:40:17 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2015/06/28/on-blogging/</guid><description>Something interesting happened this morning which leads to existence of this post.
I had gone to visit a long time friend and mentor Amarjit at his home. It was unusual of him to not welcome me at the door himself. I soon learnt why — Deepak Malani was there!
I know Deepak for about 4–5 years now, mostly from stories told by seniors (of IEEE Glory Days) and from Amarjit himself.</description></item><item><title>Review of No Place to Hide by Glenn Greenwald</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2015/04/12/review-of-no-place-to-hide-by-glenn-greenwald/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2015 12:37:38 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2015/04/12/review-of-no-place-to-hide-by-glenn-greenwald/</guid><description>No Place to Hide: Edward Snowden, the NSA and the Surveillance State by Glenn Greenwald
My rating: 4 of 5 stars
I had bought this book right away after reading the following tweet from a concerned friend:
It took me another 5 months to actually start reading the book.
Review First two chapters read like a Dan Brown thriller except that you constantly keep reminding yourself that this is not fiction and events leading to the Snowden revelations actually happened this way.</description></item><item><title>2014: Year in Review</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2014/12/31/2014-year-in-review/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 23:59:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2014/12/31/2014-year-in-review/</guid><description>Books If I had to describe what my year was about in just one word, it would be these. I was surrounded by books, all sorts of them, throughout the year. I had set out a goal to read 26 full-length books, ie, one per fortnight over the year. I was following the plan until May, when I rediscoverd my love for comic books with the launch of Amar Chitra Katha Android app and the 12 comic books that came free with it.</description></item><item><title>Review of A 'Psycho' Path</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2014/10/23/review-of-a-psycho-path/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2014 14:38:38 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2014/10/23/review-of-a-psycho-path/</guid><description>A &amp;lsquo;Psycho&amp;rsquo; Path by Haris Ibrahim K. V.
My rating: 3 of 5 stars
A first collection of stories &amp;amp; articles from a budding writer friend. Liked the book overall.
The stories are imaginative and much often leave one thinking near the end. Some articles felt lacking in trying to convey the intended meaning, but others especially void Easy(); and The Magic of Reading were quite well written.
Looking forward to a full length book from the author.</description></item><item><title>Diwali</title><link>https://techglider.in/status/2013/11/03/diwali/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2013 14:35:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/status/2013/11/03/diwali/</guid><description>Note: This is an archived post from my unmaintained Tumblr blog https://k4rtik.tumblr.com</description></item><item><title>Week 1 at Bangalore and Work</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2013/07/21/week-1-at-bangalore-and-work/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2013 14:53:31 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2013/07/21/week-1-at-bangalore-and-work/</guid><description>I landed at Bangalore airport last week flying on an indiGo for the first time; found the experience better than JetKonnect from my first flight.
Next day (Sunday) started early with a walk to Oracle Tech Park and back to get myself familiarized with the area before first day at work. A much-needed haircut followed.
Having caught cold with the change in weather, I had to miss the Goodreads meetup planned at Brigade Road during the day, which I was eagerly awaiting to attend with a friend.</description></item><item><title>Sometimes, those casual group FB chats ...</title><link>https://techglider.in/status/2013/05/30/sometimes-those-casual-group-fb-chats-.../</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2013 18:57:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/status/2013/05/30/sometimes-those-casual-group-fb-chats-.../</guid><description>Note: This is an archived post from my unmaintained Tumblr blog https://k4rtik.tumblr.com</description></item><item><title>Nothing in the world can take the place...</title><link>https://techglider.in/quote/2013/05/14/nothing-in-the-world-can-take-the-place/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2013 00:32:04 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/quote/2013/05/14/nothing-in-the-world-can-take-the-place/</guid><description>Nothing in the world can take the place of persistence. Talent will not; nothing is more common than unsuccessful men with talent. Genius will not; unrewarded genius is almost a proverb. Education will not; the world is full of educated derelicts. Persistence and determination alone are omnipotent. The slogan Press On! has solved and always will solve the problems of the human race.
&amp;mdash;Calvin Coolidge (Discovered this as my MITian friend Ankur&amp;rsquo;s gmail chat status)</description></item><item><title>Of FOSSMeets at NIT Calicut</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2013/04/14/of-fossmeets-at-nit-calicut/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 08:33:41 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2013/04/14/of-fossmeets-at-nit-calicut/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been over a month and a half since the last edition of FOSSMeet at NIT Calicut. As an active member of organizing team for FOSSMeets &amp;lsquo;10 and &amp;lsquo;11 and a keen but silent observer for the 2013 edition, I want to share some history, some ideas &amp;amp; few observations with this post. The intent is to generate discussion among people who have been part of earlier FOSSMeets and to leave some things to ponder about (and act on) for juniors.</description></item><item><title>Having good teachers is important This can make...</title><link>https://techglider.in/quote/2012/08/23/having-good-teachers-is-important-this-can-make-4/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2012 16:28:25 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/quote/2012/08/23/having-good-teachers-is-important-this-can-make-4/</guid><description>Having good teachers is important. This can make or kill your interests. Even Kalam attributes being what he is today to him having great teachers. Unfortunately, this is something which is not under one’s control.
&amp;mdash;me (on a twitter conversation with Delbin about electives, teachers and interest in subjects)</description></item><item><title>Ponderings of the Year Past: Part 2</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2012/03/26/ponderings-of-the-year-past-part-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2012 21:03:03 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2012/03/26/ponderings-of-the-year-past-part-2/</guid><description>The following are few important lessons I learnt over the gone year – 2011 (see Part 1 here):
Friends To be very frank (and you can call me weird), I didn&amp;rsquo;t know the meaning of a close friend until about early 2011. As far as I remember, until first semester, definition of a friend for me was somebody who shared similar interests, mutual respect, and trust. I remember objecting to Rama to call him names (in return of his such various favors) by saying &amp;ldquo;dude, I respect you!</description></item><item><title>Control All Computers in a Lab from a Single System</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2012/02/12/control-all-computers-in-a-lab-from-a-single-system/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2012 03:10:21 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2012/02/12/control-all-computers-in-a-lab-from-a-single-system/</guid><description>Quoting Dhandeep, our super-cool lab-admin:
now , all 70 systems in the lab can be switched on and switched off by single commands from the hostel&amp;hellip;
Yes, that and a lot more is possible in our Software Systems Lab now. How? Read on&amp;hellip;
The Setup We have over 70 systems with Ubuntu 10.04 LTS installed on them. There is an administrative account (let&amp;rsquo;s call it admin for this post) and a guest (limited privilege) account on each.</description></item><item><title>And I successfully pulled out two consecutive all...</title><link>https://techglider.in/status/2011/03/06/and-i-successfully-pulled-out-two-consecutive-all/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2011 00:22:25 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/status/2011/03/06/and-i-successfully-pulled-out-two-consecutive-all/</guid><description>And I successfully pulled out two consecutive all-nighters - a first time in my life! For the record: my first all nighter in college was just in last sem (during which Jaseem had to kick me 2-3 times to keep me awake).
And these two were spent properly working on something I love and without facing any loss in productivity during the day. Congrats to myself!</description></item><item><title>The Branch Tour 2011 and me (Part 2)</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2011/03/01/the-branch-tour-2011-and-me-part-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 02:30:42 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2011/03/01/the-branch-tour-2011-and-me-part-2/</guid><description>This is second and the last part of my earlier post - The Branch Tour 2011 and me. Please read my last post before reading this.
Disclaimer: The following post is dedicated to all my branch mates and is a little more on the personal side. Additionally, the post is too long and may not be of any relevance for those who seek to attain any bit of technical nirvana from this blog.</description></item><item><title>The Branch Tour 2011 and me (Part 1)</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2011/02/28/the-branch-tour-2011-and-me-part-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2011 02:30:13 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2011/02/28/the-branch-tour-2011-and-me-part-1/</guid><description>Disclaimer: The following post is dedicated to all my branch mates and is a little more on the personal side. Additionally, the post is too long and may not be of any relevance for those who seek to attain any bit of technical nirvana from this blog. So, you may happily TLDR this post.
Many have asked me why I decided to go for branch tour when almost none of the northies were ready to go.</description></item><item><title>Something that has stuck with me after A...</title><link>https://techglider.in/status/2010/12/23/something-that-has-stuck-with-me-after-a/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2010 18:30:23 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/status/2010/12/23/something-that-has-stuck-with-me-after-a/</guid><description>Something that has stuck with me after Anjhan&amp;rsquo;s keynote at the last FOSS.IN:
When you are pissed off at somebody, and you&amp;rsquo;re angry at them, you just haven&amp;rsquo;t given them enough time. Just give them a little more time — and they&amp;rsquo;ll almost always impress you.</description></item><item><title>Just noticed 850 friends in my facebook ...</title><link>https://techglider.in/status/2010/12/18/just-noticed-850-friends-in-my-facebook/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2010 11:29:58 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/status/2010/12/18/just-noticed-850-friends-in-my-facebook/</guid><description>Just noticed 850 friends in my facebook account and wondered - How many of these have I met personally or even over a chat? Gotta shorten up this list.</description></item><item><title>Adventure on our first visit to an airport</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2010/03/09/adventure-on-our-first-visit-to-an-airport/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2010 13:09:34 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2010/03/09/adventure-on-our-first-visit-to-an-airport/</guid><description>On Friday, I along with my friend Amit (aka Pandey) went to the Kozhikode airport to receive the guest Mr. Aditya Sengupta of FOSSEE, IIT Bombay. This was our first chance to visit an airport. We went in a taxi provided by IEEE Students Branch of our college. The peculiar thing about the taxi was its name: Taxi Kinglikutty (pardon me if I am messing up the name).
We reached 15 minutes earlier than the scheduled time of arrival and found that the flight was delayed by 20 minutes.</description></item><item><title>Easter egg on Google: New Year 2010 Countdown</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2009/12/31/easter-egg-on-google-new-year-2010-countdown/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2009 10:30:30 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2009/12/31/easter-egg-on-google-new-year-2010-countdown/</guid><description>My friend Amit had just created an account on GMail and logged out after that. Just then, he opened Google and was going to search something when I mentioned I&amp;rsquo;m Feeling Lucky to him. He asked what is that to which I thought of replying by showing him the official explanation by Google, so I clicked on &amp;rsquo;the&amp;rsquo; button without any search string. And voila! It showed this:
After scratching my head for few seconds, it occurred to me that it could be the countdown to welcome the new year 2010.</description></item></channel></rss>