<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>facebook on The TechGlider</title><link>techglider.in/tags/facebook/</link><description>Recent content in facebook on The TechGlider</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2016 06:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="techglider.in/tags/facebook/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Reflections on the Facebook Sannyasa</title><link>techglider.in/post/2016/04/24/reflections-on-the-facebook-sannyasa/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2016 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2016/04/24/reflections-on-the-facebook-sannyasa/</guid><description>As some of you reading this might be aware I have been away for a while.
I deactivated my Facebook account sometime in the first week of Feb; it has been over 75 days. I did try activating it once after 30 days were over and realized within a couple of hours, how ugly and consumeristic this part of the Internet is and since then had not tried logging in again until last night.</description></item><item><title>Sometimes, those casual group FB chats ...</title><link>techglider.in/status/2013/05/30/sometimes-those-casual-group-fb-chats-.../</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2013 18:57:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/status/2013/05/30/sometimes-those-casual-group-fb-chats-.../</guid><description>Note: This is an archived post from my unmaintained Tumblr blog https://k4rtik.tumblr.com</description></item><item><title>One of the creepiest gifts I give to ...</title><link>techglider.in/status/2013/05/28/one-of-the-creepiest-gifts-i-give-to-.../</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2013 03:39:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/status/2013/05/28/one-of-the-creepiest-gifts-i-give-to-.../</guid><description>Note: This is an archived post from my unmaintained Tumblr blog https://k4rtik.tumblr.com</description></item><item><title>Of FOSSMeets at NIT Calicut</title><link>techglider.in/post/2013/04/14/of-fossmeets-at-nit-calicut/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 08:33:41 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2013/04/14/of-fossmeets-at-nit-calicut/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been over a month and a half since the last edition of FOSSMeet at NIT Calicut. As an active member of organizing team for FOSSMeets &amp;lsquo;10 and &amp;lsquo;11 and a keen but silent observer for the 2013 edition, I want to share some history, some ideas &amp;amp; few observations with this post. The intent is to generate discussion among people who have been part of earlier FOSSMeets and to leave some things to ponder about (and act on) for juniors.</description></item><item><title>Ponderings of the Year Past: Part 2</title><link>techglider.in/post/2012/03/26/ponderings-of-the-year-past-part-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2012 21:03:03 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2012/03/26/ponderings-of-the-year-past-part-2/</guid><description>The following are few important lessons I learnt over the gone year – 2011 (see Part 1 here):
Friends To be very frank (and you can call me weird), I didn&amp;rsquo;t know the meaning of a close friend until about early 2011. As far as I remember, until first semester, definition of a friend for me was somebody who shared similar interests, mutual respect, and trust. I remember objecting to Rama to call him names (in return of his such various favors) by saying &amp;ldquo;dude, I respect you!</description></item><item><title>Disconnect - An Experiment</title><link>techglider.in/post/2011/07/10/disconnect-an-experiment/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2011 18:37:01 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2011/07/10/disconnect-an-experiment/</guid><description>This will be short.
A small announcement: I will be out of touch for about a week on the Internet. Disconnected on all social networks (including twitter) and off-line on chats (including GMail chat) and unavailable on SMS. I have already disabled all email and SMS notifications from the social networks. This is just for the sake of experimenting to see if I can still live without social media, so don&amp;rsquo;t get weird ideas about this.</description></item><item><title>Just noticed 850 friends in my facebook ...</title><link>techglider.in/status/2010/12/18/just-noticed-850-friends-in-my-facebook/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2010 11:29:58 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/status/2010/12/18/just-noticed-850-friends-in-my-facebook/</guid><description>Just noticed 850 friends in my facebook account and wondered - How many of these have I met personally or even over a chat? Gotta shorten up this list.</description></item><item><title>Why I use Twitter? And why not Orkut or Facebook?</title><link>techglider.in/post/2009/10/11/why-i-use-twitter-and-why-not-orkut-or-facebook/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2009 16:05:28 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2009/10/11/why-i-use-twitter-and-why-not-orkut-or-facebook/</guid><description>So, it all started in 2006 when I was in class 11. The wave of orkut. I still remember, how I missed all the fun, when during the vacations after class X boards, most of my friends got broadband connections at their homes and started using orkut and became so close with each other and even with girls. I came to know of orkut only when it was too late sometime at the end of August 2006.</description></item></channel></rss>