<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Photos on The TechGlider</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/categories/photos/</link><description>Recent content in Photos on The TechGlider</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2011 17:37:37 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/categories/photos/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Good Bye TechGlider Forums, Ta-Ta NITC Wiki</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2011/07/10/good-bye-techglider-forums-ta-ta-nitc-wiki/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2011 17:37:37 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2011/07/10/good-bye-techglider-forums-ta-ta-nitc-wiki/</guid><description>Today I bid adieu to The TechGlider Forums which used to reside at http://techglider.in/forums Started in August of 2008, it was my attempt to build a tech support community around my friends and visitors of my website - TechGlider.in. This decision comes at a time when I have realized it&amp;rsquo;s no longer a good idea to build a community like this on phpBB, with the advent of platforms like facebook and twitter (and Google+ more recently) and their penetrations in our lives.</description></item><item><title>The Story of the TechGlider</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2011/03/26/the-story-of-the-techglider/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2011 05:41:22 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2011/03/26/the-story-of-the-techglider/</guid><description>Hi all, In this post I will be sharing some interesting points that fell along during realization of my idea of the TechGlider.First of all I am sharing some initial hand-drawn logos for the site. These were shared with my friend Arvis on June 28, 2009 for his comments.
The following was the outcome of earlier designs on July 5, 2009:
The following is a screenshot of StudenTech.</description></item><item><title>The Story of the LAN at A</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2010/07/02/the-story-of-the-lan-at-a/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2010 04:46:38 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2010/07/02/the-story-of-the-lan-at-a/</guid><description>The following post was supposed to be published on Feb 28, 2010. But due to my procrastination and the importance of this I am finally publishing it now after so much time has passed.
So, finally, the much awaited (and the answer to the most asked question to me: Abe, kab aa raha hai&amp;hellip;?) - LAN is here at A Hostel, my hostel at NIT Calicut.
It all started with a challenge I accepted from Aakash to bring the LAN to A Hostel within month of starting of second sem.</description></item><item><title>Adventure on our first visit to an airport</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2010/03/09/adventure-on-our-first-visit-to-an-airport/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2010 13:09:34 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2010/03/09/adventure-on-our-first-visit-to-an-airport/</guid><description>On Friday, I along with my friend Amit (aka Pandey) went to the Kozhikode airport to receive the guest Mr. Aditya Sengupta of FOSSEE, IIT Bombay. This was our first chance to visit an airport. We went in a taxi provided by IEEE Students Branch of our college. The peculiar thing about the taxi was its name: Taxi Kinglikutty (pardon me if I am messing up the name).
We reached 15 minutes earlier than the scheduled time of arrival and found that the flight was delayed by 20 minutes.</description></item><item><title>Easter egg on Google: New Year 2010 Countdown</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2009/12/31/easter-egg-on-google-new-year-2010-countdown/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2009 10:30:30 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2009/12/31/easter-egg-on-google-new-year-2010-countdown/</guid><description>My friend Amit had just created an account on GMail and logged out after that. Just then, he opened Google and was going to search something when I mentioned I&amp;rsquo;m Feeling Lucky to him. He asked what is that to which I thought of replying by showing him the official explanation by Google, so I clicked on &amp;rsquo;the&amp;rsquo; button without any search string. And voila! It showed this:
After scratching my head for few seconds, it occurred to me that it could be the countdown to welcome the new year 2010.</description></item><item><title>Tathva and the Seniors - Part 1</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2009/11/20/tathva-and-the-seniors-part-1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2009 17:55:21 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2009/11/20/tathva-and-the-seniors-part-1/</guid><description>OK, I agree, it&amp;rsquo;s been too late to post about Tathva. But I had this post in mind since the end of Tathva on October 25, 2009. This is the time, when I am quitting my procrastination and I am free from the daily schedule and writing this post.
First of all, let me talk about the Lecture Series at Tathva &amp;lsquo;09. It started with Dr. APJ Abdul Kalam visiting the campus, and continued with talks by Dr.</description></item><item><title>This is How a Budding Engineer Searches for his Glasses</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2009/11/15/this-is-how-a-budding-engineer-searches-for-his-glasses/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2009 08:34:33 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2009/11/15/this-is-how-a-budding-engineer-searches-for-his-glasses/</guid><description>Just spotted this on the unofficial Notice Board of Hostel A (my hostel at NIT Calicut). Please click on the pics to enlarge:
Disclaimer: The names and other sensitive info has been smudged to preserve the person&amp;rsquo;s privacy.
This left me wondering of the creative minds of my hostel mates. And yeah, if you find his specs, please return them. You can post a comment here and ask me to help you return the glasses ;).</description></item><item><title>A Brief Overview of Ubuntu 9.10 Karmic Koala</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2009/10/30/a-brief-overview-of-ubuntu-9-10-karmic-koala/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2009 17:06:05 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2009/10/30/a-brief-overview-of-ubuntu-9-10-karmic-koala/</guid><description>Just got my hands on to latest version of Ubuntu 9.10 Karmic Koala around 5 hours ago. So, this will be a very brief overview of Ubuntu&amp;rsquo;s latest version.
Me being Ubuntu crazy, just started exploring it after downloading it. I setup my 8 GB Corsair Flash Voyager as a bootable Ubuntu 9.10 drive using USB Startup Disk Creator available in Jaunty.
Booting into the live system was similar as before except for the color and design of the Ubuntu logo on bootup has changed.</description></item><item><title>Dr. APJ Abdul Kalam's visit to NIT Calicut</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2009/10/15/dr-apj-abdul-kalams-visit-to-nit-calicut/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2009 16:29:33 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2009/10/15/dr-apj-abdul-kalams-visit-to-nit-calicut/</guid><description>It was this day, that I was waiting for almost a month now. Dr. APJ Abdul Kalam visiting the campus of National Institute of Technology Calicut, my college.
And, it was just yesternight and today&amp;rsquo;s morning, that I was so excited to get his one glimpse in front of my eyes. Everything in the campus seemed so good yesterday, with all the decorations, lightings and preparations in Open Air Theatre (OAT) and near Aryabhatta Hall.</description></item><item><title>Chhole Bekaar Waale...??</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2009/07/16/chhole-bekaar-waale/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2009 23:14:21 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2009/07/16/chhole-bekaar-waale/</guid><description>Just spotted on this in Navyug Market (Ghaziabad) yesterday:
I visited Navyug Market yesterday with Mukul for some quick and cheap photostats (@ Rs. 0.75 per page). After coming out of the shop, Mukul pointed towards this vendor which caught my eye.
I was bit in a hurry but couldn&amp;rsquo;t stop the temptation of taking a snap. I asked the vendor whether I could take a photo. The Chhole Wala (in the center) agreed with a smile and said &amp;ldquo;Arrey kyun nahin?</description></item><item><title>And hence, I used my right to vote</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2009/05/11/and-hence-i-used-my-right-to-vote/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2009 04:15:51 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2009/05/11/and-hence-i-used-my-right-to-vote/</guid><description>So I did it, and for the first time. You won&amp;rsquo;t believe when I write that I was way too excited to do this for almost a month.
Ok let me make things clear: I voted for the first time.
I am 19 and as many other adolescents was excited to be able to vote after turning 18. But last year I didn&amp;rsquo;t get my EPIC (Elector&amp;rsquo;s Photo Identity Card) as you are supposed to be 18 on January 1st of the year to be eligible for voting.</description></item><item><title>TechGlider logo, finally designed</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2008/09/30/techglider-logo-finally-designed/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2008 04:48:54 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2008/09/30/techglider-logo-finally-designed/</guid><description>I am happy :-) to inform all of you that I have finally designed a logo for the TechGlider:
Although I am not that satisfied with the logo, but I think it will do for the time being. Any suggestions for improvement of the logo are welcome.
I couldn&amp;rsquo;t finish the development of TechGlider this week (designing a logo really takes too much of time ;-)</description></item><item><title>Back with a blast (actually 5) ...</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2008/09/14/back-with-a-blast-actually-5/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2008 11:52:29 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2008/09/14/back-with-a-blast-actually-5/</guid><description>Finally, I came back for the weekend, yesterday.
Slept late at night (around 1:30 AM), the night before yesterday, so was late for the morning journey.
Something unusual happened during my journey in the DTC bus, that I may not be able forget easily. While traveling with my friend Manoj in the bus, I pointed out to him the message written on the back of every seat:
Apni seat ke neeche dekhiye.</description></item><item><title>A Guide to Installing Fedora 9: Part 2</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2008/09/07/a-guide-to-installing-fedora-9-part-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2008 14:52:21 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2008/09/07/a-guide-to-installing-fedora-9-part-2/</guid><description>So, you have already booted up with the live DVD. Follow this part to actually install Fedora on your system&amp;hellip;
The Main Installation of Fedora: After reaching to the Fedora Desktop (if you don&amp;rsquo;t know how, follow the first part of this guide), use the &amp;ldquo;Install to Hard Drive&amp;rdquo; icon to start the Fedora installer. You will be greeted with the following window: Click &amp;lsquo;Next&amp;rsquo;. Select the layout of your keyboard from the list that appears (usually US English).</description></item><item><title>A Guide to Installing Fedora 9: Part 1</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2008/09/06/a-guide-to-installing-fedora-9-part-1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2008 01:50:41 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2008/09/06/a-guide-to-installing-fedora-9-part-1/</guid><description>This is a beginner&amp;rsquo;s tutorial to installing Fedora 9 on your PC. In a recent survey I found that Fedora is more popular in India than Ubuntu (my personal favorite) so I decided to give a installation guide for Fedora instead of Ubuntu (read: http://techglider.in/blog/blog1.php/20 &amp;hellip; thiversary).
Prerequisites: You will need
Fedora 9 installation DVD (to know how to get one, visit: http://techglider.in/blog/blog1.php/20 &amp;hellip; ting-linux)
A PC system with atleast 9 GB of free space and minimum of 256 MB of RAM</description></item><item><title>Fedora 9 Installation Screenshots uploaded</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2008/09/05/fedora-9-installation-screenshots-uploaded/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2008 12:59:14 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2008/09/05/fedora-9-installation-screenshots-uploaded/</guid><description>:phew: Finally, the screenshots for Fedora 9 installation have been uploaded (with great difficulty and mess up of my system and internet connection in the last few days).
To view a slide show follow the link: http://www.flickr.com/photos/techglider/sets/72157607119105020/show/
Hope to write a &amp;ldquo;full guide to installing Fedora 9 on your PC&amp;rdquo; by Sunday.</description></item><item><title>FOSS and LAMP Workshop at ABES by ILUG-D</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2008/08/27/foss-and-lamp-workshop-at-abes-by-ilug-d/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2008 16:15:45 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2008/08/27/foss-and-lamp-workshop-at-abes-by-ilug-d/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been more than 10 days since I last posted &amp;lsquo;cause I was (and am) following a very busy schedule.
A lot happened in these days. The most prominent event among many was the LAMP workshop by the India Linux Users&amp;rsquo; Group, Delhi held on August 23, 2008 at ABES Engineering College.
I was trying to get a fully working linux distro installed on my PC since I first assembled my PC back in December 2006.</description></item><item><title>iPhone 3G</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2008/08/23/iphone-3g/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2008 15:23:35 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2008/08/23/iphone-3g/</guid><description>As you may be knowing, Apple&amp;rsquo;s iPhone 3G has been launched just yesterday (Aug 22, 2008) at 00:00 hours by Airtel and Vodafone in India. They have kept its pricing as Rs. 31,000 for the 8 GB version and Rs. 36,100 for the 16 GB variant.
The iPhone is an example of convergence device which integrates an iPod, an internet device and of course a phone into a single piece of hardware.</description></item><item><title>That hard and tiring day of July 31</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2008/08/05/that-hard-and-tiring-day-of-july-31/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2008 14:22:47 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2008/08/05/that-hard-and-tiring-day-of-july-31/</guid><description>I mentioned about this day in my post of August 1.
I started the day at night by wishing a friend birthday, eventually making her wakeup at midnight. Then, came the inauguration of my website with my first post on The TechGlider Blog at 6 in the morning. This was the easy part of the day.
I reached the Ghaziabad Railway Station at 7:50 to board the train to Tilak Bridge at Delhi, for I use to go to South Delhi to attend FIITJEE classes for IIT-JEE preparation.</description></item></channel></rss>