<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>foss.in on The TechGlider</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/tags/foss.in/</link><description>Recent content in foss.in on The TechGlider</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 08:33:41 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/tags/foss.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Of FOSSMeets at NIT Calicut</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2013/04/14/of-fossmeets-at-nit-calicut/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 08:33:41 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2013/04/14/of-fossmeets-at-nit-calicut/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been over a month and a half since the last edition of FOSSMeet at NIT Calicut. As an active member of organizing team for FOSSMeets &amp;lsquo;10 and &amp;lsquo;11 and a keen but silent observer for the 2013 edition, I want to share some history, some ideas &amp;amp; few observations with this post. The intent is to generate discussion among people who have been part of earlier FOSSMeets and to leave some things to ponder about (and act on) for juniors.</description></item><item><title>Really Achieving Your Childhood Dreams - The Last Lecture</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2011/03/09/really-achieving-your-childhood-dreams-the-last-lecture/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2011 19:01:21 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2011/03/09/really-achieving-your-childhood-dreams-the-last-lecture/</guid><description>I finally got a chance to watch this wonderful talk (by Randy Pausch) popularly known as The Last Lecture. I wanted to watch this for a long time - since Anjhan mentioned about it in his keynote at foss.in and since Prateek Kalyankar had recommended this to me in Jan.
A really nice watch for anyone who has ever dreamed and thought of fulfilling them. I was particularly amazed to see a youthful, energetic, handsome Randy deliver that talk in such a cheerful, darkly funny way, while being just a few months away from his death (and knowing it!</description></item><item><title>Something that has stuck with me after A...</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/status/2010/12/23/something-that-has-stuck-with-me-after-a/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2010 18:30:23 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/status/2010/12/23/something-that-has-stuck-with-me-after-a/</guid><description>Something that has stuck with me after Anjhan&amp;rsquo;s keynote at the last FOSS.IN:
When you are pissed off at somebody, and you&amp;rsquo;re angry at them, you just haven&amp;rsquo;t given them enough time. Just give them a little more time — and they&amp;rsquo;ll almost always impress you.</description></item><item><title>FOSS.IN just got over. And it was the la...</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/status/2010/12/18/foss-in-just-got-over-and-it-was-the-la/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2010 11:23:23 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/status/2010/12/18/foss-in-just-got-over-and-it-was-the-la/</guid><description>FOSS.IN just got over. And it was the last one ever. I am so grateful to Praveen because of whom I made up my mind to attend it. I badly needed a change in my thinking process which this foss.in has succeeded in bringing. This new blog is one step of the impact of the change.</description></item></channel></rss>