<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Personal on The TechGlider</title><link>techglider.in/tags/personal/</link><description>Recent content in Personal on The TechGlider</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2016 21:15:39 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="techglider.in/tags/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>2016: Year (and a half) in Review</title><link>techglider.in/post/2016/12/31/2016-year-and-a-half-in-review/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2016 21:15:39 -0500</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2016/12/31/2016-year-and-a-half-in-review/</guid><description>I wanted to write an EoY Review post last year like I did two years ago but I didn&amp;rsquo;t as I was too busy making sure 2016 was beginning with my most important goal for that year&amp;mdash;overcoming my fear of coding and becoming a better programmer. 2016 has been a great year of personal learning and I want to celebrate its passing by documenting some of that learning and experiences.</description></item><item><title>Things I wish I knew in College</title><link>techglider.in/post/2016/10/01/things-i-wish-i-knew-in-college/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 10:51:01 -0400</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2016/10/01/things-i-wish-i-knew-in-college/</guid><description>Meta About a month ago, I asked the following question to the NIT Calicut CSE student body:
If you could ask only one question to an NITC CSE alumnus with diverse experience in industry, higher studies, and research, what would you?
The most raised concerns were:
How to decide between higher studies and industry as your next career move? What are the limitations of an NITC CSE education and how to succeed in the field despite them?</description></item><item><title>Reflections on the Facebook Sannyasa</title><link>techglider.in/post/2016/04/24/reflections-on-the-facebook-sannyasa/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2016 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2016/04/24/reflections-on-the-facebook-sannyasa/</guid><description>As some of you reading this might be aware I have been away for a while.
I deactivated my Facebook account sometime in the first week of Feb; it has been over 75 days. I did try activating it once after 30 days were over and realized within a couple of hours, how ugly and consumeristic this part of the Internet is and since then had not tried logging in again until last night.</description></item><item><title>Java</title><link>techglider.in/post/2016/01/02/java/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2016 22:51:18 -0500</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2016/01/02/java/</guid><description>I don&amp;rsquo;t really recall why I avoided Java all this while.
Few weeks after arriving here at Brown, I learnt Brown is, what they call, a Java school. That&amp;rsquo;s probably not completely true, but for a vast majority of students that take Andy&amp;rsquo;s intro class, CS15, it is. I have come to realize it is not such a bad thing (quite the opposite).
I remember my first few weeks at college when I was trying to teach myself Java in the CC (whoa, they have a website now!</description></item><item><title>Relearning Computer Science</title><link>techglider.in/post/2015/10/28/relearning-computer-science/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2015 11:35:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2015/10/28/relearning-computer-science/</guid><description>Awakening I was awaken from a long sleep of ignorance with some events that occurred in the last couple of weeks. A sudden surge of conscientiousness about taking my education in my hands was one of the immediate results.
The inflection point was getting to hear Bryan Cantrill in person and interviewing with him the next day. I didn’t do my best, but was humbled by Cantrill into realizing how much I had to learn.</description></item><item><title>Exploring Medium</title><link>techglider.in/post/2015/06/29/exploring-medium/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2015 15:41:42 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2015/06/29/exploring-medium/</guid><description>I am considering writing more often, more personal posts on Medium at https://medium.com/@k4rtik. Here&amp;rsquo;s first one among them:</description></item><item><title>2014: Year in Review</title><link>techglider.in/post/2014/12/31/2014-year-in-review/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 23:59:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2014/12/31/2014-year-in-review/</guid><description>Books If I had to describe what my year was about in just one word, it would be these. I was surrounded by books, all sorts of them, throughout the year. I had set out a goal to read 26 full-length books, ie, one per fortnight over the year. I was following the plan until May, when I rediscoverd my love for comic books with the launch of Amar Chitra Katha Android app and the 12 comic books that came free with it.</description></item><item><title>Week 1 at Bangalore and Work</title><link>techglider.in/post/2013/07/21/week-1-at-bangalore-and-work/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2013 14:53:31 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2013/07/21/week-1-at-bangalore-and-work/</guid><description>I landed at Bangalore airport last week flying on an indiGo for the first time; found the experience better than JetKonnect from my first flight.
Next day (Sunday) started early with a walk to Oracle Tech Park and back to get myself familiarized with the area before first day at work. A much-needed haircut followed.
Having caught cold with the change in weather, I had to miss the Goodreads meetup planned at Brigade Road during the day, which I was eagerly awaiting to attend with a friend.</description></item><item><title>Of FOSSMeets at NIT Calicut</title><link>techglider.in/post/2013/04/14/of-fossmeets-at-nit-calicut/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 08:33:41 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2013/04/14/of-fossmeets-at-nit-calicut/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been over a month and a half since the last edition of FOSSMeet at NIT Calicut. As an active member of organizing team for FOSSMeets &amp;lsquo;10 and &amp;lsquo;11 and a keen but silent observer for the 2013 edition, I want to share some history, some ideas &amp;amp; few observations with this post. The intent is to generate discussion among people who have been part of earlier FOSSMeets and to leave some things to ponder about (and act on) for juniors.</description></item><item><title>Musing over The Challenge</title><link>techglider.in/post/2013/02/11/musing-over-the-challenge/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2013 07:28:32 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2013/02/11/musing-over-the-challenge/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been 10 days since I started this challenge. Up to now, I seem to be failing in living up to the daily requirement in the Fibonacci order (0, 1, 1, 2 - the day gaps); of course, I don&amp;rsquo;t want the sequence to continue.
In retrospect, I can see what stopped me in the days I missed - once it was just a tiring day, someday it was work/extended meeting, some day just plain lack of creativity.</description></item><item><title>Even after giving enough time to that someone...</title><link>techglider.in/status/2013/02/08/even-after-giving-enough-time-to-that-someone/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2013 17:50:21 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/status/2013/02/08/even-after-giving-enough-time-to-that-someone/</guid><description>Even after giving enough time to that someone you are pissed off with, you can&amp;rsquo;t always expect to be impressed. Perhaps Randy was wrong. I held this view for a very long time; but time has taken such a turn in last few months that I am only left wondering what Randy exactly meant by enough time.</description></item><item><title>28 Days Challenge</title><link>techglider.in/post/2013/02/01/28-days-challenge/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 16:30:02 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2013/02/01/28-days-challenge/</guid><description>Inspired long back by Oliver Emberton&amp;rsquo;s herculian 30 Day Challenger, I have decided to try it out for myself this month. Feb being the smallest month should serve as the easiest possible start. ;-)
The motivation for doing this are similar - stretching myself to give up on a bad habit, get the most out of my day, or being more productive in general.
Given that I have a lot to say, things that keep on forming virtual blog posts in my mind - some of which are technical, some about my dream college, some advice for juniors, some worldly pondering, some internal struggles - I have decided on my first challenge:</description></item><item><title>Ponderings of the Year Past: Part 2</title><link>techglider.in/post/2012/03/26/ponderings-of-the-year-past-part-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2012 21:03:03 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2012/03/26/ponderings-of-the-year-past-part-2/</guid><description>The following are few important lessons I learnt over the gone year – 2011 (see Part 1 here):
Friends To be very frank (and you can call me weird), I didn&amp;rsquo;t know the meaning of a close friend until about early 2011. As far as I remember, until first semester, definition of a friend for me was somebody who shared similar interests, mutual respect, and trust. I remember objecting to Rama to call him names (in return of his such various favors) by saying &amp;ldquo;dude, I respect you!</description></item><item><title>Ponderings of the Year Past: Part 1</title><link>techglider.in/post/2012/03/26/ponderings-of-the-year-past-part-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2012 19:59:28 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2012/03/26/ponderings-of-the-year-past-part-1/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been long since I wrote something. To be frank, it was last July in which I actually spoke out my mind. Of course, I wished to write a lot more (who doesn&amp;rsquo;t). This one is going to be long, so I decided to partition it.
The following are few important lessons I learnt over the gone year - 2011:
Computer Science != Computer Engineering Vineeth Sir always calls it Computing Science, we even had a discussion over it, perhaps over a year back( and once again recently); the doubt got cleared up only after I looked up ACM&amp;rsquo;s Computing Curricula Recommendations which defines five sub-disciplines of computing: Computer Science, Computer Engineering, Information Systems, Information Technology, and Software Engineering (they have pretty decent comparisons among these disciplines using pictures and charts).</description></item><item><title>Disconnect - An Experiment</title><link>techglider.in/post/2011/07/10/disconnect-an-experiment/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2011 18:37:01 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2011/07/10/disconnect-an-experiment/</guid><description>This will be short.
A small announcement: I will be out of touch for about a week on the Internet. Disconnected on all social networks (including twitter) and off-line on chats (including GMail chat) and unavailable on SMS. I have already disabled all email and SMS notifications from the social networks. This is just for the sake of experimenting to see if I can still live without social media, so don&amp;rsquo;t get weird ideas about this.</description></item><item><title>Choosing an Android Phone - Not an Easy Job</title><link>techglider.in/post/2011/05/23/choosing-an-android-phone-not-an-easy-job/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2011 16:42:51 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2011/05/23/choosing-an-android-phone-not-an-easy-job/</guid><description>Little background It&amp;rsquo;s almost a month now since I sold my old Nokia N72 (fondly named PlatiniumJunior by me), hoping to buy an Android-based smartphone soon. Since then, I have realized how dependent I was on the phone - thinking of taking a quick snap and realizing I don&amp;rsquo;t have a camera anymore is disappointing, same is getting stuck at a word while reading and missing that MSDict software on my phone which was always ready as a quick reference, similar is being jobless at places I am forced to visit at times (or when there were power outages of countless hours at home, more on this in another post) and missing the phone again which I could use to read some or other ebook.</description></item><item><title>I am free no matter what rules surround...</title><link>techglider.in/quote/2011/03/06/i-am-free-no-matter-what-rules-surround/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2011 09:17:47 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/quote/2011/03/06/i-am-free-no-matter-what-rules-surround/</guid><description>I am free, no matter what rules surround me. If I find them tolerable, I tolerate them; if I find them too obnoxious, I break them. I am free because I know that I alone am morally responsible for everything I do.
&amp;mdash;Robert A. Heinlein, &amp;ldquo;The Moon Is a Harsh Mistress&amp;rdquo;, 1966. Source: http://en.wikiquote.org/wiki/The_Moon_Is_a_Harsh_Mistress</description></item><item><title>And I successfully pulled out two consecutive all...</title><link>techglider.in/status/2011/03/06/and-i-successfully-pulled-out-two-consecutive-all/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2011 00:22:25 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/status/2011/03/06/and-i-successfully-pulled-out-two-consecutive-all/</guid><description>And I successfully pulled out two consecutive all-nighters - a first time in my life! For the record: my first all nighter in college was just in last sem (during which Jaseem had to kick me 2-3 times to keep me awake).
And these two were spent properly working on something I love and without facing any loss in productivity during the day. Congrats to myself!</description></item><item><title>The Branch Tour 2011 and me (Part 2)</title><link>techglider.in/post/2011/03/01/the-branch-tour-2011-and-me-part-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 02:30:42 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2011/03/01/the-branch-tour-2011-and-me-part-2/</guid><description>This is second and the last part of my earlier post - The Branch Tour 2011 and me. Please read my last post before reading this.
Disclaimer: The following post is dedicated to all my branch mates and is a little more on the personal side. Additionally, the post is too long and may not be of any relevance for those who seek to attain any bit of technical nirvana from this blog.</description></item><item><title>The Branch Tour 2011 and me (Part 1)</title><link>techglider.in/post/2011/02/28/the-branch-tour-2011-and-me-part-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2011 02:30:13 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2011/02/28/the-branch-tour-2011-and-me-part-1/</guid><description>Disclaimer: The following post is dedicated to all my branch mates and is a little more on the personal side. Additionally, the post is too long and may not be of any relevance for those who seek to attain any bit of technical nirvana from this blog. So, you may happily TLDR this post.
Many have asked me why I decided to go for branch tour when almost none of the northies were ready to go.</description></item><item><title>Discovered today the only two subjects I...</title><link>techglider.in/status/2011/01/20/discovered-today-the-only-two-subjects-i/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2011 15:07:21 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/status/2011/01/20/discovered-today-the-only-two-subjects-i/</guid><description>Discovered today the only two subjects I am really liking in my 4th sem of BTech:
Data Structures and Algorithms - no attendance, low strength, more discussion possible in Sudeep Sir&amp;rsquo;s class Computer Organization - I think I was always more inclined towards hardware and internals of computer system, assembly language programming comes as a bonus part with this course</description></item><item><title>List of Books Read So Far</title><link>techglider.in/post/2008/09/08/list-of-books-read-so-far/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2008 01:50:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2008/09/08/list-of-books-read-so-far/</guid><description>This is a list of books I used to maintain at The TechGlider Forums, imported here for keeping it updated.
Here I list the books I have read (only those whose names I remember) so far (in finishing order):
Harry Potter and the Philosopher&amp;rsquo;s Stone, by J K Rowling
Harry Potter and the Chamber of Secrets, by J K Rowling
Harry Potter and the Prisoner of Azkaban, by J K Rowling</description></item><item><title>My First Post and Myself Poured Out for the Day</title><link>techglider.in/post/2008/03/11/my-first-post-and-myself-poured-out-for-the-day/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2008 00:23:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2008/03/11/my-first-post-and-myself-poured-out-for-the-day/</guid><description>Well, just letting this start off. My desire to have a blog is pushing me to start it now; just in the middle of my XII Class Boards Examinations. Just had my English paper today; went bad somehow. May be I was just thinking of myself as a great writer who can never fail. But all just went bad and I don&amp;rsquo;t know. I completed all the stuff that was asked in the paper but don&amp;rsquo;t know why I didn&amp;rsquo;t get the feeling of satisfaction after the examination was over.</description></item></channel></rss>