<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>distro on The TechGlider</title><link>techglider.in/tags/distro/</link><description>Recent content in distro on The TechGlider</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2009 15:08:30 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="techglider.in/tags/distro/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Essential software for a working Ubuntu 9.04 Desktop</title><link>techglider.in/post/2009/09/19/essential-software-for-a-working-ubuntu-9-04-desktop/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2009 15:08:30 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2009/09/19/essential-software-for-a-working-ubuntu-9-04-desktop/</guid><description>These are the steps to follow if you want your latest Ubuntu install to have all the essential software and codecs installed so that you can use your Ubuntu linux system as a/an replacement/addition of windows operating system.
You should be connected to internet to follow these steps. You can use Ctrl+Shift+V to paste the copied code in Terminal, which can be accessed as Applications-&amp;gt;Accessories-&amp;gt;Terminal.
First of all, choose the best server in System-&amp;gt;Administration-&amp;gt;Software Sources.</description></item><item><title>A Guide to Installing Fedora 9: Part 2</title><link>techglider.in/post/2008/09/07/a-guide-to-installing-fedora-9-part-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2008 14:52:21 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2008/09/07/a-guide-to-installing-fedora-9-part-2/</guid><description>So, you have already booted up with the live DVD. Follow this part to actually install Fedora on your system&amp;hellip;
The Main Installation of Fedora: After reaching to the Fedora Desktop (if you don&amp;rsquo;t know how, follow the first part of this guide), use the &amp;ldquo;Install to Hard Drive&amp;rdquo; icon to start the Fedora installer. You will be greeted with the following window: Click &amp;lsquo;Next&amp;rsquo;. Select the layout of your keyboard from the list that appears (usually US English).</description></item><item><title>A Guide to Installing Fedora 9: Part 1</title><link>techglider.in/post/2008/09/06/a-guide-to-installing-fedora-9-part-1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2008 01:50:41 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2008/09/06/a-guide-to-installing-fedora-9-part-1/</guid><description>This is a beginner&amp;rsquo;s tutorial to installing Fedora 9 on your PC. In a recent survey I found that Fedora is more popular in India than Ubuntu (my personal favorite) so I decided to give a installation guide for Fedora instead of Ubuntu (read: http://techglider.in/blog/blog1.php/20 &amp;hellip; thiversary).
Prerequisites: You will need
Fedora 9 installation DVD (to know how to get one, visit: http://techglider.in/blog/blog1.php/20 &amp;hellip; ting-linux)
A PC system with atleast 9 GB of free space and minimum of 256 MB of RAM</description></item><item><title>My entry into the open world of linux</title><link>techglider.in/post/2008/08/03/my-entry-into-the-open-world-of-linux/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2008 00:31:32 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2008/08/03/my-entry-into-the-open-world-of-linux/</guid><description>July 30, 2008, the day I decided to completely scrap off Windows XP and switched to linux as my only operating system. Now, after a successful transition from the proprietary to the open source, I am all happy and a lot more secure and satisfied :-), for the world of linux provides complete relief from the hassles of spyware, viruses and usual breakdowns of windows.
For those who don&amp;rsquo;t know about linux, it is an operating system platform which is free and open (in the sense that you can see its code, modify it, distribute it and do a lot more).</description></item></channel></rss>