<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>TGB on The TechGlider</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/tags/tgb/</link><description>Recent content in TGB on The TechGlider</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2011 07:43:51 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/tags/tgb/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>...and, we're back!</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2011/03/13/and-we-are-back/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2011 07:43:51 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2011/03/13/and-we-are-back/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been so long - missing the TechGlider - my dream, my hard work of over 2 years was gone. Started in July 2008, gone in July 2010. :(
The reason of this long absence: I lost the ownership of the domain techglider.com - partly because of my own carelessness, and partly because of my webhost Four &amp;lsquo;S&amp;rsquo; Tech&amp;rsquo;s troubles. In the process, I did learn a few interesting things like the concept of drop catching, how the companies like GoDaddy make so much money; and more importantly how not to lose my domain again.</description></item><item><title>The TechGlider Blog is now Kartik Scribbles...</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2009/11/08/the-techglider-blog-is-now-kartik-scribbles/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2009 11:28:34 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2009/11/08/the-techglider-blog-is-now-kartik-scribbles/</guid><description>This change is something I wanted to incorporate since I restored this blog in the beginning of last month. Finally, the change is here.
The main reason why I changed the name of the blog is simple. &amp;lsquo;The TechGlider Blog&amp;rsquo; sounds like the official blog of my site - TechGlider.com which, in its actuality, is not that. This is my blog, Kartik&amp;rsquo;s. So, the name Kartik Scribbles&amp;hellip;
More personalized, more sensible, more fun, more readable.</description></item><item><title>The TechGlider Blog is back</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2009/10/03/the-techglider-blog-is-back/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2009 09:11:09 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2009/10/03/the-techglider-blog-is-back/</guid><description>I am really happy to announce that I have been able to restore the TGB successfully (after fiddling with the backups for almost a month). This period of two and a half months without my blog was really unbearable for me; the only thing that helped me bear this pain was what was happening in my real life. A lot of wonderful events have changed my life (e.g. I have taken admission in BTech CSE at NIT Calicut).</description></item><item><title>Welcome to the All New TechGlider Blog</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2008/10/06/welcome-to-the-all-new-techglider-blog/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2008 23:46:23 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2008/10/06/welcome-to-the-all-new-techglider-blog/</guid><description>This is my first post on WordPress and through this I welcome you to the all new TechGlider Blog.
I am finally finished with moving the TGB to WordPress. WordPress offers a plethora of plugins to customize one&amp;rsquo;s blog and I am trying to choose what are those that I need for the TGB. As pointed out in my last post, this change hasn&amp;rsquo;t been easy. I almost lost all of my previous posts for there was no efficient way to import the posts from my b2evolution installation to WordPress, so I had to do it manually and took a whole day for that (these type of repetitive works are really a pain in the neck for me).</description></item><item><title>Mainstream development of TechGlider in full flow</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2008/09/23/mainstream-development-of-techglider-in-full-flow/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2008 00:31:45 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2008/09/23/mainstream-development-of-techglider-in-full-flow/</guid><description>And, I came back earlier by a week from the schedule.
I am happy to announce that the start of the next week (hopefully) will see the rise of TechGlider in its full avatar; fully loaded with most of stuff I have to offer.
I have got certain idea of what is going to be the logo for the TechGlider and will be designing it on paper in this week. The main site is no longer hidden: you are no longer directed to this TechGlider Blog on typing www.</description></item></channel></rss>