<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>fedora on The TechGlider</title><link>techglider.in/tags/fedora/</link><description>Recent content in fedora on The TechGlider</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2013 14:39:46 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="techglider.in/tags/fedora/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Found the culprit for a long standing problem...</title><link>techglider.in/status/2013/04/19/found-the-culprit-for-a-long-standing-problem/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2013 14:39:46 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/status/2013/04/19/found-the-culprit-for-a-long-standing-problem/</guid><description>Found the culprit for a long standing problem with Linux install disk booting on my Dell Studio XPS 1645 today at http://forums.linuxmint.com/viewtopic.php?f=46&amp;amp;t=126993#p692786 - it was my wireless card. Was facing this problem at least since last October when I tried to install latest editions of Fedora and ArchLinux but couldn&amp;rsquo;t. On Linux Mint 14 Cinnamon now.</description></item><item><title>Build EiskaltDC++ on Fedora 15 Lovelock 64-bit</title><link>techglider.in/post/2011/10/06/build-eiskaltdc-on-fedora-16-lovelock-64-bit/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2011 07:19:04 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2011/10/06/build-eiskaltdc-on-fedora-16-lovelock-64-bit/</guid><description>EiskaltDC++ is a cross-platform program that uses the Direct Connect and ADC protocol. The direct connect client LinuxDC++ available in rpmfusion repos doesn&amp;rsquo;t yet support ADC protocol and hence doesn&amp;rsquo;t work with the DC++ Hub that has been setup in our hostel. I had to compile Eiskalt from the sources. Posting here the steps I had to follow for a rather painful build.
I am using Fedora 15 64-bit with GNOME 3 desktop.</description></item><item><title>Installing 64-bit version of Flash Player on Fedora 13</title><link>techglider.in/post/2010/10/16/installing-64-bit-version-of-flash-player-on-fedora-13/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Oct 2010 17:18:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2010/10/16/installing-64-bit-version-of-flash-player-on-fedora-13/</guid><description>I have been using Fedora 64-bit KDE for many months now, but was too lazy to install flash player (I don&amp;rsquo;t usually need it as I am no YouTube junkie) until now. But today I had to visit some sites whose content seemed next to none without flash plugin on my browser. This forced me to install flash player finally.
Such a person who always wants to remain at the cutting edge as I am, I tried installing the latest Flash Player &amp;ldquo;Square&amp;rdquo; Preview Release 64-bit available from Adobe Labs.</description></item><item><title>Back to linux and switching to WordPress...</title><link>techglider.in/post/2008/10/05/back-to-linux-and-switching-to-wordpress/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2008 12:36:38 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2008/10/05/back-to-linux-and-switching-to-wordpress/</guid><description>I am glad to tell you that I have got rid of windows XP (again!) after muddling my head for 2 days trying to make it stable on my system. Now, I feel better that I gave it up in just 4 days of use and got rid of shame (read about it here) I was feeling that I installed XP again. I now have 2 variants of linux viz. Ubuntu 8.</description></item><item><title>A Guide to Installing Fedora 9: Part 2</title><link>techglider.in/post/2008/09/07/a-guide-to-installing-fedora-9-part-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2008 14:52:21 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2008/09/07/a-guide-to-installing-fedora-9-part-2/</guid><description>So, you have already booted up with the live DVD. Follow this part to actually install Fedora on your system&amp;hellip;
The Main Installation of Fedora: After reaching to the Fedora Desktop (if you don&amp;rsquo;t know how, follow the first part of this guide), use the &amp;ldquo;Install to Hard Drive&amp;rdquo; icon to start the Fedora installer. You will be greeted with the following window: Click &amp;lsquo;Next&amp;rsquo;. Select the layout of your keyboard from the list that appears (usually US English).</description></item><item><title>A Guide to Installing Fedora 9: Part 1</title><link>techglider.in/post/2008/09/06/a-guide-to-installing-fedora-9-part-1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2008 01:50:41 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2008/09/06/a-guide-to-installing-fedora-9-part-1/</guid><description>This is a beginner&amp;rsquo;s tutorial to installing Fedora 9 on your PC. In a recent survey I found that Fedora is more popular in India than Ubuntu (my personal favorite) so I decided to give a installation guide for Fedora instead of Ubuntu (read: https://techglider.in/blog/blog1.php/20 &amp;hellip; thiversary).
Prerequisites: You will need
Fedora 9 installation DVD (to know how to get one, visit: https://techglider.in/blog/blog1.php/20 &amp;hellip; ting-linux)
A PC system with atleast 9 GB of free space and minimum of 256 MB of RAM</description></item><item><title>Fedora 9 Installation Screenshots uploaded</title><link>techglider.in/post/2008/09/05/fedora-9-installation-screenshots-uploaded/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2008 12:59:14 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2008/09/05/fedora-9-installation-screenshots-uploaded/</guid><description>:phew: Finally, the screenshots for Fedora 9 installation have been uploaded (with great difficulty and mess up of my system and internet connection in the last few days).
To view a slide show follow the link: http://www.flickr.com/photos/techglider/sets/72157607119105020/show/
Hope to write a &amp;ldquo;full guide to installing Fedora 9 on your PC&amp;rdquo; by Sunday.</description></item></channel></rss>