<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>inspiration on The TechGlider</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/tags/inspiration/</link><description>Recent content in inspiration on The TechGlider</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2016 06:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/tags/inspiration/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Reflections on the Facebook Sannyasa</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2016/04/24/reflections-on-the-facebook-sannyasa/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2016 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2016/04/24/reflections-on-the-facebook-sannyasa/</guid><description>As some of you reading this might be aware I have been away for a while.
I deactivated my Facebook account sometime in the first week of Feb; it has been over 75 days. I did try activating it once after 30 days were over and realized within a couple of hours, how ugly and consumeristic this part of the Internet is and since then had not tried logging in again until last night.</description></item><item><title>Goal today</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/status/2016/03/25/goal-today/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2016 13:14:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/status/2016/03/25/goal-today/</guid><description>Note: This is an archived post from my unmaintained Tumblr blog https://k4rtik.tumblr.com</description></item><item><title>The Gap</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/quote/2015/12/06/the-gap/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2015 21:19:16 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/quote/2015/12/06/the-gap/</guid><description>Nobody tells this to people who are beginners, I wish someone told me. All of us who do creative work, we get into it because we have good taste. But there is this gap. For the first couple years you make stuff, it&amp;rsquo;s just not that good. It&amp;rsquo;s trying to be good, it has potential, but it&amp;rsquo;s not. But your taste, the thing that got you into the game, is still killer.</description></item><item><title>On Blogging</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2015/06/28/on-blogging/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2015 23:40:17 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2015/06/28/on-blogging/</guid><description>Something interesting happened this morning which leads to existence of this post.
I had gone to visit a long time friend and mentor Amarjit at his home. It was unusual of him to not welcome me at the door himself. I soon learnt why — Deepak Malani was there!
I know Deepak for about 4–5 years now, mostly from stories told by seniors (of IEEE Glory Days) and from Amarjit himself.</description></item><item><title>Review of V for Vendetta</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2015/05/01/review-of-v-for-vendetta/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 20:59:51 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2015/05/01/review-of-v-for-vendetta/</guid><description>V for Vendetta by Alan Moore
My rating: 4.5 of 5 stars
I had seen the film adaptation 4-5 years ago but hardly recalled what it was about. Decided to watch it again after I was done with the graphic novel and compare the two.
The Graphic Novel First couple of volumes in the 10-volume series didn&amp;rsquo;t make much sense and were rather slow to read as I was just getting introduced to the characters.</description></item><item><title>Review of No Place to Hide by Glenn Greenwald</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2015/04/12/review-of-no-place-to-hide-by-glenn-greenwald/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2015 12:37:38 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2015/04/12/review-of-no-place-to-hide-by-glenn-greenwald/</guid><description>No Place to Hide: Edward Snowden, the NSA and the Surveillance State by Glenn Greenwald
My rating: 4 of 5 stars
I had bought this book right away after reading the following tweet from a concerned friend:
It took me another 5 months to actually start reading the book.
Review First two chapters read like a Dan Brown thriller except that you constantly keep reminding yourself that this is not fiction and events leading to the Snowden revelations actually happened this way.</description></item><item><title>Learn</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/quote/2015/03/05/live-as-if-you-were-to-die-tomorrow-learn/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2015 07:13:09 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/quote/2015/03/05/live-as-if-you-were-to-die-tomorrow-learn/</guid><description>Live as if you were to die tomorrow. Learn as if you were to live forever.
&amp;mdash;Mahatma Gandhi, Goodreads citation (did not find any authoritative source of this quote)
This used to be my motto for a long time before college, cannot recall when this disappeared from my active conscience. Caught my eye when Prof. Adam Porter quoted this in the announcement email for week 7 of his Coursera class on Programming Mobile Applications for Android Handheld Systems.</description></item><item><title>15 Commitments of Conscious Leadership</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/quote/2014/11/30/15-commitments-of-conscious-leadership/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2014 12:37:31 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/quote/2014/11/30/15-commitments-of-conscious-leadership/</guid><description>Read as &amp;lsquo;commitment&amp;rsquo; and then a &amp;lsquo;counter-commitment&amp;rsquo; for each point.
I commit to taking full responsibility for the circumstances of my life, and my physical, emotional, mental and spiritual wellbeing. I commit to support others to take full responsibility for their lives.
I commit to blaming others and myself for what is wrong in the world. I commit to being a victim, villain, or a hero and taking more or less than 100% responsibility.</description></item><item><title>You literally ought to be asking yourself all...</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/quote/2013/11/13/you-literally-ought-to-be-asking-yourself-all/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2013 15:48:09 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/quote/2013/11/13/you-literally-ought-to-be-asking-yourself-all/</guid><description>You literally ought to be asking yourself all of the time - what&amp;rsquo;s the most important thing I could be working on in the world right now; and if you are not working on that, why aren&amp;rsquo;t you?
&amp;mdash;Aaron Swartz, as quoted by @TarenSK in the upcoming documentary on Swartz (Source: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3izOJ7zX5I0)</description></item><item><title>Your work is going to fill a large...</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/quote/2013/10/17/your-work-is-going-to-fill-a-large/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2013 10:01:53 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/quote/2013/10/17/your-work-is-going-to-fill-a-large/</guid><description>Your work is going to fill a large part of your life, and the only way to be truly satisfied is to do what you believe is great work. And the only way to do great work is to love what you do. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t found it yet, keep looking. Don&amp;rsquo;t settle. As with all matters of the heart, you&amp;rsquo;ll know when you find it. And, like any great relationship, it just gets better and better as the years roll on.</description></item><item><title>Review of An Autobiography or The Story of my Experiments with Truth</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2013/07/08/review-of-an-autobiography-or-the-story-of-my-experiments-with-truth/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2013 12:28:28 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2013/07/08/review-of-an-autobiography-or-the-story-of-my-experiments-with-truth/</guid><description>An Autobiography or The Story of my Experiments with Truth by Mahatma Gandhi
My rating: 5 of 5 stars
Recommended read to understand what Mahatma Gandhi and his ideals of Truth and Ahimsa stood for, in his own words.
Gandhi does full justice with the autobiography not failing to mention incidences from his life which could be termed as objectionable, or embarrassing. His exploration of dietetics, religion, dressing styles and later politics reaffirms my belief in a statement one of my professors made about Gandhi which inspired me to read the book:</description></item><item><title>Review of Surely You're Joking, Mr. Feynman!</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2013/05/30/review-of-surely-youre-joking-mr.-feynman/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2013 09:44:31 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2013/05/30/review-of-surely-youre-joking-mr.-feynman/</guid><description>Surely You&amp;rsquo;re Joking, Mr. Feynman! by Richard P. Feynman
My rating: 5 of 5 stars
This is one of those books which bring a turning point in your life, and make you reevaluate it, much like Randy Pausch&amp;rsquo;s The Last Lecture and Steve Jobs bio for me. Made me take interest in physics around us again. :)
Feynman was surely a man of multiple lives, how could anybody live so much?</description></item><item><title>Nothing in the world can take the place...</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/quote/2013/05/14/nothing-in-the-world-can-take-the-place/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2013 00:32:04 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/quote/2013/05/14/nothing-in-the-world-can-take-the-place/</guid><description>Nothing in the world can take the place of persistence. Talent will not; nothing is more common than unsuccessful men with talent. Genius will not; unrewarded genius is almost a proverb. Education will not; the world is full of educated derelicts. Persistence and determination alone are omnipotent. The slogan Press On! has solved and always will solve the problems of the human race.
&amp;mdash;Calvin Coolidge (Discovered this as my MITian friend Ankur&amp;rsquo;s gmail chat status)</description></item><item><title>Turning Points by APJ Abdul Kalam - A Review</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2013/04/16/turning-points-by-apj-abdul-kalam-a-review/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2013 09:15:26 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2013/04/16/turning-points-by-apj-abdul-kalam-a-review/</guid><description>Turning Points: A Journey Through Challenges by A.P.J. Abdul Kalam
My rating: 4 of 5 stars
A good book that shows the life of a President that India loved, sheds light on the decisions he made that were considered controversial and inspires the leader in one. Not a book for a casual reader, for sure, they might complain it&amp;rsquo;s boring.
I feel Kalam uplifted the position of President of India with his initiatives during his tenure.</description></item><item><title>Of FOSSMeets at NIT Calicut</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2013/04/14/of-fossmeets-at-nit-calicut/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 08:33:41 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2013/04/14/of-fossmeets-at-nit-calicut/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been over a month and a half since the last edition of FOSSMeet at NIT Calicut. As an active member of organizing team for FOSSMeets &amp;lsquo;10 and &amp;lsquo;11 and a keen but silent observer for the 2013 edition, I want to share some history, some ideas &amp;amp; few observations with this post. The intent is to generate discussion among people who have been part of earlier FOSSMeets and to leave some things to ponder about (and act on) for juniors.</description></item><item><title>The programmers of tomorrow are the wizards of...</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/quote/2013/02/26/the-programmers-of-tomorrow-are-the-wizards-of/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2013 18:59:54 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/quote/2013/02/26/the-programmers-of-tomorrow-are-the-wizards-of/</guid><description>The programmers of tomorrow are the wizards of the future. You&amp;rsquo;re going to look like you have magic powers compared to everybody else.
&amp;mdash;Gabe Newell, Founder and President, Valve (Source: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dU1xS07N-FA courtesy of code.org)</description></item><item><title>Musing over The Challenge</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2013/02/11/musing-over-the-challenge/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2013 07:28:32 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2013/02/11/musing-over-the-challenge/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been 10 days since I started this challenge. Up to now, I seem to be failing in living up to the daily requirement in the Fibonacci order (0, 1, 1, 2 - the day gaps); of course, I don&amp;rsquo;t want the sequence to continue.
In retrospect, I can see what stopped me in the days I missed - once it was just a tiring day, someday it was work/extended meeting, some day just plain lack of creativity.</description></item><item><title>I spent my years from age 11 to...</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/quote/2013/02/04/i-spent-my-years-from-age-11-to/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2013 18:38:01 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/quote/2013/02/04/i-spent-my-years-from-age-11-to/</guid><description>I spent my years from age 11 to 19 thinking about software. And if I have something that I really know, it&amp;rsquo;s software. I&amp;rsquo;m a hobbyist in biotech, but I could never go and make a world-class contribution in another field.
&amp;mdash;Bill Gates. Source: http://articles.economictimes.indiatimes.com/2002-11-18/news/27331168_1_bill-gates-kumar-mangalam-birla-aditya-vikram-birla-group/2 (This was a great inspiration when choosing CS as a discipline after school; I seem to have forgotten how big an ideal Gates was for me then.</description></item><item><title>Logicomix: An Epic Search for Truth</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2013/02/03/logicomix-an-epic-search-for-truth/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2013 18:52:40 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2013/02/03/logicomix-an-epic-search-for-truth/</guid><description>This one needs to be quick, 14 minutes until midnight.
Logicomix (Photo credit: Wikipedia)
In this post I want to introduce a graphic novel which I read about a year back - Logicomix: An Epic Search for Truth.
How I ended up reading this is an interesting story in itself. Let me try to recite in minimum possible words. During that time (Sem 6) I had enrolled for a course called Computational Complexity by Murali sir.</description></item><item><title>Always code as if the guy who ends...</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/quote/2012/12/28/always-code-as-if-the-guy-who-ends/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2012 10:39:01 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/quote/2012/12/28/always-code-as-if-the-guy-who-ends/</guid><description>Always code as if the guy who ends up maintaining your code will be a violent psychopath who knows where you live. Code for readability.
&amp;mdash;John F Woods. Source: https://groups.google.com/d/msg/comp.lang.c++/rYCO5yn4lXw/oITtSkZOtoUJ (With special attribution to two juniors who posted this on homepage of CSEA&amp;rsquo;s upcoming website.)</description></item><item><title>Having good teachers is important This can make...</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/quote/2012/08/23/having-good-teachers-is-important-this-can-make-4/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2012 16:28:25 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/quote/2012/08/23/having-good-teachers-is-important-this-can-make-4/</guid><description>Having good teachers is important. This can make or kill your interests. Even Kalam attributes being what he is today to him having great teachers. Unfortunately, this is something which is not under one’s control.
&amp;mdash;me (on a twitter conversation with Delbin about electives, teachers and interest in subjects)</description></item><item><title>It is necessary to work if not from...</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/quote/2012/07/18/it-is-necessary-to-work-if-not-from/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2012 08:29:33 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/quote/2012/07/18/it-is-necessary-to-work-if-not-from/</guid><description>It is necessary to work, if not from inclination, at least from despair. Everything considered, work is less boring than amusing oneself.
&amp;mdash;Charles Baudelaire (discovered this in Vinod Pathari Sir&amp;rsquo;s email signature and found it particularly interesting)</description></item><item><title>Steve Jobs by Walter Isaacson - A Review</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2012/06/22/steve-jobs-by-walter-isaacson-a-review/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2012 14:34:57 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2012/06/22/steve-jobs-by-walter-isaacson-a-review/</guid><description>iSteve Jobs by Walter Isaacson
My rating: 5 of 5 stars
In my opinion a biography of Jobs can&amp;rsquo;t be better than this - so impartial, detailed and so well researched.
You not only get to learn about a man who perfected convergence of art and technology and changed the way people interact with tech, but also what Apple is about, its ethos and how it was built.
Visiting book stores these days you will found a whole shelf of Steve Jobs biographies, my advice, don&amp;rsquo;t worry about the cost and buy this one!</description></item><item><title>Ponderings of the Year Past: Part 1</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2012/03/26/ponderings-of-the-year-past-part-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2012 19:59:28 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2012/03/26/ponderings-of-the-year-past-part-1/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been long since I wrote something. To be frank, it was last July in which I actually spoke out my mind. Of course, I wished to write a lot more (who doesn&amp;rsquo;t). This one is going to be long, so I decided to partition it.
The following are few important lessons I learnt over the gone year - 2011:
Computer Science != Computer Engineering Vineeth Sir always calls it Computing Science, we even had a discussion over it, perhaps over a year back( and once again recently); the doubt got cleared up only after I looked up ACM&amp;rsquo;s Computing Curricula Recommendations which defines five sub-disciplines of computing: Computer Science, Computer Engineering, Information Systems, Information Technology, and Software Engineering (they have pretty decent comparisons among these disciplines using pictures and charts).</description></item><item><title>The Next Generation of Makers</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/quote/2011/04/08/the-next-generation-of-makers-2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2011 09:49:41 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/quote/2011/04/08/the-next-generation-of-makers-2/</guid><description>I know the future is what I make it.
I believe I can make the world better.
I understand I need knowledge and passion.
I choose to participate, not observe.
I work with my hands and my mind.
I pursue beauty in what I produce.
I see art in science and science in art.
I value skills.
I am the next generation of Maker!
&amp;mdash;Source: http://www.</description></item><item><title>List of Books Read So Far</title><link>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2008/09/08/list-of-books-read-so-far/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2008 01:50:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://k4rtik.github.io/techglider.in/post/2008/09/08/list-of-books-read-so-far/</guid><description>This is a list of books I used to maintain at The TechGlider Forums, imported here for keeping it updated.
Here I list the books I have read (only those whose names I remember) so far (in finishing order):
Harry Potter and the Philosopher&amp;rsquo;s Stone, by J K Rowling
Harry Potter and the Chamber of Secrets, by J K Rowling
Harry Potter and the Prisoner of Azkaban, by J K Rowling</description></item></channel></rss>