<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>slideshow on The TechGlider</title><link>techglider.in/tags/slideshow/</link><description>Recent content in slideshow on The TechGlider</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2009 17:06:05 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="techglider.in/tags/slideshow/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Brief Overview of Ubuntu 9.10 Karmic Koala</title><link>techglider.in/post/2009/10/30/a-brief-overview-of-ubuntu-9-10-karmic-koala/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2009 17:06:05 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2009/10/30/a-brief-overview-of-ubuntu-9-10-karmic-koala/</guid><description>Just got my hands on to latest version of Ubuntu 9.10 Karmic Koala around 5 hours ago. So, this will be a very brief overview of Ubuntu&amp;rsquo;s latest version.
Me being Ubuntu crazy, just started exploring it after downloading it. I setup my 8 GB Corsair Flash Voyager as a bootable Ubuntu 9.10 drive using USB Startup Disk Creator available in Jaunty.
Booting into the live system was similar as before except for the color and design of the Ubuntu logo on bootup has changed.</description></item><item><title>A Guide to Installing Fedora 9: Part 1</title><link>techglider.in/post/2008/09/06/a-guide-to-installing-fedora-9-part-1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2008 01:50:41 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2008/09/06/a-guide-to-installing-fedora-9-part-1/</guid><description>This is a beginner&amp;rsquo;s tutorial to installing Fedora 9 on your PC. In a recent survey I found that Fedora is more popular in India than Ubuntu (my personal favorite) so I decided to give a installation guide for Fedora instead of Ubuntu (read: http://techglider.in/blog/blog1.php/20 &amp;hellip; thiversary).
Prerequisites: You will need
Fedora 9 installation DVD (to know how to get one, visit: http://techglider.in/blog/blog1.php/20 &amp;hellip; ting-linux)
A PC system with atleast 9 GB of free space and minimum of 256 MB of RAM</description></item><item><title>Fedora 9 Installation Screenshots uploaded</title><link>techglider.in/post/2008/09/05/fedora-9-installation-screenshots-uploaded/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2008 12:59:14 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2008/09/05/fedora-9-installation-screenshots-uploaded/</guid><description>:phew: Finally, the screenshots for Fedora 9 installation have been uploaded (with great difficulty and mess up of my system and internet connection in the last few days).
To view a slide show follow the link: http://www.flickr.com/photos/techglider/sets/72157607119105020/show/
Hope to write a &amp;ldquo;full guide to installing Fedora 9 on your PC&amp;rdquo; by Sunday.</description></item></channel></rss>