<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>FOSSCell on The TechGlider</title><link>techglider.in/tags/fosscell/</link><description>Recent content in FOSSCell on The TechGlider</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 08:33:41 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="techglider.in/tags/fosscell/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Of FOSSMeets at NIT Calicut</title><link>techglider.in/post/2013/04/14/of-fossmeets-at-nit-calicut/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 08:33:41 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2013/04/14/of-fossmeets-at-nit-calicut/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been over a month and a half since the last edition of FOSSMeet at NIT Calicut. As an active member of organizing team for FOSSMeets &amp;lsquo;10 and &amp;lsquo;11 and a keen but silent observer for the 2013 edition, I want to share some history, some ideas &amp;amp; few observations with this post. The intent is to generate discussion among people who have been part of earlier FOSSMeets and to leave some things to ponder about (and act on) for juniors.</description></item><item><title>Accessing NIT Calicut's Ubuntu Mirror (in the campus)</title><link>techglider.in/post/2011/02/01/accessing-nit-calicuts-ubuntu-mirror-in-the-campus/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 01:20:47 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2011/02/01/accessing-nit-calicuts-ubuntu-mirror-in-the-campus/</guid><description>As the FOSSCell webserver has been facing troubles these days, the instructions to use the Ubuntu Mirror of NIT Calicut that were available on the FOSSCell wiki are being missed by many. Here they are though not in the informative way as were given on the wiki:
Add the following to your /etc/apt/sources.list and comment out other similar repos.
deb http://192.168.40.97/ubuntu lucid-updates main multiverse restricted universe deb http://192.168.40.97/ubuntu lucid-security main multiverse restricted universe deb http://192.</description></item><item><title>Software Freedom Day 2010 at NIT Calicut</title><link>techglider.in/post/2010/09/18/software-freedom-day-2010-at-nit-calicut/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2010 21:55:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>techglider.in/post/2010/09/18/software-freedom-day-2010-at-nit-calicut/</guid><description>I am a member of the Free and Open Source Software Users group - FOSSCell - at my college - NIT Calicut. We celebrated Software Freedom Day yesterday for the first time.
We started planning for the celebration on our mailing list 5 days ago. Amid a lot of heated discussions we kept on updating the FOSSCell wiki ( http://fosscell.nitc.ac.in/wiki ) with our ideas, plans, suggestions, names of attendees and volunteers.</description></item></channel></rss>