<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>reviews on The TechGlider</title><link>https://techglider.in/tags/reviews/</link><description>Recent content in reviews on The TechGlider</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2015 20:18:19 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://techglider.in/tags/reviews/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Reading A Tour of C++</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2015/07/18/tour-of-cplusplus/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2015 20:18:19 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2015/07/18/tour-of-cplusplus/</guid><description>I have been reading Bjarne Stroustrup’s A Tour of C++ and the language feels like a totally new language since my last project in C++ which was years ago. Since, (re-)learning a language requires both reading and writing code, I decided to work through some exercises on Exercism.
For C++, Exercism encourages a test-driven approach to solving problems and requires some tooling support (CMake) to focus on solving the problem instead of wasting time on setting up a build system for each exercise.</description></item><item><title>Review of Around India in 80 Trains</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2015/05/03/review-of-around-india-in-80-trains/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2015 18:27:30 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2015/05/03/review-of-around-india-in-80-trains/</guid><description>Around India in 80 Trains by Monisha Rajesh
My rating: 3 of 5 stars
Got my hands on this book about two years ago when Amazon.in was launched and they were giving away some free Kindle books. Started reading it only when the Goodreads Indian Readers group picked this book as their April 2015 read.
Review This was the first time I read a travelogue and cannot say if I like the genre.</description></item><item><title>Review of V for Vendetta</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2015/05/01/review-of-v-for-vendetta/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 20:59:51 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2015/05/01/review-of-v-for-vendetta/</guid><description>V for Vendetta by Alan Moore
My rating: 4.5 of 5 stars
I had seen the film adaptation 4-5 years ago but hardly recalled what it was about. Decided to watch it again after I was done with the graphic novel and compare the two.
The Graphic Novel First couple of volumes in the 10-volume series didn&amp;rsquo;t make much sense and were rather slow to read as I was just getting introduced to the characters.</description></item><item><title>Review of No Place to Hide by Glenn Greenwald</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2015/04/12/review-of-no-place-to-hide-by-glenn-greenwald/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2015 12:37:38 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2015/04/12/review-of-no-place-to-hide-by-glenn-greenwald/</guid><description>No Place to Hide: Edward Snowden, the NSA and the Surveillance State by Glenn Greenwald
My rating: 4 of 5 stars
I had bought this book right away after reading the following tweet from a concerned friend:
It took me another 5 months to actually start reading the book.
Review First two chapters read like a Dan Brown thriller except that you constantly keep reminding yourself that this is not fiction and events leading to the Snowden revelations actually happened this way.</description></item><item><title>Review of A Study in Scarlet</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2014/11/19/review-of-a-study-in-scarlet/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2014 18:11:08 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2014/11/19/review-of-a-study-in-scarlet/</guid><description>A Study in Scarlet by Arthur Conan Doyle
My rating: 5 of 5 stars
One word - unputdownable!
Background I am not into reading classics, but chanced upon obtaining the first volume of Sherlock Holmes: The Complete Novels and Stories from a friend. To much of my astonishment, a text written in late 19th century turned out to be really engaging.
Not very comfortable in reading fat books, I started reading out the volume in the form of a sample from Kindle store on my Paperwhite.</description></item><item><title>Habibi by Craig Thompson - A Review</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2014/11/09/habibi-by-craig-thompson-a-review/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2014 19:20:13 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2014/11/09/habibi-by-craig-thompson-a-review/</guid><description>Habibi by Craig Thompson
My rating: 5 of 5 stars
At 672 pages, this is probably the longest graphic novel I have read, but one can&amp;rsquo;t go just by the page count, I finished it within 24 hours of acquiring the book from a friend. Yes, it was that engaging.
The book portrays the complicated relationship of two child slaves who meet by chance, grow up together, get separated and meet again, all this while craving for each other&amp;rsquo;s company while facing the hardship of the world.</description></item><item><title>Review of Business Doctors: Management Consulting Gone Wild</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2014/10/26/review-of-business-doctors-management-consulting-gone-wild/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2014 21:38:12 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2014/10/26/review-of-business-doctors-management-consulting-gone-wild/</guid><description>Business Doctors: Management Consulting Gone Wild by Sameer Kamat
My rating: 3 of 5 stars
I don&amp;rsquo;t generally pick up fiction books that easily, but when I first read about the book, I found it intriguing. The fact that the book is self-published added to my curiosity.
So, when Sameer approached me over Goodreads and offered a complimentary copy in exchange of an honest review, I was all but happy.</description></item><item><title>Review of A 'Psycho' Path</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2014/10/23/review-of-a-psycho-path/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2014 14:38:38 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2014/10/23/review-of-a-psycho-path/</guid><description>A &amp;lsquo;Psycho&amp;rsquo; Path by Haris Ibrahim K. V.
My rating: 3 of 5 stars
A first collection of stories &amp;amp; articles from a budding writer friend. Liked the book overall.
The stories are imaginative and much often leave one thinking near the end. Some articles felt lacking in trying to convey the intended meaning, but others especially void Easy(); and The Magic of Reading were quite well written.
Looking forward to a full length book from the author.</description></item><item><title>Review of A Byte of Vim</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2014/04/13/review-of-a-byte-of-vim/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2014 13:10:21 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2014/04/13/review-of-a-byte-of-vim/</guid><description>A Byte of Vim by Swaroop C.H.
My rating: 4 of 5 stars
Finished that 30-minute crash course with vimtutor and don&amp;rsquo;t yet know the power of vim?
This small book is your next best step to become an effective vimmer.
One star less only because the book is out of maintenance and one may find many broken links. Also, the formatting of the definitive source (PDF) could be a bit better.</description></item><item><title>Review of The Elements of Style</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2014/03/24/review-of-the-elements-of-style/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2014 13:05:57 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2014/03/24/review-of-the-elements-of-style/</guid><description>The Elements of Style (Original Edition) by William Strunk Jr.
My rating: 3 of 5 stars
I read the original edition (1918) which is in public domain now (one good and properly hyperlinked version can be found at http://books.cat-v.org/writing/elements-of-style/.
Three stars because much of advice regarding English usage in this book is outdated now. I am aware of the expanded edition by Strunk and White but even that edition is from 1959; I doubt I will gain a lot by reading it.</description></item><item><title>Swaraj by Arvind Kejriwal - A Review</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2014/03/20/swaraj-by-arvind-kejriwal-a-review/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2014 17:53:41 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2014/03/20/swaraj-by-arvind-kejriwal-a-review/</guid><description>Swaraj by Arvind Kejriwal
My rating: 4 of 5 stars
Ended up reading a Hindi book after many years, &amp;lsquo;कथेतर&amp;rsquo; (non-fiction, new word learnt!) on that.
Little Background I haven&amp;rsquo;t followed Kejriwal&amp;rsquo;s or Anna&amp;rsquo;s movement from the beginning. I first gave serious attention when AAP managed to win a substantial number of seats in Delhi last December. Since then, I have come to admire Kejriwal&amp;rsquo;s clarity of thought, his ideas and his mission, all of which can be ascertained in any of his recent interviews or QA&amp;rsquo;s with audience where neither the interviewer nor the public leave any stone unturned to grill him.</description></item><item><title>Review of The Immortals Of Meluha</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2014/03/01/review-of-the-immortals-of-meluha/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 12:54:42 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2014/03/01/review-of-the-immortals-of-meluha/</guid><description>The Immortals Of Meluha by Amish Tripathi
My rating: 4 of 5 stars
Fast paced and interesting. I don&amp;rsquo;t think I have read any mythological fiction before and this as a first wasn&amp;rsquo;t a bad start. Hope to finish the trilogy in next few months.
I recall the craze about Shiva trilogy while in college, especially among the folks at LH ;). Written using very simple words, the book re-imagines Shiva as a man and describes his journey in the strange and unfamiliar world of Meluha and beyond.</description></item><item><title>Review of Jaya: An Illustrated Retelling of the Mahabharata</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2014/01/30/review-of-jaya-an-illustrated-retelling-of-the-mahabharata/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2014 12:47:52 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2014/01/30/review-of-jaya-an-illustrated-retelling-of-the-mahabharata/</guid><description>Jaya: An Illustrated Retelling of the Mahabharata by Devdutt Pattanaik
My rating: 5 of 5 stars
Wanted to read Mahabharata before I moved on to reading some other books which compare their content with Mahabharata and its characters.
I remember reading the condensed version in grade 7 which was part of the syllabus under Hindi literature but never had a chance to go deeper. There are many variants of the epic with different point of views, delivering different level of depth and in different languages.</description></item><item><title>Review of Fun Home: A Family Tragicomic</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2014/01/11/review-of-fun-home-a-family-tragicomic/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2014 12:38:12 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2014/01/11/review-of-fun-home-a-family-tragicomic/</guid><description>Fun Home: A Family Tragicomic by Alison Bechdel
My rating: 5 of 5 stars
Didn&amp;rsquo;t realize the author is a woman before reading the first chapter and looking up her name on Google. Neither did I know she is the one behind Bechdel test (used for identifying gender bias in movies and other works of fiction).
Combining both the genres I like - (auto)biographies and graphic novels, it was a worthy read, similar to the only other autobiographical graphic novel I have read: Art Spiegelman&amp;rsquo;s Maus.</description></item><item><title>Review of An Autobiography or The Story of my Experiments with Truth</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2013/07/08/review-of-an-autobiography-or-the-story-of-my-experiments-with-truth/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2013 12:28:28 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2013/07/08/review-of-an-autobiography-or-the-story-of-my-experiments-with-truth/</guid><description>An Autobiography or The Story of my Experiments with Truth by Mahatma Gandhi
My rating: 5 of 5 stars
Recommended read to understand what Mahatma Gandhi and his ideals of Truth and Ahimsa stood for, in his own words.
Gandhi does full justice with the autobiography not failing to mention incidences from his life which could be termed as objectionable, or embarrassing. His exploration of dietetics, religion, dressing styles and later politics reaffirms my belief in a statement one of my professors made about Gandhi which inspired me to read the book:</description></item><item><title>Review of Surely You're Joking, Mr. Feynman!</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2013/05/30/review-of-surely-youre-joking-mr.-feynman/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2013 09:44:31 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2013/05/30/review-of-surely-youre-joking-mr.-feynman/</guid><description>Surely You&amp;rsquo;re Joking, Mr. Feynman! by Richard P. Feynman
My rating: 5 of 5 stars
This is one of those books which bring a turning point in your life, and make you reevaluate it, much like Randy Pausch&amp;rsquo;s The Last Lecture and Steve Jobs bio for me. Made me take interest in physics around us again. :)
Feynman was surely a man of multiple lives, how could anybody live so much?</description></item><item><title>Turning Points by APJ Abdul Kalam - A Review</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2013/04/16/turning-points-by-apj-abdul-kalam-a-review/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2013 09:15:26 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2013/04/16/turning-points-by-apj-abdul-kalam-a-review/</guid><description>Turning Points: A Journey Through Challenges by A.P.J. Abdul Kalam
My rating: 4 of 5 stars
A good book that shows the life of a President that India loved, sheds light on the decisions he made that were considered controversial and inspires the leader in one. Not a book for a casual reader, for sure, they might complain it&amp;rsquo;s boring.
I feel Kalam uplifted the position of President of India with his initiatives during his tenure.</description></item><item><title>Logicomix: An Epic Search for Truth</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2013/02/03/logicomix-an-epic-search-for-truth/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2013 18:52:40 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2013/02/03/logicomix-an-epic-search-for-truth/</guid><description>This one needs to be quick, 14 minutes until midnight.
Logicomix (Photo credit: Wikipedia)
In this post I want to introduce a graphic novel which I read about a year back - Logicomix: An Epic Search for Truth.
How I ended up reading this is an interesting story in itself. Let me try to recite in minimum possible words. During that time (Sem 6) I had enrolled for a course called Computational Complexity by Murali sir.</description></item><item><title>Steve Jobs by Walter Isaacson - A Review</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2012/06/22/steve-jobs-by-walter-isaacson-a-review/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2012 14:34:57 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2012/06/22/steve-jobs-by-walter-isaacson-a-review/</guid><description>iSteve Jobs by Walter Isaacson
My rating: 5 of 5 stars
In my opinion a biography of Jobs can&amp;rsquo;t be better than this - so impartial, detailed and so well researched.
You not only get to learn about a man who perfected convergence of art and technology and changed the way people interact with tech, but also what Apple is about, its ethos and how it was built.
Visiting book stores these days you will found a whole shelf of Steve Jobs biographies, my advice, don&amp;rsquo;t worry about the cost and buy this one!</description></item></channel></rss>