<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>wordpress on The TechGlider</title><link>https://techglider.in/tags/wordpress/</link><description>Recent content in wordpress on The TechGlider</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2014 01:30:58 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://techglider.in/tags/wordpress/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Posts from The TechGlider Blog Migrated</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2014/10/27/posts-from-the-techglider-blog-migrated/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2014 01:30:58 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2014/10/27/posts-from-the-techglider-blog-migrated/</guid><description>Just a quick note that I have successfully migrated all posts from the original TechGlider Blog which used to reside at https://techglider.in/kartik/blog couple of years ago.
This completes migration of all my written content. Fixing broken links, images, etc. is the major work that remains.
Aside:
I ended up skimming through much of my old content, feels very childish now; my friends from that time might get a laugh or two reading about memories recorded in here.</description></item><item><title>reinit</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2014/10/26/reinit/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2014 15:04:13 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2014/10/26/reinit/</guid><description>Today I am relaunching my website - https://techglider.in - in a new avatar. This, in the form of techglider.com, used to be my first website on the Internet until the .com domain was stolen by a domain shark. Sometime later, I switched to writing on wordpress.com and stopped maintaining this site.
A constant feeling of not having an official web home and a permanent place to put my thoughts out for the world has been nagging me for months, this reinit is the first step in solving this problem.</description></item><item><title>Easiest Way to Setup a Web Development Environment on Ubuntu-based Distros</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2011/07/08/easiest-way-to-setup-a-web-development-environment-on-ubuntu-based-distros/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2011 18:30:21 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2011/07/08/easiest-way-to-setup-a-web-development-environment-on-ubuntu-based-distros/</guid><description>Did you know how easy it is to get a basic web development environment on your Ubuntu-based Linux distribution? Guess what, it just takes 2 commands on the Terminal:
sudo apt-get install tasksel This will install a small utility which lets you install a lot packages grouped together as software collections.
sudo tasksel Launch tasksel and select &amp;lsquo;LAMP server&amp;rsquo; by pressing the SPACE key, press ENTER when you are done (see attached screenshot).</description></item><item><title>Done messing up enough with the looks of...</title><link>https://techglider.in/status/2011/03/13/done-messing-up-enough-with-the-looks-of/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2011 17:33:55 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/status/2011/03/13/done-messing-up-enough-with-the-looks-of/</guid><description>Done messing up enough with the looks of my old blog for the day. Have exams this week and haven&amp;rsquo;t studied a thing. Need to take a week&amp;rsquo;s break from the net. ;)
On another note: I have restored my website: TechGlider.in during this Ragam. Do take a look at &amp;hellip;and, we&amp;rsquo;re back!.</description></item><item><title>...and, we're back!</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2011/03/13/and-we-are-back/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2011 07:43:51 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2011/03/13/and-we-are-back/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been so long - missing the TechGlider - my dream, my hard work of over 2 years was gone. Started in July 2008, gone in July 2010. :(
The reason of this long absence: I lost the ownership of the domain techglider.com - partly because of my own carelessness, and partly because of my webhost Four &amp;lsquo;S&amp;rsquo; Tech&amp;rsquo;s troubles. In the process, I did learn a few interesting things like the concept of drop catching, how the companies like GoDaddy make so much money; and more importantly how not to lose my domain again.</description></item><item><title>Wow Just noticed my blog reached over a...</title><link>https://techglider.in/status/2011/02/25/wow-just-noticed-my-blog-reached-over-a/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2011 10:30:32 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/status/2011/02/25/wow-just-noticed-my-blog-reached-over-a/</guid><description>Wow! Just noticed - my blog reached over a 1000 hits. Hope to be a more regular blogger this time.</description></item><item><title>The reason why I recently shifted to thi...</title><link>https://techglider.in/status/2010/12/25/the-reason-why-i-recently-shifted-to-thi/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Dec 2010 02:47:21 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/status/2010/12/25/the-reason-why-i-recently-shifted-to-thi/</guid><description>The reason why I recently shifted to this blog is detailed at http://kartikscribbles.posterous.com/one-last-post-on-my-posterous</description></item><item><title>Welcome to the All New TechGlider Blog</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2008/10/06/welcome-to-the-all-new-techglider-blog/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2008 23:46:23 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2008/10/06/welcome-to-the-all-new-techglider-blog/</guid><description>This is my first post on WordPress and through this I welcome you to the all new TechGlider Blog.
I am finally finished with moving the TGB to WordPress. WordPress offers a plethora of plugins to customize one&amp;rsquo;s blog and I am trying to choose what are those that I need for the TGB. As pointed out in my last post, this change hasn&amp;rsquo;t been easy. I almost lost all of my previous posts for there was no efficient way to import the posts from my b2evolution installation to WordPress, so I had to do it manually and took a whole day for that (these type of repetitive works are really a pain in the neck for me).</description></item><item><title>Back to linux and switching to WordPress...</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2008/10/05/back-to-linux-and-switching-to-wordpress/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2008 12:36:38 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2008/10/05/back-to-linux-and-switching-to-wordpress/</guid><description>I am glad to tell you that I have got rid of windows XP (again!) after muddling my head for 2 days trying to make it stable on my system. Now, I feel better that I gave it up in just 4 days of use and got rid of shame (read about it here) I was feeling that I installed XP again. I now have 2 variants of linux viz. Ubuntu 8.</description></item></channel></rss>