<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>hacker on The TechGlider</title><link>https://techglider.in/tags/hacker/</link><description>Recent content in hacker on The TechGlider</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2016 22:51:18 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://techglider.in/tags/hacker/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Java</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2016/01/02/java/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2016 22:51:18 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2016/01/02/java/</guid><description>I don&amp;rsquo;t really recall why I avoided Java all this while.
Few weeks after arriving here at Brown, I learnt Brown is, what they call, a Java school. That&amp;rsquo;s probably not completely true, but for a vast majority of students that take Andy&amp;rsquo;s intro class, CS15, it is. I have come to realize it is not such a bad thing (quite the opposite).
I remember my first few weeks at college when I was trying to teach myself Java in the CC (whoa, they have a website now!</description></item><item><title>Relearning Computer Science</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2015/10/28/relearning-computer-science/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2015 11:35:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2015/10/28/relearning-computer-science/</guid><description>Awakening I was awaken from a long sleep of ignorance with some events that occurred in the last couple of weeks. A sudden surge of conscientiousness about taking my education in my hands was one of the immediate results.
The inflection point was getting to hear Bryan Cantrill in person and interviewing with him the next day. I didn’t do my best, but was humbled by Cantrill into realizing how much I had to learn.</description></item><item><title>Controlling iTunes using Android Wear</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2015/07/14/controlling-itunes-using-android-wear/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2015 16:58:36 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2015/07/14/controlling-itunes-using-android-wear/</guid><description>I happen to be surrounded by a lot of gadgets lately. One of them is a pretty Moto 360, one of the early Android Wear watches:
and another a MacBook Air (PlatiniumAir) which is about to celebrate its first anniversary:
This morning while walking-reading in my room, I had iTunes on the MacBook playing some tracks from one of the auto-generated Apple Music playlists. Now, it’s fairly easy to flick away mobile (lying away on my desk) notifications using my watch and not interrupt my reading for more than a couple seconds.</description></item><item><title>Review of No Place to Hide by Glenn Greenwald</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2015/04/12/review-of-no-place-to-hide-by-glenn-greenwald/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2015 12:37:38 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2015/04/12/review-of-no-place-to-hide-by-glenn-greenwald/</guid><description>No Place to Hide: Edward Snowden, the NSA and the Surveillance State by Glenn Greenwald
My rating: 4 of 5 stars
I had bought this book right away after reading the following tweet from a concerned friend:
It took me another 5 months to actually start reading the book.
Review First two chapters read like a Dan Brown thriller except that you constantly keep reminding yourself that this is not fiction and events leading to the Snowden revelations actually happened this way.</description></item><item><title>You literally ought to be asking yourself all...</title><link>https://techglider.in/quote/2013/11/13/you-literally-ought-to-be-asking-yourself-all/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2013 15:48:09 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/quote/2013/11/13/you-literally-ought-to-be-asking-yourself-all/</guid><description>You literally ought to be asking yourself all of the time - what&amp;rsquo;s the most important thing I could be working on in the world right now; and if you are not working on that, why aren&amp;rsquo;t you?
&amp;mdash;Aaron Swartz, as quoted by @TarenSK in the upcoming documentary on Swartz (Source: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3izOJ7zX5I0)</description></item><item><title>Of FOSSMeets at NIT Calicut</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2013/04/14/of-fossmeets-at-nit-calicut/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 08:33:41 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2013/04/14/of-fossmeets-at-nit-calicut/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been over a month and a half since the last edition of FOSSMeet at NIT Calicut. As an active member of organizing team for FOSSMeets &amp;lsquo;10 and &amp;lsquo;11 and a keen but silent observer for the 2013 edition, I want to share some history, some ideas &amp;amp; few observations with this post. The intent is to generate discussion among people who have been part of earlier FOSSMeets and to leave some things to ponder about (and act on) for juniors.</description></item><item><title>The programmers of tomorrow are the wizards of...</title><link>https://techglider.in/quote/2013/02/26/the-programmers-of-tomorrow-are-the-wizards-of/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2013 18:59:54 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/quote/2013/02/26/the-programmers-of-tomorrow-are-the-wizards-of/</guid><description>The programmers of tomorrow are the wizards of the future. You&amp;rsquo;re going to look like you have magic powers compared to everybody else.
&amp;mdash;Gabe Newell, Founder and President, Valve (Source: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dU1xS07N-FA courtesy of code.org)</description></item><item><title>Always code as if the guy who ends...</title><link>https://techglider.in/quote/2012/12/28/always-code-as-if-the-guy-who-ends/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2012 10:39:01 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/quote/2012/12/28/always-code-as-if-the-guy-who-ends/</guid><description>Always code as if the guy who ends up maintaining your code will be a violent psychopath who knows where you live. Code for readability.
&amp;mdash;John F Woods. Source: https://groups.google.com/d/msg/comp.lang.c++/rYCO5yn4lXw/oITtSkZOtoUJ (With special attribution to two juniors who posted this on homepage of CSEA&amp;rsquo;s upcoming website.)</description></item><item><title>It is necessary to work if not from...</title><link>https://techglider.in/quote/2012/07/18/it-is-necessary-to-work-if-not-from/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2012 08:29:33 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/quote/2012/07/18/it-is-necessary-to-work-if-not-from/</guid><description>It is necessary to work, if not from inclination, at least from despair. Everything considered, work is less boring than amusing oneself.
&amp;mdash;Charles Baudelaire (discovered this in Vinod Pathari Sir&amp;rsquo;s email signature and found it particularly interesting)</description></item><item><title>A Fun Security Weekend with null and sCTF</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2012/06/22/a-fun-security-weekend-with-null-and-sctf/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2012 19:39:05 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2012/06/22/a-fun-security-weekend-with-null-and-sctf/</guid><description>I know it&amp;rsquo;s quite late to post about the last weekend when another weekend is around the corner, but couldn&amp;rsquo;t control myself as the last one was so eventful. :)
It was almost 2 weeks back that I got to know about sCTF 2012. I have always wanted to learn about computer security (and the darker side of hacking), but haven&amp;rsquo;t been able to give time it to it. What followed was a quick search for team members from among my batch via FB - Nithin immediately showed interest, we pulled Jerrin in too.</description></item><item><title>(Bangalore) Summer of '12... with BeagleBone</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2012/06/13/bangalore-summer-of-12-with-beaglebone/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2012 16:42:13 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2012/06/13/bangalore-summer-of-12-with-beaglebone/</guid><description>This post will be slightly long. Lots of exciting things happening over a Bangalore summer this year for me. :D
Somehow I always wanted to learn more about hardware and with a mentor like Khasim the road seems a lot more exciting. I first met him when he came to conduct a workshop on BeagleBoard during Tathva 2009 at my college - NIT Calicut. I was just a fresher then and have since regretted that I could not attend that workshop completely (due to my participation in various CS related competitions).</description></item><item><title>Control All Computers in a Lab from a Single System</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2012/02/12/control-all-computers-in-a-lab-from-a-single-system/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2012 03:10:21 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2012/02/12/control-all-computers-in-a-lab-from-a-single-system/</guid><description>Quoting Dhandeep, our super-cool lab-admin:
now , all 70 systems in the lab can be switched on and switched off by single commands from the hostel&amp;hellip;
Yes, that and a lot more is possible in our Software Systems Lab now. How? Read on&amp;hellip;
The Setup We have over 70 systems with Ubuntu 10.04 LTS installed on them. There is an administrative account (let&amp;rsquo;s call it admin for this post) and a guest (limited privilege) account on each.</description></item><item><title>even if you wrote 100% of the code...</title><link>https://techglider.in/quote/2011/10/04/even-if-you-wrote-100-of-the-code/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2011 12:43:28 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/quote/2011/10/04/even-if-you-wrote-100-of-the-code/</guid><description>&amp;hellip;even if you wrote 100% of the code, and even if you are the best programmer in the world and will never need any help with the project at all, the thing that really matters is the users of the code. The code itself is unimportant; the project is only as useful as people actually find it.
&amp;mdash;Linus Torvalds, on Software Development Management. Source: http://h30565.www3.hp.com/t5/Feature-Articles/Linus-Torvalds-s-Lessons-on-Software-Development-Management/ba-p/440</description></item><item><title>Root Samsung Galaxy S i9000 running GINGERBREAD.DDJV6 using Ubuntu Linux</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2011/06/21/root-samsung-galaxy-s-i9000-running-gingerbread-ddjv6-using-ubuntu-linux/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2011 17:01:54 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2011/06/21/root-samsung-galaxy-s-i9000-running-gingerbread-ddjv6-using-ubuntu-linux/</guid><description>I bought a Samsung Galaxy S i9000 just last month. The most prominent reason to buy an Android phone was that it&amp;rsquo;s based on Linux and I love the UNIX-based OS. Besides, Android as a platform provides so many opportunities into application development (and even kernel hacking) that I was simply tempted to buy one since last year.
I have explored the phone since I got my hands on it - trying various apps, playing with 3G internet speeds (3.</description></item><item><title>7 Commandments of the Personal Computer Revolution</title><link>https://techglider.in/quote/2011/04/22/7-commandments-of-the-personal-computer-revolution/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2011 13:11:08 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/quote/2011/04/22/7-commandments-of-the-personal-computer-revolution/</guid><description>7 Commandments of the Personal Computer Revolution:
Access to Computers - and anything that might teach you something about the way the world works - should be unlimited and total. Always yield to the Hands-on Imperative. All information should be free. Mistrust authority - promote decentralization. Hackers should be judged by their hacking, not bogus criteria such as degrees, age, race,or position. You can create art and beauty on a computer.</description></item><item><title>The Next Generation of Makers</title><link>https://techglider.in/quote/2011/04/08/the-next-generation-of-makers-2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2011 09:49:41 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/quote/2011/04/08/the-next-generation-of-makers-2/</guid><description>I know the future is what I make it.
I believe I can make the world better.
I understand I need knowledge and passion.
I choose to participate, not observe.
I work with my hands and my mind.
I pursue beauty in what I produce.
I see art in science and science in art.
I value skills.
I am the next generation of Maker!
&amp;mdash;Source: http://www.</description></item><item><title>The Hacker Attitude</title><link>https://techglider.in/quote/2011/03/10/the-hacker-attitude/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2011 09:03:29 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/quote/2011/03/10/the-hacker-attitude/</guid><description>The Hacker Attitude:
The world is full of fascinating problems waiting to be solved. No problem should ever have to be solved twice. Boredom and drudgery are evil. Freedom is good. Attitude is no substitute for competence. &amp;mdash;Eric Steven Raymond at How To Become A Hacker</description></item><item><title>Building a Modern Computer in 12 Steps - A Perfect Elective Course for Sem 3 of CSE</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2011/02/28/building-a-modern-computer-in-12-steps-a-perfect-elective-course-for-sem-3-of-cse/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2011 17:01:40 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2011/02/28/building-a-modern-computer-in-12-steps-a-perfect-elective-course-for-sem-3-of-cse/</guid><description>Just watched this Google Tech Talk on From Nand to Tetris in 12 steps by Shimon Schocken introducing a course he developed along with Noam Nisan:
A must watch for all CS faculty of hardware, algorithms and systems.
The course covers 12 projects to be done over a single semester covering building everything from basic logic gates to computer architecture, and from machine language to an operating system starting from a False and a NAND using a custom HDL.</description></item><item><title>The Pleasure of Finding Things Out</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2011/01/05/the-pleasure-of-finding-things-out/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2011 20:25:41 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2011/01/05/the-pleasure-of-finding-things-out/</guid><description>Just watched this video whose link I got from Anjhan&amp;rsquo;s blog, an interview of Richard Feynman. I started out to watch only the first 10 minutes but really couldn&amp;rsquo;t stop myself to watch the whole thing (although I have to attend class at 8 AM). Must watch for the curious thinker, the scientist, the hacker.</description></item><item><title>Hacker</title><link>https://techglider.in/quote/2010/12/23/hacker-any-person-who-likes-to-explor/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2010 18:21:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/quote/2010/12/23/hacker-any-person-who-likes-to-explor/</guid><description>Any person who likes to explore details of a system and extend their functionality as opposed to most people who prefer to learn the bare minimum.
&amp;mdash;Aanjhan Ranganathan (@tuxmaniac) Source: http://www.tuxmaniac.com/work/presentations/keynote.pdf</description></item><item><title>How to become a Hacker?</title><link>https://techglider.in/post/2008/10/05/how-to-become-a-hacker/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2008 08:21:49 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://techglider.in/post/2008/10/05/how-to-become-a-hacker/</guid><description>A lot of people ask me &amp;ldquo;how can I become a hacker&amp;rdquo;?
I ask them to differentiate between a hacker and a cracker first and specify what do they actually want to become. If the answer is a hacker, I need to direct them to this page (perhaps the best page on the net for a guide to becoming a hacker): http://www.catb.org/~esr/faqs/hacker-howto.html
For crackers-to-be I don&amp;rsquo;t have very-healthy feelings and ask them to correct their mindsets.</description></item></channel></rss>